<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Dog on Pest Policy</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/dog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dog on Pest Policy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/dog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Best Dog Backpack Carrier for Hiking</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/best-dog-backpack-carrier-for-hiking/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/best-dog-backpack-carrier-for-hiking/</guid>
      <description>When choosing the best dog backpack carrier for hiking, you can consider things like comfort, durability, size, and safety. These factors ensure that both ...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When choosing the best <a href="/posts/best-dog-beds/">dog</a> backpack carrier for hiking, you can consider things like comfort, durability, size, and safety. These factors ensure that both you and your canine companion have an enjoyable and safe experience on the trail.</p>
<h3 id="key-factors-to-consider">Key Factors to Consider</h3>
<p>**1. Comfort **
Some products, like the
<a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CSG5YRZF/?tag=p-policy-20"><strong>K9 Sport Sack AIR Plus</strong></a>
, prioritize comfort for both the dog and the owner. This carrier has padded shoulder straps and back panels, reducing strain during long hikes.</p>
<p>Additionally, it offers excellent ventilation with mesh sides, keeping your dog cool. Comfort is vital, especially during extended hikes, to prevent fatigue for both parties.
**2. Durability **
Durability is crucial when selecting a dog backpack carrier, especially for rough terrains. The
<a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07CRS4FWW/?tag=p-policy-20"><strong>Kurgo G-Train Pet Backpack</strong></a>
is a standout option, made with waterproof and stain-resistant fabric.</p>
<p>Its sturdy construction ensures that it can handle the wear and tear of frequent hiking trips, providing a long-lasting solution for adventurers.
**3. Size and Fit **
Ensuring the backpack fits your dog properly is essential for their safety and comfort.</p>
<p>The
<strong>Outward Hound PoochPouch</strong>
is available in multiple sizes, making it easier to find a carrier that fits your dog&rsquo;s breed and size. A well-fitted carrier prevents your dog from feeling cramped and reduces the risk of injury.</p>
<p>Related:
<a href="https://pestpolicy.com/best-flea-shampoo-for-dogs/">Top dog flea shampoos</a>
**4. Safety Features **
Safety features like harness attachments, reflective strips, and secure zippers are essential.</p>
<p>The
<strong>PetAmi Deluxe Pet Carrier Backpack</strong>
comes with a reinforced structure that keeps the carrier from collapsing on your dog, ensuring their safety throughout the hike. Reflective strips also enhance visibility during low-light conditions, adding an extra layer of security.
**5. Ease of Use **
Some products, like the
<strong>NICREW Dog Backpack Carrier</strong>
, are designed with ease of use in mind. This carrier allows for easy loading and unloading, which is particularly useful for dogs who might be anxious or uncooperative.</p>
<p>Quick-release buckles and adjustable straps make it easy to put on and take off, ensuring a hassle-free experience.</p>
<h2 id="top-5-recommendations---dog-backpack-carrier-for-hiking">Top 5 Recommendations - Dog Backpack Carrier for Hiking</h2>
<h3 id="heading"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CSG5YRZF/?tag=p-policy-20">**1. K9 Sport Sack AIR Plus **</a></h3>
<p><strong>K9 Sport Sack AIR Plus</strong>
stand out with their highly adjustable and padded shoulder straps, which are designed to distribute weight evenly across the hiker&rsquo;s back, reducing strain during long treks.</p>
<dl>
<dt>This model also includes a detachable storage bag that can be used to carry additional gear, such as snacks, water, or a first-aid kit, ensuring you&rsquo;re well-prepared for your outdoor adventure.</dt>
<dt><strong>Benefits</strong></dt>
<dd>The K9 Sport Sack AIR Plus is highly adjustable, making it comfortable for hikers of different sizes. Its ventilation ensures your dog stays cool.</dd>
</dl>
<ul>
<li><strong>Cons</strong>: It might not be ideal for larger dog breeds, and the detachable storage bag can make the carrier feel bulky.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="2-kurgo-g-train-pet-backpack"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07CRS4FWW/?tag=p-policy-20"><strong>2. Kurgo G-Train Pet Backpack</strong></a></h3>
<p>On the other hand, the
<strong>Kurgo G-Train Pet Backpack</strong>
offers unique durability, thanks to its construction from waterproof and stain-resistant fabric. This makes it particularly appealing for hikers who frequently encounter challenging weather conditions or rough terrain.</p>
<dl>
<dt>The G-Train&rsquo;s separate storage compartment is another distinctive feature, providing ample space for personal items without compromising the comfort of your dog inside the carrier.</dt>
<dt><strong>Benefits</strong></dt>
<dd>The durability of this carrier makes it ideal for rugged hikes. It also doubles as a traditional carrier when youre off the trail.</dd>
</dl>
<ul>
<li><strong>Cons</strong>: The design might be a bit too rigid for some dogs, and it can be on the heavier side.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="3-outward-hound-poochpouch"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0081XII9S/?tag=p-policy-20"><strong>3. Outward Hound PoochPouch</strong></a></h3>
<p>Meanwhile, the
<strong>Outward Hound PoochPouch</strong>
is noteworthy for its availability in various sizes, accommodating a wide range of dog breeds.</p>
<dl>
<dt>This feature ensures a snug fit, which is crucial for the dog&rsquo;s safety and comfort. Its water-resistant nylon fabric adds another layer of protection, making it ideal for unpredictable weather, keeping your dog dry and comfortable.</dt>
<dt><strong>Benefits</strong></dt>
<dd>The range of sizes ensures a proper fit for your dog, enhancing their comfort. The water-resistant fabric is also useful for unexpected weather changes.</dd>
</dl>
<ul>
<li><strong>Cons</strong>: The straps may not be as padded as other models, which could lead to discomfort during long hikes.
Related:
<a href="https://pestpolicy.com/best-puppy-shampoo-for-fleas/">Top puppy shampoo</a>
.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="4-petami-deluxe-pet-carrier-backpack"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07B62YX1V/?tag=p-policy-20"><strong>4. PetAmi Deluxe Pet Carrier Backpack</strong></a></h3>
<p>The
<strong>PetAmi Deluxe Pet Carrier Backpack</strong>
boasts a well-ventilated design that includes a reinforced structure, ensuring that the carrier maintains its shape and does not collapse on your dog. This is particularly important for ensuring your pet&rsquo;s safety during the hike.</p>
<dl>
<dt>Additionally, the inclusion of multiple storage pockets and a collapsible water bowl makes this carrier highly functional, providing convenience without sacrificing safety or comfort.</dt>
<dt><strong>Benefits</strong></dt>
<dd>The reinforced structure ensures the carrier remains upright, keeping your dog safe. The extra storage and included water bowl are great for long hikes.</dd>
</dl>
<ul>
<li><strong>Cons</strong>: It might feel a bit cramped for larger dogs, and the multiple storage pockets could add extra weight.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="5-nicrew-dog-backpack-carrier"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B01E3INMFE/?tag=p-policy-20"><strong>5. NICREW Dog Backpack Carrier</strong></a></h3>
<p>Finally, the
<strong>NICREW Dog Backpack Carrier</strong>
is designed with ease of use in mind, especially for smaller dogs. Its standout feature is the simple loading and unloading process, which is ideal for dogs that may be anxious or uncooperative when being placed in a carrier.</p>
<dl>
<dt>The breathable mesh sides ensure proper ventilation, making it a great choice for warmer climates or longer hikes where overheating could be a concern.</dt>
<dt><strong>Benefits</strong></dt>
<dd>The ease of use is a significant advantage, especially for dogs that are not used to being carried. The breathable design keeps your dog cool.</dd>
</dl>
<ul>
<li><strong>Cons</strong>: It is not suitable for larger breeds, and the lack of additional storage may require you to carry extra bags.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h3>
<p>Choosing the right dog backpack carrier for hiking ensures that both you and your furry friend can enjoy the great outdoors comfortably and safely.</p>
<p>By considering key factors like comfort, durability, size, safety, and ease of use, and by exploring the top products available, you can find the perfect carrier for your needs.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Dog Beds</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/best-dog-beds/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/best-dog-beds/</guid>
      <description>A dog that has comfortable bedding (best dog beds) is always a happily living pet, and it will definitely bond with the owner and other households amazingl...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A dog that has comfortable bedding (best dog beds) is always a happily living pet, and it will definitely bond with the owner and other households amazingly well.</p>
<ul>
<li>Selecting the beds is the most crucial process for any dog owner who wishes to transforms its entire lifestyle and boost its daily activeness.
Notably, Dogs Bed Orthopedic comes in varieties of colors such as grey, blue, red, orange, etc. for your optional selection. Check these
flea treatments for dogs
.</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="in-a-hurry-see-these-best-dog-beds"><strong>In a Hurry? See these Best Dog Beds</strong></h1>
<p>[amazon bestseller=&ldquo;Best Dog Beds&rdquo; items=&ldquo;2&rdquo; template=&ldquo;table&rdquo;]</p>
<h2 id="1-our-1-picksheri-high-bolster-machine-washable-calming-dog-bed"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07P6DQMQ4/?tag=p-policy-20">1. Our #1 Pick:Sheri High-Bolster, Machine Washable, Calming Dog Bed</a></h2>
<p>[amazon box=&ldquo;B07P6DQMQ4&rdquo; template=&ldquo;horizontal&rdquo;]
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jRA93UualfM">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jRA93UualfM</a></p>
<h2 id="2-2-pick-furhaven-memory-foam--orthopedic-dog-bed"><strong>2. #2 Pick: Furhaven Memory-Foam &amp; Orthopedic Dog Bed</strong></h2>
<p>[amazon box=&ldquo;B0759JPRKY&rdquo; template=&ldquo;horizontal&rdquo;]
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NH3nGxPpPkM">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NH3nGxPpPkM</a></p>
<h2 id="3-3-pick-big-barker-7-pillow-dog-bed-headrest-edition"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0786PVJQS/?tag=p-policy-20">3. #3 Pick: Big Barker 7&quot; Pillow Dog Bed (Headrest Edition)</a></h2>
<p>[amazon box=&ldquo;B0786PVJQS&rdquo; template=&ldquo;horizontal&rdquo;]
Big Barker is our
number one dog bed
that features a high-density therapeutic foam that gives your pet dog a comfortable sleep without any cases of spinal or back pain.</p>
<ul>
<li>Its exceptional top quality and sturdy cover are nicely weaved for easier removal when washing.</li>
<li>The Big Barker is extra-large in size (48 x 60)to accommodate large dogs as well.
Moreover, the product is long-lasting (durable) as its able to retain over 94% of its original shape for more than 10 years.</li>
<li>The USA handmade product is incompressible (wont flatten) thus can sustain several pets without a problem.</li>
<li>Yourpet dogwill definitely enjoy the headrest that this bed comes with.
The Big Barker is specially designed to help relieve your dog&rsquo;s joint pain, back pain, or alleviate conditions such as hip dysplasia and arthritis.
In addition, this product comes in a variety of impressive
colors to select from as well as different sizes
(large, extra-large or giant XXL)
This dog bed is 100% washable (easier to clean). The soft micro-fibers that are sandwiched in the Big Barker make it waterproof.
The Good:</li>
<li>100% washable  easier to clean</li>
<li>High-density therapeutic foam</li>
<li>Comfortable  has a soft microfiber cover.</li>
<li>Durable- 10 years service</li>
<li>Nice design and variety of colors</li>
<li>Large in size and has a headrest</li>
<li>The top-quality USA made</li>
<li>Calibrated for medium and large dogs
The Bad:</li>
<li>Not suitable for small dogs
Read Also:
Flea Treatment for Cats</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="4-friends-forever-orthopedic-dog-bed-lounge-sofa"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B01LYMYKHW/?tag=p-policy-20">4. Friends Forever Orthopedic Dog Bed Lounge Sofa</a></h2>
<p>[amazon box=&ldquo;B01LYMYKHW&rdquo; template=&ldquo;horizontal&rdquo;]
Lounge Sofa is a forever luxurious night sleep for your lovely pet dog. It is aesthetically designed using classically soft, baby mattress foam that will give your dog continuous comfort while relaxing.</p>
<ul>
<li>The top-quality khaki cover additionally gives your pet exceptional therapy while asleep.</li>
<li>The middle-grade foam comes in various sizes, from small to giant XXL. Therefore, this product can be used by any dog size as long as you make the right considerations.
The Lounges bolster lining gives this dog bed a couch design, which provides back orthopedic therapy and helps nurse back pain, leg joints, and aid in supporting its neck and head nicely.
The lounge sofa comes in four impressive colors, i.e., Pewter, Cocoa, Vanilla, and Khaki Beige, that will help bo of pet&rsquo;s confidence pet psychologically.
Importantly, the foam mattress and strongly stitched cover are 100% waterproof  your dog urine will spill over instead of penetrating.</li>
<li>The easy-to-clean (hand or machine cleaning) top cover can easily remove any time.</li>
<li>Moreover, it has anti-tear and hair resistance properties that help secures your dogs skin perfectly well without any removal.
Notably, this dog bed is manufactured with slip resistance and a non-skid base (adds extra friction) to prevent slipping when the dog jumps over it.
The Good:</li>
<li>Durable and 100% washable</li>
<li>Non-skid and Non-slip base</li>
<li>Variety of sizes  from small to XXL</li>
<li>Bolster couch design</li>
<li>Four impressive colors</li>
<li>Strongly stitched softcover</li>
<li>Exceptional comfort  baby soft foam mattress</li>
<li>100% waterproof
The Bad:</li>
<li>Slightly expensive
Related:
Can Humans Get Ear Mites from Dogs?</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="5-sealy-lux-quad-layer-orthopedic-dog-bed"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B00G3D4S3S/?tag=p-policy-20">5. Sealy Lux Quad Layer Orthopedic Dog Bed</a></h2>
<p>[amazon box=&ldquo;B00G3D4S3S&rdquo; template=&ldquo;horizontal&rdquo;]
The pro-charcoal base Sealy Lux is a classical ideal dog bed that features a high-quality, incompressible mattress that is extra-hardened to improve its lifespan.</p>
<ul>
<li>The dog bed features a nice impressive couch design that enables your dog to lean backward at will.</li>
<li>This therapeutic exercise aids in joints massage and nursing of the backbone, especially for a dog suffering from arthritis or spinal injuries.
Sealy Lux has anti-slip and non-skid base properties that help prevent
bed movement when your dog jumps
or plays on the couch.
The strong quad-layer mattress is also 100% waterproof. Also, the
bed features a nice multi-colored soft
cover that is easier to remove and clean.
This product is machine washable and comes with odor absorbing properties that help keep your environment odor-free.
Youll appreciate the overall net weight of Sealy Lux as it wont weigh you down when relocating. Moreover, the bed has a flat top-pad designed to create a puppies-run field.
The energy gel incorporated in this product always keeps away any excess heat generated on the couch when your pet dog is asleep, thus leaving it ever fresh.
The Good:</li>
<li>Waterproof and easy to clean softcover</li>
<li>Comfortable  quad-layer foam mattress</li>
<li>Budget-friendly and orthopedic support</li>
<li>Odor absorbing and machine washable</li>
<li>Heat cooling energy gel</li>
<li>Multiple-color options</li>
<li>Anti-slip and non-skid base properties</li>
<li>Durable high-density foam</li>
<li>Classic impressive couch design
The Bad:</li>
<li>Not Suitable for very large dogs</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="6-kopeks-7-inch-thick-orthopedic-dog-bed"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B01MRICFU2/?tag=p-policy-20">6. Kopeks 7-Inch Thick Orthopedic Dog Bed</a></h2>
<p>[amazon box=&ldquo;B01MRICFU2&rdquo; template=&ldquo;horizontal&rdquo;]
Kopeks is a 100% orthopedic dog bed designed to make your dogs sleep extra comfortable.
It features top-quality, hypoallergenic memory foam that is self-hardened to prevent any possible flattening while in use (durable).</p>
<ul>
<li>The soft plush outer cover encompasses a simple zip mechanism that allows quick removal when cleaning.</li>
<li>Moreover, the cover is specially designed with a non-skid base to avoid any movement when pushed along.
The anti-slip rubber bottom of Kopeks is slightly raised and adds extra friction to allow more stability.
Actually, this product also comes with soft, strongly stitched water-resistant inner liners to keep the machine washable orthopedic mattress always clean and fresh.
You will enjoy optional product selection since Kopeks comes in three impressive colors (grey, brown, or Combinations).
The raised pillow cushion end of Kopeks provides an extra head or neck rest for your pet when asleep.
Moreover, this bed is manufactured in large sizes (50x34x7) and thus would be best used by medium or large size dogs.
The Good:</li>
<li>Hypoallergenic memory foam</li>
<li>The washable waterproof outer cover</li>
<li>Best designed for large dogs</li>
<li>Anti-slip rubber base and non-skid bottom</li>
<li>Strongly stitched water-resistant inner liners</li>
<li>3 cushioned pillow for headrest</li>
<li>Machine washable and 7 thickness</li>
<li>Comfortable and durable</li>
<li>Self-hardened to prevent flattening</li>
<li>Several color options  brown, grey</li>
<li>Top Quality
The Bad:</li>
<li>Not suitable for puppies
Related:
[Diatomaceous Earth for <a href="/posts/best-dog-backpack-carrier-for-hiking/">Fleas</a> on Dogs](<a href="https://pestpolicy.com/diatomaceous-earth-for-fleas-on-dogs/">https://pestpolicy.com/diatomaceous-earth-for-fleas-on-dogs/</a>)</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="7-shag-vegan-fur-donut-cuddler"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07BB63HBN/?tag=p-policy-20">7. Shag Vegan Fur Donut Cuddler</a></h2>
<p>[amazon box=&ldquo;B07BB63HBN&rdquo; template=&ldquo;horizontal&rdquo;]
The Vegan fur is a <a href="/posts/best-dog-brush-for-short-hair-shedding/">dog</a> bed designed with extra softness to cuddle your pet nicely while asleep.
The product feature a donut (round/rectangular) shape that is highly flexible  this allows your dog to sink in nicely while asleep and makes it generate great warmth.</p>
<ul>
<li>You will definitely like the tender softness Vegan comes with  mainly to cater to your puppys comfort during the cold season.</li>
<li>The water-resistance nylon coating and pet-safe faux fur help deliver unparalleled superior comfort to your dog always.
Moreover, this product is easy to wash (you need to keep it in clean treated water and rinse to dry)
The raised compressible rim creates a curl option that helps massage your pet when jumping or playing, while the super-soft fabrics create relief for both muscles and joints.
The product comes in three main sizes to select from, i.e., extra-large, large, and small. Moreover, youll also have color options to choose from, either between Taupe or Frost.
Importantly, Vegan has an impressive design that creates a sense of security and makes it more cozy &amp; luxurious for your dog&rsquo;s home use.
Notably, Vegan comes with a zipper for easier removal when cleaning.
The Good:</li>
<li>Comfortable and luxurious</li>
<li>Soft curl-safe faux fur</li>
<li>Compressible cozy fabric</li>
<li>Muscle and joint relief therapy</li>
<li>Variety of sizes- small, large &amp; extra large</li>
<li>Multiple-colors  Taupe, and Frost</li>
<li>Hand or machine washable</li>
<li>Water-resistant and durable</li>
<li>Best for all dogs ages
The Bad:</li>
<li>Requires a carpeted floor</li>
<li>Need frequent cleaning
Related:
Best Tick Collars for Dogs</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="8-furhaven-pet-dog-bed"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07PXTPLNW/?tag=p-policy-20">8. Furhaven Pet Dog Bed</a></h2>
<p>[amazon box=&ldquo;B07PXTPLNW&rdquo; template=&ldquo;horizontal&rdquo;]
Furhaven is a cradle-shaped dog
bed that features a high-density foam mattress
that guarantees long life.
The dual pillow design that comes with Furhaven creates extra comfort since your dog can rest both the legs and head while asleep.</p>
<ul>
<li>The strongly stitch cover is nicely decorated with classical hemming to bring out a great home impression when in use.</li>
<li>Furhaven has a plush faux fur surface that gives your dog ultimate comfort while asleep.
Moreover, the outer cover is specially manufactured with anti-slip and non-skid base material, which prevents possible slipping while your dog jumps or plays with its puppies.
The outer cover of Furhaven is 100% waterproof and easier to remove. Besides, the product can either be washed using the machine or hands.
Importantly, the orthopedic foam grade is vet-approved and has sturdy layers that highly help in muscle massage and joint therapy.
Furhaven is manufactured in all sizes, i.e., small, medium as well as jumbo plus (36x56x8) that will perfectly serve any age of your pet dog.
Notably, the 8 thick foam is self-hardened to withstand extra-weigh without flattening.
The Good:</li>
<li>Variety of colors  cream, gray, or chocolate</li>
<li>Machine or hand washable</li>
<li>Dual cushioned head and footrest</li>
<li>Several sizes-small, medium, large and jumbo plugs</li>
<li>Comfortable  soft faux fur outer cover</li>
<li>Anti-slip and non-skid base properties</li>
<li>100% Waterproof</li>
<li>Extra-thick orthopedic foam grade</li>
<li>Elegant ergonomic design
The Bad:</li>
<li>Unsuitable for a dog with teething issues</li>
<li>Slightly expensive
Related:
<a href="https://pestpolicy.com/best-flea-collar-for-dogs/">Best Flea Collar for Dogs</a></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="9-the-dogs-bed-orthopedic"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0737NN185/?tag=p-policy-20">9. The Dogs Bed Orthopedic</a></h2>
<p>[amazon box=&ldquo;B0737NN185&rdquo; template=&ldquo;horizontal&rdquo;]
When it comes to top-quality single-layer beddings, Dogs Bed Orthopedic is the best product to buy as it comes with an elegant comfy experience that boosts your pets confidence.</p>
<ul>
<li>This dog bed is specially designed to withstand extra-heavy weight without flattening/deformation.</li>
<li>Also, your pet dog will enjoy rolling from either end as it enjoys the soft, luxurious outer covers curling.
The single-layer orthopedic mattress grade is vet approve and will serve you for more than 10 years before any serious damages occur (durable).
Dogs Bed Orthopedic is 100% waterproof and machine washable. The high-density memory foam has a premium 4 thick base riser with anti-slip and non-skid properties to further prevent any slipping and improve base stability.
Dogs Bed Orthopedic is engineered with a therapeutic design to help relieve both joints and back pain on your dog as well as improve its muscle relaxation.
Actually, this product is best for dogs with conditions such as osteochondritis, arthritis, elbow dysplasia, and patellar luxation.
Importantly, this dog bed has strongly stitched end hems that wont come out easily (for teething dogs) and have nice decorations to create a classic visual impression while at home.
The Good:</li>
<li>High-density orthopedic foam mattress</li>
<li>Vet-approved therapeutic foam.</li>
<li>Hand or machine washable outer cover</li>
<li>Classical design and impressive colors</li>
<li>Variety of sizes  from small to extra large</li>
<li>4 ground stabilizer</li>
<li>Best for all dogs ages</li>
<li>Self-hardened cant deform easily</li>
<li>High quality and durable</li>
<li>Waterproof and pain relief
The Bad:</li>
<li>Slightly expensive</li>
<li>No Bolster cushioning
Related:
Best Tick Shampoo for Dogs</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>Having the best dog bed for your pet is very important to make its lifestyle better every day.</p>
<ul>
<li>You will need to consider your pet&rsquo;s age, health condition, and general weight before placing your dog bed order.
Importantly, you should consider the durability and cleaning options of any of these products without forgetting that the best dog bed is the one that will give your pet awesome comfort when asleep.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Dog Brush for Short Hair Shedding</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/best-dog-brush-for-short-hair-shedding/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/best-dog-brush-for-short-hair-shedding/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sometimes
vacuuming
your carpets, floors, or sofas off any dog hair is never enough. It can get tiring and time-consuming, significantly when your dog is shedding excessive hair.</p>
<ul>
<li>But a good with a hairbrush, you can remove the excess hair thats on your dogs coat. Also, if your dog has short and smooth hair, it requires regular grooming.
But, finding the best dog brush for short hair shedding is a challenging task.
<strong>See the top hair combs.�</strong>
[amazon bestseller=&ldquo;Best Dog Brush for Short Hair Shedding&rdquo; items=&ldquo;2&rdquo; template=&ldquo;table&rdquo;]</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="1-1-top-pick-chirpy-pets-grooming-brush-for-short--long-hair"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0178VW3PS/?tag=p-policy-20">1. #1 Top Pick: Chirpy-Pets Grooming Brush for Short &amp; Long Hair</a></h2>
<p>[amazon box=&ldquo;B0178VW3PS&rdquo; template=&ldquo;horizontal&rdquo;]
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=16q683HLMXU">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=16q683HLMXU</a></p>
<h2 id="2-2-pick-pet-neat-dog-de-shedding-dogs-tool"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B01M5DS0Z7/?tag=p-policy-20">2. #2 Pick: Pet-Neat Dog De-shedding Dogs Tool</a></h2>
<p>[amazon box=&ldquo;B01M5DS0Z7&rdquo; template=&ldquo;horizontal&rdquo;]
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4E-eqbZ8b7c">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4E-eqbZ8b7c</a></p>
<h2 id="3-3-pick-crbn-shedding--detangling-brush-for-short-dog-hair"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08C1LFPY4/?tag=p-policy-20">3. #3 Pick: crbn Shedding &amp; Detangling Brush for Short Dog Hair</a></h2>
<p>[amazon box=&ldquo;B08C1LFPY4&rdquo; template=&ldquo;horizontal&rdquo;]
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZSMSs9HHYRk">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZSMSs9HHYRk</a></p>
<h2 id="4-100-natural-boar-bristle-hair-brush-for-short"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B00WNGH08O/?tag=p-policy-20">4. 100% Natural Boar Bristle Hair Brush for Short</a></h2>
<p>[amazon box=&quot;
B00WNGH08O
&quot; template=&ldquo;horizontal&rdquo;]
Next up is Boar Bristle Brush thats great for thin and fine dog hair giving you an excellent shine.</p>
<ul>
<li>The Boar Bristle Brush is an excellent selection as it smoothens the hair while still distributing the scalp&rsquo;s oils.</li>
<li>Boar Bristle Brush�will also be great as itll help separate the dogs hair into smaller sections.
Further, the hair coat will be left smooth and shining.�Its bristles are not too hard to scratch the dog&rsquo;s
scalp.
However, it&rsquo;ll easily massage the scalp while moving through the pet&rsquo;s hair while enhancing natural oils&rsquo; release -
I recommend getting dog beds
.
I would recommend that you employ a tougher comb to detangle the tough hair before using this Boar Bristle Brush. However, this brush will work great for fine and delicate hair, as itll leave it intact.
The tool is lightweight and durable to easily move through the short hair due to the
Schima wood handle.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="5-halova-pet-comb-professional-double-sided-pin"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B074M6BVJQ/?tag=p-policy-20">5. HaloVa Pet Comb, Professional Double Sided Pin</a></h2>
<p>[amazon box=&quot;
B074M6BVJQ
&quot; template=&ldquo;horizontal&rdquo;]
HaloVa Pet Comb has double-sided bristles that also have quality wood. Further, I loved the plastic pin that wont scratch the dogs skin.</p>
<ul>
<li>You&rsquo;ll find this dog brush also comfortable to hold due to the wooden handle.</li>
<li>HaloVa Pet Comb is both durable and strong to allow great grooming while still maintaining good blood circulation in the dogs coat.
Also, the comb&rsquo;s bristle side as itll easily glide (with no static) in the dogs fur.
HaloVa
Pet Comb will help remove any excess hair
, fur, and loose dirt from the dogs topcoat. Like the other two dog brushes above, this model also helps distribute the skin&rsquo;s oils and leave it healthier.</li>
<li>You can use this dog brush&rsquo;s pin side to remove hair tangles for a dog with no undercoats like the poodles.</li>
<li>However, for thick-haired dogs, you should the above reviewed FURminator de-shredding brush.
The bristles on this brush are close together and will be great for short-haired dogs like pug dogs or coarser hair. I noted that the bristle would be appropriate to remove knots and tangles.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="6-furminator-for-dogs-undercoat-deshedding-tool"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0040QW33W/?tag=p-policy-20">6. FURminator for Dogs Undercoat Deshedding Tool</a></h2>
<p>[amazon box=&quot;
B0040QW33W
&quot; template=&ldquo;horizontal&rdquo;]
Topping our list is the FURminator de-shedding brush thatll enable you de-shed your dog and achieve a full-deep dog wash.
You can be assured that youll now stopping your
<a href="https://pestpolicy.com/can-%5Bfleas%5D(/posts/best-cordless-vacuum-for-pet-hair/)-live-in-human-hair/">living space off dog hair</a>
numerous times in a fortnight.
On quality, avoid brushes with bristles made from thin plastics or cheap wood as they&rsquo;ll break easily with short hair such as the chihuahua, Shih Tzu, or the pug <a href="/posts/best-dog-backpack-carrier-for-hiking/">dog</a>.
I would recommend this dog brush for cutting the hair thatll be falling off from your dogs dog onto the furniture, floors, coats, and car.
Luckily, this brush wont cut any hair on the topcoat, and thus the dogs undercoat will breathe easily and regulate the dogs temperature.
For a dog with heavy hair shedding and particularly during spring or fall, you can use the FURminator deShedding brush about 12-15 times per month.</p>
<ul>
<li>But, for light hair shedding, you can use the brush for roughly 15 minutes each time and about 2-3 times every week.</li>
<li>In addition to removing excess dog hair, the FURminator deShedding brush will also remove all the shed coat pieces from the pets skin.
Also, for timid and small dogs, choose the slicker brushes as theyll assist in spreading the natural oils produced on the dogs coat  leaving your pet smart and healthy.
Related:
Best Flea Treatment for Dogs</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="7-chris-christensen-oval-pin-brush-27mm"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B000ES6DJ0/?tag=p-policy-20">7. Chris Christensen Oval Pin Brush, 27mm</a></h2>
<p>[amazon box=&quot;
B000ES6DJ0
&quot; template=&ldquo;horizontal&rdquo;]
The Chris Oval Pin Brush is a wire-pin model thatll prove great for your dog that has medium, curly, or woolly hair like the Shih Tzu or Maltipoo.
Chris Oval Pin Brush is also a light de-shredding tool thats equally firm cushioned and durable.
It&rsquo;s also a highly comfortable dog brush for short hair that wont scratch your dogs skin (due to the smooth tips), but its also stylish.
However, this pin brush model wont readily remove the loose dog hair compared to the de-shedding brushes, but it will be great for just brushing the dogs topcoat.
Further, the brush has rounded pins that lessen the dog&rsquo;s amount of discomfort while brushing it.
Itll easily remove all dirt, spread the body oils, and glide in the dog&rsquo;s coat. Also, you can easily detach the removed hair from the brush pins after youre done.
Related:
<a href="https://pestpolicy.com/best-flea-shampoo-for-dogs/">Best Flea Shampoo for Dogs</a></p>
<h2 id="8-hertzko-self-cleaning-slicker-brush--removes-loose-under-coat"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B00ZGPI3OY/?tag=p-policy-20">8. Hertzko Self Cleaning Slicker Brush  Removes Loose Under-coat</a></h2>
<p>[amazon box=&quot;
B00ZGPI3OY
&quot; template=&ldquo;horizontal&rdquo;]
Hertzko Self Cleaning is a great brush thats compact, strong, and efficient in removing excessive hair on your dogs coat.
Itll easily untangle the difficult hairs with even less pain to your pet with short hair.</p>
<ul>
<li>Luckily, this dog hairbrush has curved bristles to easily remove the excess hair thats on your dogs coat.</li>
<li>This would otherwise make the dog bristles not get overly close to the dogs skin and might even hurt it.
The curved bristles brushing would also enhance better blood flow that will promote faster growth of hair strands. It has retractable blades that are simple to clean.
Further, the dog brush wont slip easily (due to the runner grips) and doesnt stain the homeowners wrists even after extended times.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>For example, you can&rsquo;t use metal de-shedders that are suitable for long-haired dog coats.
You have to consider the price and quality variation for the brushes in the market.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Vacuum for Dog Hair</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/best-vacuum-for-dog-hair/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/best-vacuum-for-dog-hair/</guid>
      <description>Even when healthy, your dog will always shed some hair - use the best vacuum for dog hair. So, the hair that&amp;#39;s dropped on carpets, floors, or sofa may irri...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Even when healthy, your dog will always shed some hair - use the best vacuum for dog hair. So, the hair that&rsquo;s dropped on carpets, floors, or sofa may irritate homeowners or
<a href="https://www.aaaai.org/conditions-treatments/allergies/pet-allergy">cause allergies</a>
.</p>
<ul>
<li>So, in this post, I&rsquo;ve reviewed the quality vacuums for dog hair - (either all-around vacuums, canister vacuums, and upright vacuums).
But most pet owners will first try to regularly
brush
or
shampoo their dog&rsquo;s hair</li>
<li>which might not be effective in some dog coats.
<strong>Check these Vacuum for Dog Hair.�</strong>
[amazon bestseller=&ldquo;Best Vacuum for Dog Hair&rdquo; items=&ldquo;2&rdquo; template=&ldquo;table&rdquo;]</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="1-our-1-pick-bissell-pet-hair-eraser-handheld-vacuum-corded-33a1"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B001EYFQ28/?tag=p-policy-20">1. Our #1 Pick: Bissell Pet Hair Eraser Handheld Vacuum, Corded, 33A1</a></h2>
<p>[amazon box=&ldquo;B001EYFQ28&rdquo; template=&ldquo;horizontal&rdquo;]
Bissell Pet Hair Eraser is excellent in cleaning dog hair, little dirt mess, dog beds, and sofas due to its high suction power.</p>
<ul>
<li>This handheld vacuum model comes with rubber bristles with comb-looking tines to easily take on the dog hair.</li>
<li>Despite have fantastic suction power, this Bissell Pet Hair Eraser allows little mobility due to its short cord.
Besides, it has fewer vacuum attachments such as the flathead attachment and the dog-hair attachment.
Further, because the vacuum is heavy, youll not be able to move it quickly.
Itll help you
kill those bed bugs
and�clean out dirt effectively, but you must place it very close to a powers source because its the corded model.
However, the dog hair tends to cling on the pet hair attachment  and thus might require cleaning after youre done vacuuming and
<a href="https://pestpolicy.com/best-drain-cleaner//">cleaning a clogged drain</a>
.
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bmD-FgVvpMU">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bmD-FgVvpMU</a></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="2-2-pickhoover-windtunnel-t-series-pet-bagged-upright-vacuum"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B001304XKE/?tag=p-policy-20">2. #2 Pick:Hoover WindTunnel T-Series Pet Bagged Upright Vacuum</a></h2>
<p>[amazon box=&ldquo;B003EQ4710&rdquo; template=&ldquo;horizontal&rdquo;]
Hoover WindTunnel T-Series is an Upright�and budget-friendly
vacuum thats great for dog hair
.</p>
<ul>
<li>I love that this vacuum is easy to use and will clean surfaces thoroughly.</li>
<li>Hoover WindTunnel T-Series is an Upright�and budget-friendly vacuum thats great for<a href="https://pestpolicy.com/can-dog-%5Bfleas%5D(/posts/best-dog-backpack-carrier-for-hiking/)-transfer-to-humans/">dog hair</a>.
I love that this vacuum is easy to use and will clean surfaces thoroughly.</li>
<li>I love it for both my regular�housekeepings and for cleaning <a href="/posts/best-dog-beds/">dog</a> hair. Mostdog owners love the�rubber blades and pettools to ease their dog-hair cleaning tasks.
So, if you have dog hair on the sofa or carpet, this Hoover WindTunnel T-Series will clean it up effectively. I consider the vacuums suction to be great and reliable for its purpose.
They will release the waste bag into the bin with just a single touch  in whats referred to as the Clean-Drop technology.
It&rsquo;s lightweight (just 15 pounds) and easy to move around while vacuuming or
killing bed bugs and their babies
.
The vacuum includes the HEPA Media Bag (made from Activated Carbon) allow easy trapping and filtering of dirt and foul odors.
However, remember to replace the vacuum bag when it&rsquo;s filled with dog hair.
Further, clean the vacuum filters regularly to ensure smooth operation to keep both the side and bag compartment working well.
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YgLmDqbgIeo">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YgLmDqbgIeo</a>
Related:
Best Bed Bug Steamer</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="3-3-pickmiele-triflex-hx1-cat-and-dog-battery-powered-bagless"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B075S9NZJL/?tag=p-policy-20">3. #3 Pick:Miele Triflex-HX1 Cat and Dog Battery-Powered Bagless</a></h2>
<p>[amazon box=&ldquo;B08C6JL63D&rdquo; template=&ldquo;horizontal&rdquo;]
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f45MxrWK3LQ">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f45MxrWK3LQ</a></p>
<h2 id="4-bobsweep-pethair-plus-robotic-vacuum-cleaner--mop"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B01JSSGSY6/?tag=p-policy-20">4. BObsweep PetHair Plus Robotic Vacuum Cleaner &amp; Mop</a></h2>
<p>[amazon box=&ldquo;B01JSSGSY6&rdquo; template=&ldquo;horizontal&rdquo;]
Next up is this bObsweep PetHair Plus thats great for cleaning dog hair, mopping, filtering dirt particles, sweeping and general home vacuuming, and also cleaning hardwood flooring.
Luckily, the vacuum has a large dustbin (about 1100 mL), which will guarantee to hold a large amount of dog hair and other dirt types before you get to the next replacement.</p>
<ul>
<li>The full command remote feature is a unique feature thats mainly on this vacuum.</li>
<li>Itll allow you to program the vacuum machine to undertake automatic cleaning over its pre-determined area.
However, bObsweep PetHair Plus is one of the most massive vacuums from diameter and height.
Therefore, most dog owners find that this vacuum will be more challenging to move to restricted areas such as under low-height chairs and sofas.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="5-dyson-ball-animal-upright-vacuum---corded"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B01BGS9JVA/?tag=p-policy-20">5. Dyson Ball Animal Upright Vacuum - Corded</a></h2>
<p>[amazon box=&ldquo;B01BGS9JVA&rdquo; template=&ldquo;horizontal&rdquo;]
Dyson Ball Animal upright is also a great vacuum for your dogs hair, in addition to cleaning hard floors, walls, stairs, and carpets.
I should note that I didnt really like the seemingly &ldquo;ball&rdquo; design as I found it harder to handle  but maybe youll have a different experience.</p>
<ul>
<li>However, this technology makes it easier to move to difficult areas.</li>
<li>On cleaning, the vacuums hose and the wand will release gently with just a single try.
However, this is not a budget-friendly type of vacuum cleaners.
Luckily, this model does not have switches and knobs that allow the machine to vacuum different sanction levels and flooring  it does this automatically.
If you have an allergy, then this upright vacuum comes with a fantastic sealed system thatll suck up all the allergens, dust, and dirt.</li>
<li>Therefore, this model will be excellent for pet owners who have allergies and Asthma.</li>
<li>The massive weight will ensure that the vacuumcleaner wont easily toppleover when youre working.
Further, youll have about 50 feet from a combination of the extendable hose plus the power cord. Check the
shark vacuum for pet hair
.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="6-shark-rotator-powered-lift-away-truepet-nv752"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B00X7R1FZ2/?tag=p-policy-20">6. Shark Rotator Powered Lift-Away TruePet (NV752)</a></h2>
<p>[amazon box=&ldquo;B00X7R1FZ2&rdquo; template=&ldquo;horizontal&rdquo;]</p>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>Good vacuums must: (1) excellently suction dog hair (with filters &amp; suctions), (2) have a central system that&rsquo;s high-powered, and (3) and strong uprights -
<a href="https://pestpolicy.com/best-dog-beds/">to control bugs use dog beds</a>
.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can Dog Fleas Transfer to Humans</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/can-dog-fleas-transfer-to-humans/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/can-dog-fleas-transfer-to-humans/</guid>
      <description>Recently my friend, Jane, got a healthy-looking dog.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Recently my friend, Jane, got a healthy-looking dog.
<strong>Sadly</strong>
, the dog was flea-infested. Jane applied
flea shampoo
on the dog to save the situation.
But, she&rsquo;s still worried whether &ldquo;Dog <a href="/posts/dog-has-fleas-and-sleeps-in-my-bed/">Fleas</a> Transfer to Humans?&rdquo; Can the bugs jump/ bite him, his kids, or his wife? I seek to answer these questions in this short post.
<strong>The simple answer is Yes</strong>
.
<a href="https://pestpolicy.com/best-%5Bflea%5D(/posts/how-to-tell-if-your-dog-has-fleas/)-combs-for-dogs/">Dog fleas (Ctenocephalides�canis</a>
) will sometimes jump onto humans, bite them and suck blood - although they mainly suck blood from dogs and cats.
Scientific research
shows
that fleas will quickly move to another and
hitchhike people as they move to other houses
,�just like the
<a href="https://ohioline.osu.edu/factsheet/HYG-2081-11">over 2,000 flea species</a>
.
[amazon bestseller=&ldquo;Best Fleas Killers&rdquo; items=&ldquo;2&rdquo; template=&ldquo;table&rdquo;]</p>
<h2 id="can-dog-fleas-transfer-to-humans-peoples-hair">Can Dog Fleas Transfer to Humans? People&rsquo;s hair?</h2>
<p>A
quick google search on whether�Can Dog Fleas
Transfer to Humans - most related information available online is false. Some articles claim that only dog fleas (Ctenocephalides canis) attack canines and that only the
*Pulex irritans *
can
bite human
beings.
<em>Pulex irritans</em>
feed on blood (humans, dogs, and cats) and will bite human beings (leaving itchy red bumps ) and only
*survive on human blood. *
<em>Fleas�</em>
transmit tapeworms, cause flea allergy dermatitis (FAD) and anemia. Control
fleas on clothes
and
kill massive flea infestation with foggers
.</p>
<h2 id="fleas-hitchhike-your-clothes-and-hair">Fleas Hitchhike, your clothes and hair.</h2>
<p>First, fleas lack
wings and thus do not fly
but jump from one host to another or hiding place. Also, fleas have rough bristles that allow them to attach themselves to the pets (
cat or dog
) fur. You can prevent this by using appropriate
human flea repellents
.
There are about 320 flea species: in the US, Ctenocephalides felis is most common. Ctenocephalides canis is common in Europe. Pigs mainly host the above two
flea species all bite
human beings, but Pulex irritans.
The insects jump about 16 inches long and eight inches high to land on any host to bite and suck blood. Notably,
fleas will mainly suck blood from any host
, humans, wild animals, or pets (cats and dogs).
Any
flea brought in by your dogs will hide
under the furniture until their larvae if fully developed. Finally, the fleas hatch and sense your warm blood and take a
bite on your skin
to suck blood. Also,
humans carry fleas to another home
on their hair and clothes.
Fleas will bite
your ankles and legs, which you see if you walk into a house infested with a massive flea population. Theyll leave some rid itchy round bumps on the location they bite.</p>
<h2 id="signs-of-fleas-transfer-from-your-dog">Signs of fleas transfer from your dog.</h2>
<p>So, howll you know when
fleas have transferred from your dog
to you or your family member? Well, first check if your dog is continuously scratching its skin and fur. Thats the first
sign because flea
bites will cause itching on both human beings and dogs.
Also, check whether your
dog has signs of allergies due to a massive flea
infestation. Further, if you note some
flea dirt
and red bumps on the dog, you should be alert that a flea attack could be coming over to you from the dog.
Brush or comb your dog keenly to check whether the comb comes out with some brown color when passed on a white surface - to avoid such purchase
good dog beds
.</p>
<h2 id="prevent-fleas-on-your-dogs">Prevent fleas on your dogs</h2>
<p>Ive pointed above that you can use flea bombs
to control massive flea
infestations in your rooms. However, to
control fleas on your dogs
,
Advantage II
and
Frontline Plus
have proven to the top models. You can also use a
flea spray for your yards
.</p>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>Fleas take host on your dog
, and thus, whenever you come too close to the pet, the fleas could jump over to you looking for a blood source.
However, fleas (apart from
<em>Pulex irritans</em>
) cannot
<a href="https://pestpolicy.com/can-fleas-live-in-human-hair/">live on human</a>
blood and thus will have to jump off to an appropriate host, particularly after sucking some of your blood.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can You Use Dog Shampoo on Cats</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/can-you-use-dog-shampoo-on-cats/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/can-you-use-dog-shampoo-on-cats/</guid>
      <description>This article will answer the question, &amp;#39;can you use dog shampoo on cats?&amp;#39;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This article will answer the question, &ldquo;can you use dog shampoo on cats?&rdquo;</p>
<p>Unlike dogs, cats don&rsquo;t need to be bathed as often; they
keep their fur healthy and clean
using their tongue.</p>
<p>So, caring for a cat can be easy, but there are some instances where your feline friend needs a more intensive shampoo, maybe to remove bad smells or contamination.</p>
<p>So, if you&rsquo;re worried if you can use dog shampoo for your cats; this article is for you!</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>The answer: Simply, NO. Most dog shampoos have harsh chemicals, ingredients (like tar and permethrin), and high pH that can be toxic to cats.�</strong></li>
<li><strong>Thus, only you use feline-friendly�shampoo for grooming your kitty. Also, If you use dog products on your cat, consult with your vet first before trying it.</strong>
Dog shampoo and other flea-control products (even those with natural ingredients) put cats at a
<a href="https://www.quora.com/Is-it-ok-to-use-dog-shampoo-on-cats">greater health risk</a>
than it does to its canine cousins.</li>
</ul>
<p>[amazon bestseller=&ldquo;Best Dog Shampoos&rdquo; items=&ldquo;2&rdquo; template=&ldquo;table&rdquo;]</p>
<h2 id="why-must-you-avoid-using-dog-shampoo-on-cats">Why Must You Avoid Using Dog Shampoo On Cats?</h2>
<p>Many people wonder why they should bathe their cats as self-grooming is a natural feline instinct. There are two things you might want to consider:</p>
<ul>
<li>You may need to wash off something your cat got into and get it out of his fur so that he won&rsquo;t ingest it when grooming.</li>
<li>The second reason, which is probably more common, is that your cat may have <a href="/posts/best-dog-backpack-carrier-for-hiking/">fleas</a> or other parasites.
So, what should you use instead?</li>
<li>If you&rsquo;re on the fence about whether or not your pet needs assistance with its grooming routine, at least consider using natural products that are skin-great for cats.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="1-harmful-chemicals-like-permethrin-and-tar">1. Harmful Chemicals like Permethrin and Tar</h3>
<p>Using <a href="/posts/best-dog-beds/">dog</a> shampoo on cats is not a good idea because some shampoos contain chemicals that are harmful to cats.</p>
<p>Some of these chemicals include permethrin, selenium sulfite, tea tree oils, and coal tar, etc.</p>
<p>You should not use dog shampoo on cats, just like you would never use baby shampoo on a cat to avoid the
<a href="https://pestpolicy.com/can-i-use-baby-shampoo-on-my-cat/">long-lasting effects</a>
.</p>
<ul>
<li>Some shampoos that are safe for cats include Oatmeal &amp; Aloe Shampoo, Herbal Conditioning Hair Rinse, Honeydew Melon Pet Shampoo, and more.</li>
<li>If you have a kitten or older cat with long hair then it is best to use some type of conditioner after shampooing especially if your home is dry.
Some people also leave the conditioner in their cat&rsquo;s fur after washing it to prevent tangles and matting, but this is not necessary unless your cat has long hair that gets tangled easily.</li>
</ul>
<p>For an alternative option for you and your pet, you can use some type of olive oil as a moisturizer.</p>
<h3 id="2-ph-differences-cats-ph-6">2. pH Differences (Cats pH 6)</h3>
<p>One can answer the question of whether one should use dog shampoo on cats by considering how pH levels are different for each animal.</p>
<p>The pH balance of an animal&rsquo;s coat is unique to its species. Dogs have a different pH level than cats, for example, and this denotes the coat&rsquo;s acidity.</p>
<p>Can you use dog shampoo on cats? No, this is not a recommended practice. Dogs have a higher pH level than cats and even humans!</p>
<ul>
<li>Dogs pH 7.5</li>
<li>cats pH 6</li>
<li>humans pH 5.5
When making shampoos it is important to take into consideration the pH levels of its various components and how the final product will affect the pet.</li>
</ul>
<p>When it comes to animal grooming products, each type is made with different pH that is appropriate for the species.</p>
<p>If you use a shampoo labeled as dog shampoo on your cat, it might wash off his fur and cause health issues - like damaging their skin.</p>
<p>Related:
20 Mule Team Borax Pest Control</p>
<h3 id="3-cause-damage-to-sensitive-skin">3. Cause damage to Sensitive skin</h3>
<p>Dogs and cats have different skin needs, and it is not recommended that you use dog-specific products on your cat because it can damage their skin and fur, which will impact how they groom themselves.</p>
<p>Using dog shampoo on cats may attract parasites that are normally found on dogs and so cleaning or pest control will be much more difficult.</p>
<p>Are you considering herbal dog shampoos for bathing the cat? Please don&rsquo;t! They have natural oils such as tea-tree oil that are toxic to cats but may be safe for humans and dogs.</p>
<ul>
<li>Important, cats and kittens lack the enzymes required to break down these natural oils and so they can become toxic if they remain on your cat for long.
This is the case even with diluted oils as they&rsquo;ll accumulate to harmful levels that will end up blocking the cat&rsquo;s skin pores and it&rsquo;s harming its fur texture.</li>
<li>Sadly, the kitten&rsquo;s coat will also absorb these natural oils leading to skin damage.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="4-harmful-insecticides">4. Harmful Insecticides</h3>
<p>Some dog shampoos have pesticides or insecticides to deal with flea or
tick problems
. Sometimes these chemicals can hurt cats.</p>
<p>For example, ingredients meant to control fleas or flies on dogs may be harmful to your cat.</p>
<p>Permethrin is an insecticide that is often used in dog shampoo. It&rsquo;s harmful to cats, especially if the cat comes into contact with it for a prolonged period of time.</p>
<p>So, what&rsquo;s the alternative?</p>
<ul>
<li>Well, use pyrethrin shampoos on your cat (but in lower quantities) as it&rsquo;ll be safer compared to the dog shampoos.
There are specific dog shampoos manufactured for the needs of dogs, and it can be tempting to use these products on cats.</li>
</ul>
<p>However, dog shampoo contains harsh chemicals that may damage a cat&rsquo;s skin or cause &ldquo;dandruff.&rdquo; If your cat has an open wound, avoid using these dog shampoos altogether.</p>
<h2 id="alternative-natural-products-to-wash-your-cat">Alternative Natural Products to Wash your Cat?</h2>
<p>Organic shampoos are usually the best choice for your pet. They use a variety of natural ingredients that will clean and condition their fur at the same time without leaving any harmful residue behind.</p>
<p>Organic shampoos also typically have less concentrated suds, which means you don&rsquo;t need to worry about them damaging sensitive skin on your cat&rsquo;s face or neckline.</p>
<p>You can find organic shampoo in most major retailers like Whole Foods Market, Costco, Trader Joe&rsquo;s, Walmart, and Target so it shouldn&rsquo;t be hard to locate one near you!</p>
<ul>
<li>Harsh chemicals may strip away essential oils from their coat</li>
<li>Pets with allergies could react poorly if they come into contact with these products during bathtime</li>
<li>Added fragrances should
I recommend some of these natural substitutes to wash your cat safely and effectively;</li>
<li>Lemon Spray</li>
<li>Aloe vera juice</li>
<li>Cedar chips</li>
<li>Peppermint extract</li>
<li>Apple Cider Vinegar
So, to give you cat that clean wash, heal its wounds, and hydrates their skin use a cat shampoo and ensure its age-appropriate.</li>
<li>It&rsquo;ll be a plus if the cat shampoo or soap also has cat-friendly pest control ability such as exterminating fleas, flies, and ticks.
Related:
IGR for Fleas</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>In summary on the question; can you use dog shampoo on cats? No, the cat-specific products will provide the best results for them during bath time.</p>
<p>You should only wash kittens with shampoos made especially for cats as well because they are more delicate and need gentler cleaning agents.</p>
<p>If you want your pet to feel clean after its bathtime session, I recommend some of these natural substitutes to wash your cat;</p>
<ul>
<li>Lemon spray (use this instead of bleach),</li>
<li>Aloe vera juice (great for dry or irritated skin)</li>
<li>Cedar chips (for waterproofing),</li>
<li>Peppermint extract(keeps fleas away).</li>
<li>Apple Cider Vinegar
I would love to hear what products other pet owners have found that they like best for their kitty!</li>
</ul>
<p>What natural alternatives did you try?�Let me know in the comments below or at
<a href="https://twitter.com/pestpolicy">@PestPolicy)</a>
on Twitter !&quot;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dog Ear Mites Vs Yeast Infection</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/dog-ear-mites-vs-yeast-infection/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/dog-ear-mites-vs-yeast-infection/</guid>
      <description>Dog Ear Mites</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[<a href="/posts/best-dog-backpack-carrier-for-hiking/">Dog</a> <a href="/posts/best-ear-mite-medicine-for-dogs/">Ear</a> Mites](<a href="https://www.petmd.com/dog/conditions/infectious-parasitic/how-treat-ear-mites-dogs">https://www.petmd.com/dog/conditions/infectious-parasitic/how-treat-ear-mites-dogs</a>)
and
<a href="https://vcahospitals.com/know-your-pet/yeast-dermatitis-in-dogs">Yeast Infections</a>
are major problems facing most dog/pet owners.</p>
<p>Could you be having challenges while differentiating between the Dog Ear Mites and Yeast Infections? Then, this article is for you.
<strong>Dog Ear Mites (also known as Otodectes cynotis mites) is a parasitic infection that is caused by tiny parasites called ear mites.�</strong>
**It is characterized by red inflammation and severe irritations. **
<strong>On the other hand, Yeast Infections is caused by growth of yeast (fungus) in the ear canal and its characterized by odor and brown greasy stinking discharge.�</strong>
Related:
<a href="https://pestpolicy.com/best-ear-mite-medicine-for-dogs/">Best Ear Mite Medicine for Dogs</a></p>
<h2 id="differences-between-dog-ear-mites-vs-yeast-infection">Differences between Dog Ear Mites Vs Yeast Infection</h2>
<h3 id="1-cause-of-infections">1. Cause of Infections.</h3>
<p>Dog Ear Mites (
<strong>also known as Otodectes cynotis mites</strong>
) is caused by very tiny parasites (you may not see them with your naked eye  you need a microscope) called ear mites which are classified under mange. These parasites feed on wax within the ear lobe and ear canal causing severe irritations and red inflammations/swellings that are very painful on touch.
<strong>On the other hand, Yeast infection</strong>
is caused by yeast growth within the ear canal. The Yeast infections can also result from the following sources: Trapped debris or water in the ear canal, Allergens such as dust, cigarette smoke, cleaning products, molds or feathers.</p>
<p>Moreover, Increased amount of oil produced in the skin, Medications such as corticosteroids, Fungus sources, Chemotherapy, Exposing dog to hot, humid weather, Using medical catheter or Weaken immune system will lead to yeast infections too. These clog the ear way-causing odor and a brownish greasy stinking discharge from the inner ear.</p>
<h3 id="2-signs-and-symptoms">2. Signs and Symptoms.</h3>
<p><strong>Dog Ear Mites</strong>
is characterized by the following signs and symptoms: Severe scratching of both inner and outer ear parts, Reddish Inflammations that may be bleeding, Clamps in the ear canal and Frequent itching at neck region.</p>
<p>Other symptoms of Dog Ear Mites include: Continuous ear irritations, Bleeding on the swellings, Spot falling of dogs hair at the ear region Dog abnormally shaking its head severally and a General body scratching like neck, head or back region.
<strong>Contrary, the Yeast Infections</strong>
is characterized by the following signs and symptoms: Clogged Ear Canal, Foul Odor coming from the ears, Greasy sticking discharge from the ears, Unbalance movement, Pawing of ears and Elephant Skin  thin skin.</p>
<p>Other Yeast infections symptoms include: Recurrent of otitis externa, Drooling and Hair loss on infected ears, Licking infected ears, Dark pigmented ear lobes Hyperpigmentation, Scabs and crusts on the ear, Change in skin color and texture, Crusty, flaky and scaly skin.
<strong>However,</strong>
Dog Ear Mites and Yeast Infections have the following similarities in signs and symptoms: General body weakness, Body hair loss in other parts, Loss of appetite, Dog generates hearing problems, Laxity or dog frequently rolling abnormally.</p>
<h3 id="3-diagnosis-process">3. Diagnosis process.</h3>
<p>To diagnose your dog Against Ear Mites, your will need to Use veterinary or Ear mites professional. This is the best way. The veterinarian may ask you some question concerning your dogs health in order to assess some of the possible cause or symptoms.</p>
<p>Also, the vet may carry out a clinical examination on your dog. He/she may take a swab or the ear canal to check what could be going on in there. Moreover, the veterinarian may try to identify presence of ear mites in your dogs ears using special equipment such as microscope or an otoscope.
<strong>On the other hand</strong>
, you may not need to necessarily need to involve veterinarian to carry out Yeast Infection Diagnosis (though its important). However, you can use the following techniques to attest yeast infections:
** Use of Acetate tape - **
Apply the acetate tape on the dogs ears/skin to collect any yeast sample that could be available.
**Through Impression smear - **
This requires you to press gently, a microscope slide, to collect yeast organisms samples on the dogs ear/skin;
<strong>Use of Cotton swab sample</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Using a wet cotton swap, rub on the dogs ear to collect yeast sample or
<strong>By Skin scraping</strong></li>
<li>Using a scalpel/blade, scarp the ear skin gently to collect yeast samples.</li>
</ul>
<p>You can also carry out
** Skin biopsy. **
Using a biopsy punch, obtain a small skin on the dogs ear and check on the yeast presence (in this technique, it is important to engage a veterinarian or specialist).</p>
<p>It is necessary to bring other pets for checkup so that treatment can begin immediately (in case they are found infected).
<em>NB: Ensure that you always put on the medical/protection gears while carrying out any diagnosis. Label all diagnosed dogs/pets appropriately.�</em></p>
<h3 id="4-treatment-methods">4. Treatment Methods</h3>
<p><strong>Dog Ear Mites can be treated</strong>
using various ear applications. These solutions are manufactured with ability to get rid of the eggs, larvae and adult ear mites.</p>
<p>You will need to pour or smear the product on the affected part and leave it to work on contact. Ensure that you select the right medicine and, where possible, consult the veterinary for advice.</p>
<p>Preferably, you can use: Tree Tea Oil (it is anti-inflammatory, anti-septic and can repel ear mites), Jojoba oil (It is anti-bacterial, antiseptic and natural safe solution) or try a homemade vinegar and water mixture for your Dog Ear Mite Treatment.
<strong>Contrary, Yeast Infections can be treated</strong>
using the following ways:
<strong>Oral Medications -</strong>
For advance yeast infections, you can use veterinary recommended oral antifungal medications such as terbinafine, fluconazole, Loft says or ketoconazole.</p>
<p>You can combine them with various antibacterial infections since most of ear infections are associated with bacteria too. You will need to administer several dose for complete treatment.
**Tropical Medication - **
Yeast Infested ears are greasy and removes stinking discharge. You will need to clean the dog with shampoo containing selenium benzoyl peroxide or sulfide first.</p>
<p>After that, bathe your dog using anti-fungal shampoo containing ketoconazole, miconazole or chlorhexidine 3-5 times daily for two to twelve weeks. This product will remove the yeast infections and maintain healthy ears for your dogs.
**Use of Coconut oil - **
This is a popular method since coconut oil contains both anti-bacteria and anti-fungal components which helps cure yeast infections.</p>
<p>The oil also ensure the ear skin is always soft and smooth for quick healing.
<em>NB: All treated dogs/pets should be kept separate from others/healthy ones. Medicines should be kept safe and away from children.</em></p>
<h2 id="similarities-between-dog-ear-mites-vs-yeast-infection">Similarities between Dog Ear Mites Vs Yeast Infection</h2>
<p>Similarities between Dog Ear Mites and Yeast Infections can be seen in the following areas:</p>
<h3 id="1-transmission">1. Transmission.</h3>
<p>Dog Ear Mites and Yeast Infections are highly contagious. They can be transmitted to other healthy dogs and animals such as cats, rabbits and even rats in similar ways.</p>
<p>The following are ways through which Dog Ear Mites and Yeast Infections can be Transmitted to other animals:</p>
<ul>
<li>Dogs Social interactions such as sleeping or playing together.</li>
<li>Sharing dogs clothes (ear mites/yeast infections can hold on dogs clothes and get transferred to the other healthy dog)</li>
<li>Through bathing them together (Sharing washing clothe  These may carry ear mites or yeast infections).
It is important to note that Dog Ear Mites and Yeast Infections are mainly transmitted on contact. You must minimize the interaction of ear mites/Yeast infected dog with others even if you will have keep it away completely.
<strong>NB: Dog Ear Mites cannot be transmitted to humans</strong></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="2-prevention-methods">2. Prevention methods.</h3>
<p>Both, the Dog Ear Mites and Yeast Infection shares common preventive methods. You can therefore use any of the following ways to prevent Dog Ear Mites and Yeast Infection on your dogs:</p>
<ul>
<li>Carry out frequent medical checkup from a veterinary or specialist.</li>
<li>Clean your dog regularly with anti-fungal or anti-bacteria shampoo that are vet approved.</li>
<li>Disinfect your dogs kennel often.</li>
<li>Avoid visiting crowded area with your dog.</li>
<li>Avoid using any product that is allergy source.</li>
<li>Trimming your dogs hair and keeping it neat.</li>
<li>Disinfect your dogs kennel with Ear mites/Yeast Infection disinfectants.</li>
<li>Avoid social interaction of your dog with others though playing.</li>
<li>Ensure that dogs clothes are well cleaned and treated.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="3-side-effects">3. Side Effects.</h3>
<p>Dog Ear mites and Yeast Infections are dangerous infections if not treated immediately. They cause continuous irritation and severe pain on your dog  this creates discomfort.</p>
<p>There is high loss of blood that is associated with Dog Ear Mites and Yeast Infections  this may lead to anemia.�Clogging caused by yeast infections and Dog Ear Mites in the ear canal as well as eardrum may cause deafness to your dog at long run.</p>
<p>Moreover, continuous ill health resulting from Dog Ear Mites and Yeast Infections may lead to general body weakness and this may eventually kill your dog.
<strong>Importantly</strong>
, these two infections spread rapidly thus overcoming your dogs healthy life in a couple of days. Research shows that most dogs die of Ear Mites and Yeast Infections yearly if not addressed at their mild stage.</p>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>Dog Ears Mites are infections caused by parasites called ear mites whereas yeast infections are initiated by yeast and fungi growth within the ear canal.</p>
<p>Though Dog Ear Mites and Yeast Infections have close similarities in symptoms, there exist great disparities. You must, therefore, maintain close diagnosis to help you offer proper medication. Always observe preventive measures highlighted in this article.</p>
<h2 id="sources">Sources:</h2>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3385579/">Dog Ear Mite Infestation: a Possible Problem in Public - NCBI</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.merckvetmanual.com/dog-owners/disorders-affecting-multiple-body-systems-of-dogs/fungal-infections-in-dogs">Fungal Infections in Dogs - Dog Owners - Merck Veterinary</a></li>
<li><a href="https://pdfs.semanticscholar.org/d7de/fd2f45d76a05e38dce1153d104d26e2f0705.pdf">Ear mite infestation in two dogs and its therapy - Semantic</a></li>
</ol>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dog Has Fleas and Sleeps in My Bed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/dog-has-fleas-and-sleeps-in-my-bed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/dog-has-fleas-and-sleeps-in-my-bed/</guid>
      <description>Sleeping with you are cat or dog on the bed is quite cozy and soothing but this may turn out different if the pet has fleas.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sleeping with you are cat or dog on the bed is quite cozy and soothing but this may turn out different if the pet has <a href="/posts/can-dog-fleas-transfer-to-humans/">fleas</a>.</p>
<ul>
<li>Psychological snuggling or sleeping next to your pet has been documented to<a href="https://www.sleepassociation.org/sleep-news/pets-may-help-you-sleep-better/">reduce anxiety and stress</a>from work or school.
So, youre wondering; your dog has fleas and sleeps in my bed, what should you do? Is it safe?
Well, fleas don&rsquo;t generally jump onto humans and bite them but they do occasionally. Therefore if the dog has fleas and it sleeps on your bed, you could end up with a massive <a href="/posts/how-to-tell-if-your-dog-has-fleas/">flea</a> problem, or (at the minimum) the fleas might just bite you while you&rsquo;re sleeping and leave you with itchy or painful skin.
Fleas will bite pets such as cats and dogs
<a href="https://pestpolicy.com/can-dog-fleas-transfer-to-humans/">but will also bite humans</a>
if they share a bed or if you go near there betting that is not flea-treated.</li>
<li>So if youve risen from your bed and you notice that your pet and yourself are scratching continuously, I encourage you to continue reading this article to know the science to check out to know whether you have fleas in the bed.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="details-dog-has-fleas-and-sleeps-in-my-bed">Details: Dog Has Fleas and Sleeps in My Bed</h2>
<p>So if your cat or dog sleeps with you on the bed and they&rsquo;re not
flea-treated
you could be attracting a flea problem around yourself.</p>
<ul>
<li>This is because fleas will jump from the dog to your body and clothes while you are sleeping or after they&rsquo;ve hidden in the bed for some time after the pet leaves.
Flea bites are generally not welcome by most humans because they lead to allergies pain irritation and itching. So, youll need to know the various flea signs and how you
can control fleas on the dogs naturally
or using chemicals.
My friend has two cats and one dog and he believes that they could have picked some fleas from the yard or garden.</li>
<li>Since he and his kids do sleep next to their pets regularly I advised him to use some Seresto Cat flea collars.</li>
<li>Further, the vet advised a flea bath (using flea shampoo that is medicated) for the dogs and also thorough vacuuming of the spaces and washing of the fabrics and bedding.
Using these flea control techniques and conducting a regular spot check of the house for fleas helped eliminate the flea problem within weeks.
Fleas love hiding in the hair or fur of dogs but humans lack such features and thus they won&rsquo;t be a favorite as a hiding place for the bugs.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="signs-that-you-dog-dropped-fleas-on-the-bed">Signs that you Dog Dropped Fleas on the Bed</h2>
<h3 id="1-flea-bites">1. Flea Bites</h3>
<p>Flea bites (itchy red and itchy dots) on your skin will be the first signs that there are fleas in your bed. The bites from fleas are concentrated in one area (clustered) they are itchy and tiny.</p>
<ul>
<li>The bites will generally be on the lower body around the feet, ankles, and shins - largely in a straight line.
Compared to bed bugs that will bite humans around the neck, arms, and face, the flea will generally bite people on their lower bodies.</li>
<li>But fleas can also on areas of the human skin that is moist and warm such as behind the knees
So if youve been sleeping next to your dog, you can also notice some bites (red dots) on the upper body, and around the elbow bends, chest, and face.
For anyone that is allergic please they may experience other side effects that may come with varied symptoms such as;</li>
<li>Shortness of breath signifying anaphylaxis</li>
<li>Extreme and intense itching</li>
<li>Rush</li>
<li>Swelling</li>
<li>Hives</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="2-flea-dirt-on-the-bed">2. Flea Dirt on the Bed</h3>
<p>If you notice black specks that are tiny in size especially after you enjoyed cuddling with your dog you may already have fleas in the bed.
The black specs are the body waste from fleas (flea dirt) which is undigested blood that is released as poop.</p>
<ul>
<li>These specks can be found on pillows, bed frames, and bedsheets.
As the dog walks around your bed during the night it will drop not just the bugs such as fleas but bacteria too.</li>
<li>So, besides bringing flea bites, the dogs sleeping on your bed could also cause the transmission of salmonella and E. coli.
Therefore, it would be advisable to keep dogs off the bed completely or ensure that you bathe them frequently.
But will flea dirt harm kids and adult humans? First, humans will only be harmed by parasites including ticks and fleas if they are bitten on the skin.</li>
<li>However in theory there is a risk of humans getting harmed when they contact or touch the flea dirt (feces).
Another question that homeowners have is why they would see flea dirt on their bed but can&rsquo;t find fleas.</li>
<li>Well, there could have been fleas on the bed at one time but they may have jumped off or were killed through the grooming and licking actions of the dogs.
So tackling the
flea dirt challenge
will require you to go ballistic to control the fleas including bathing the dog with flea shampoo.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="flea-treating-your-bed-and-house">Flea Treating Your Bed and House</h2>
<p>Do you suspect or are sure that there are fleas in your bed you require to wash the bedding using hot water.</p>
<ul>
<li>Speed while dealing with the pest is a critical factor to stop them from multiplying in your residence.
So wash the beddings through a hot cycle with detergent (including all the mattress pads, pillows, blankets, and sheets).</li>
<li>After washing the bedding, you may use a dryer and the Heat will help kill even more fleas.
Also, you should vacuum the mattress thoroughly (and rigorously) including on the underside and its seams. I advise that you repeat the vacuuming process a number of times.</li>
<li>Remember to vacuum the headboard especially if it&rsquo;s made of fabric.
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sLxExsHhV2I">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sLxExsHhV2I</a>
Additional steps you can take to control fleas in the whole bedroom include
using a flea bomb
.
Flea treating the house will ensure you remove the flea eggs and the other place from various places including the carpets.
A product like the Addams house spray will kill bed bugs, ticks, and fleas. The chemical will knock down the fleas in about 5 minutes and offer protection against the pests for about 7 months.
The next product is Adams carpet powder that will kill please in all various life cycle stages. Luckily, each of the packages will flea treat up to 400 square feet (1 - 2 rooms).
Finally, flea-treat they had since the dogs may also carry the bugs from outdoors to the indoor spaces. The product I recommend is the Adams garden spray that will kill ants mosquitoes ticks and fleas for about one month.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="flea-treating-the-dog">Flea Treating the Dog</h2>
<p>So it&rsquo;s also very important that you control fleas that are hosted or hiding on them that&rsquo;s including the dogs.</p>
<h3 id="1-topical-and-oral-flea-control">1. Topical and Oral Flea Control</h3>
<p>Despite that plays will persist and become annoying you can use spot-on treatments and dog flea pills to remove these pests.
However, you must know the stage of the flea life cycle that the flea treatment remedy is aimed at for example it could be targeted at larvae and flea eggs or just the adult fleas.
In addition, other treatments will combine heartworm prevention and flea control in that single remedy.</p>
<h4 id="a-flea-medications-that-require-prescription">a. Flea Medications that require Prescription</h4>
<p>Besides some of the flea treatments may not require a prescription but others will - so it&rsquo;s important to consult the vet on this.</p>
<ul>
<li>However, prescription flea medications are an excellent way to exterminate fleas.
An example is the Bravecto (fluralaner) that will continue killing fleas for about 3 months but its knockdown effect is within 2 hours.
Other flea medications with a first-time knockdown effect of about 30 minutes include the Trifexis and Comfortis which will also continue killing phrase for about 30 days.</li>
<li>Among these three treatments are some that will only kill the flea eggs and thus will contribute to the breaking of the flea life cycle over time.
Also, if your pet is hypersensitive or allergic to flea saliva, I advise you to select a treatment that will target faux adult fleas before they bite on the cat or dog.</li>
<li>Some of the approved products for dogs that have hypersensitivity to flea bites include Vectra 3D and Seresto collar.</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="b-flea-medications-that-dont-require-prescription">b. Flea Medications that Dont require Prescription</h4>
<p>The market has a number of flea-treatment products for your dog that won&rsquo;t require a prescription.</p>
<ul>
<li>But the downside is that most of these non-prescription products could have alone effectiveness compared to the prescription-based alternatives.
Some of the flea treatment products that won&rsquo;t require a prescription include spot-on treatments, oral flea treatments, flea collars, flea sprays, flea powders, and flea shampoos.
I have to note that these remedies are good emergency products for flea treatment on your dog but some owners have reported the persistence of fleas even after using these and prescription products.</li>
<li>An example is theCapstar Flea tabletsthat you will give to your dog orally and it will start killing the fleas in 30 minutes and it is able to exterminate almost 95% of the bug population in just 4 hours.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="2-using-dog-flea-shampoos">2. Using Dog Flea Shampoos</h3>
<p>There are a number of dog shampoos that are formulated to kill fleas and they are considered relatively effective if you use them as directed.
But the effectiveness of the flea shampoo will depend on the ingredients that are used and the procedure used to apply it.</p>
<ul>
<li>Also, avoid bathing the puppies with dog flea shampoo that may have toxic ingredients such as Tea tree.
Awesome check the age of a puppy to determine if it will be able to understand being method and weighted with the flea shampoo for about 10 minutes - depending on how long the flea shampoo directs the application to last.
Finally, after washing the dog with the flea shampoo you can now use a tick and flea comb to help remove all the dead pests from the dog&rsquo;s fur.</li>
<li>Another point to note is that flea shampoos won&rsquo;t provide continued protection for fleas to the dogs and thus you require to use another flea treatment for that purpose.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>So in conclusion it is clear that sleeping next to your dog can have many advantages including stress relief but the pet may also cause flea problems if the animal is flea-infested.</p>
<ul>
<li>So it is important that you the dog before allowing it on your bed. Also, wash and dry the bedding exterminate any fleas left behind.
Flea-treating the yard and your house will also help control the bugs from the surroundings.
Thats all.
Cheers!</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Did My Dog Get Fleas</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-did-my-dog-get-fleas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-did-my-dog-get-fleas/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I noticed my neighbor&amp;#39;s dog scratching and upon further inspection, I have served simply that on them.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Recently, I noticed my neighbor&rsquo;s dog scratching and upon further inspection, I have served simply that on them.</p>
<ul>
<li>So my neighbor&rsquo;s biggest question was how did my dog get <a href="/posts/best-dog-backpack-carrier-for-hiking/">fleas</a> this is a question. Has it become a flea magnet? This is a question I&rsquo;ll be answering in this article.
**But in brief, dogs can get fleas from other animals such as foxes, raccoons, and rodents, or from the house (from flea-infested blankets, rugs, and bedding), or even in outdoor spaces such as the neighbor&rsquo;s yard, or flea-infested kennels. **</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="details-how-did-my-dog-get-fleas">Details: How Did My <a href="/posts/best-dog-beds/">Dog</a> Get Fleas?</h2>
<h3 id="1-can-dogs-get-fleas-from-other-animals-wildlife-hotspot-1">1. Can Dogs Get Fleas From Other Animals? Wildlife? Hotspot #1</h3>
<p>Yes, dogs can get fleas from other animals including wildlife, and household pets like cats.
Notably, cat fleas will not discriminate against their hosts and thus will bite even the dogs.</p>
<ul>
<li>However, dog fleas only prefer to bite dogs and suck their blood.
Dogs are generally social by nature and this could make them a flea magnet.</li>
<li>When interacting with other animals (wild and domestic ones) dogs among other birds could come into contact with fleas.
Despite that fleas are not high jumpers, then hop onto your dog and begin their colony.
Many flea-infested animals will be a great danger to your dogs.</li>
<li>For example, house mice that are flea-infested may drop the fleas around the house or directly spread them to your dog.
Other wild or domestic animals that will carry fleas are;</li>
</ul>
<ol>
<li>Bovine</li>
<li>Foxes</li>
<li>Raccoons</li>
<li>Deer</li>
<li>Rabbits</li>
<li>Opossum</li>
<li>Skunks</li>
<li>Squirrels</li>
<li>Ferrets</li>
<li>Birds</li>
<li>Rodents
So, dogs will pick fleas from different animals including pets and wildlife.</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>Wild animals will visit various open spaces such as your yard and dogs also like moving around such areas.
Also, in their daily work, dogs move through various areas including the backyard, and may come into contact with animals like raccoons, squirrels, rabbits, or birds.
<strong>Ways Of Preventing A Flea Infestation From Animals</strong>
First, you will require to reduce the level or frequency of contact between the flea-infested animals and your dogs.
Therefore, you must discourage the world animals from getting into your backyard.
Initial steps to achieve these may include are moving the dog&rsquo;s seeds, nuts, and food from the yard.</li>
<li>Also, you can discourage raccoons and foxes from getting into your yard by keeping does garbage bags in sealed bins.
However, don&rsquo;t discourage the dogs from socializing with other pets including other dogs as this could hinder their well-being.</li>
<li>On the contrary, I recommend that you employeffective flea treatment on a regular basis.
So, you need to flea treat the dogs and all the other pets in the house as these will reduce the probability of flea infestation on dogs.
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LZ9kNS8KDBA">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LZ9kNS8KDBA</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="2-can-dogs-get-fleas-from-the-house-hotspot-2">2. Can Dogs Get Fleas From the House? Hotspot #2</h3>
<p>Please can get into the house through various ways including hitchhiking onto humans or pets.
For example, wild animals like mice are raccoons can carry fleas from the outdoor spaces to your indoor areas.
Also,
humans may also carry the fleas
from other houses of the yard through shoes or clothing.
Other ways that the fleas will get into your house include flea-infested toys, blankets, rugs, and pet bedding.</p>
<ul>
<li>So take precaution when receiving off buying second-hand household items - ensure to flea treat such items with ways that willkill even the flea eggs.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="3-can-dogs-get-fleas-from-dog-facilities-hotspot-3">3. Can Dogs Get Fleas From Dog Facilities? Hotspot #3</h3>
<p>Despite that it&rsquo;s not common, dogs may also pick fleas from different dogs (including wild dogs) in their environment.
For example, your dog may pick fleas from the dog park as it will come into contact with many animals; some of which may already have fleas.
Also, the dog park grounds could be covered with fleas that will be searching for the dogs as their host.</p>
<ul>
<li>I note that there isn&rsquo;t much that we can do to control the fleas on the dog park grounds.
But you can take preventative measures by administering some appropriate dog flea treatment.
Indoor dog facilities must also be flea-treated before allowing your dog to visit such areas.
So, take precautions; as regards the application of flea control techniques, as you choose the dog&rsquo;s daycare, pet boarding, or groomer.</li>
<li>A proactive step that I can take is to enquire about flea outbreaks in the facility and the steps they took to manage them and also how they prevented exposure to other pets including dogs.</li>
<li>Groomers&rsquo; facilities can also be a hotspot for fleas to jump onto your dog but extra caution must be taken as regards the groomer&rsquo;s gear as they could already be infected.
So, as noted earlier, ensure that the groom has laid down procedures for flea control and appropriate washing of the dogs.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="4-can-dogs-get-fleas-from-outdoor-spaces-hotspot-4">4. Can Dogs Get Fleas From Outdoor Spaces? Hotspot #4</h3>
<p>Fleas love the humid and warm climate that is mainly outdoors; which allows them to survive for long in such areas.
You will find flea eggs in shady and cool locations of your outdoor spaces.
Therefore, the dogs can get a flea infestation if they frequent such places in your yard.
So, which outdoor areas can my dog get in contact with fleas?</p>
<ol>
<li>Neighboring yards</li>
<li>Under porches</li>
<li>Dog houses</li>
<li>Kennels</li>
<li>Backyard</li>
<li>Dog park or run
The please that you find in your backyard could have come from the neighbors yards or via wildlife.
It will be easy to inspect and control fleas in the yard but this may not be possible at the dog run or dog park that is flea-infested.
So, you may need to ask around if other pet owners have experienced fleas on their dogs after visiting the run or park.</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>This information on a possible flea infestation will help you know where and when to take your dog outdoors without major risk of such bug attacks.
It&rsquo;s not a wonder that dogs could also pick fleas from your own backyard.
The fleas might have been dropped by wild animals (rabbits, deer, or squirrels) and they&rsquo;ll sit in the grass waiting for a suitable host for food and breeding purposes.</li>
<li>So, the fleas might jump onto your dog. The most you can do is toflea-treat the yardand also administer flea medication to the dogs; either oral or topical.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="how-to-control-fleas-on-your-dog">How To Control Fleas On Your Dog</h2>
<p>It doesn&rsquo;t matter whether you are dog is well protected or super clean, they may always catch fleas.</p>
<ul>
<li>Therefore, from the onset, I would suggest that you put your dog on some flea prevention remedies like AdvantageMulti and Comfortis.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="step-1-early-detection">Step 1: Early Detection</h3>
<p>Detecting fleas in their early stages will help you prevent the occurrence of a full-blown flea attack within weeks.
Therefore, It&rsquo;s important to promote early detection of fleas by checking unique signs on the pet (dog) and in the house.</p>
<ul>
<li>Some of the most common signs of a flea infestation on your dog will include excessive scratching and nibbling.</li>
<li>Also, the occurrence of red patches and sudden loss of hair on the dog&rsquo;s skin may indicate an infestation.
So, if you notice these signs of fleas, I recommend you undertake an extensive investigation by keenly combing through the dog&rsquo;s fur.</li>
<li>In addition, examine if you see small black dirt (which is fleas body waste).</li>
<li>Also, you can set down the dog on some white towel and then continue brushing its fur downwards
Therefore, it will now be easy to notice the flea dirt and the adult fleas when you have the white towel background.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="step-2-flea-treat-the-pet-dog">Step 2: Flea-Treat the Pet (Dog)</h3>
<p>Shop for a pesticide that will exterminate the adult fleas and the flea larvae.
For the dogs (and other pets) plus the house to become flea-free, you&rsquo;ll need to effectively kill all the flea larvae.</p>
<ul>
<li>Therefore, when purchasing that pesticide, casual that it includes larvae-killing ingredients such as methoprene and pyriproxyfen.
Bathe the cats and dogs in four to five days prior or after flea- or tick-treating to them with spot-on remedies like Advantage II or K9 Advantix II.
Notably, the chemicals in these spot-on flea treatments will move into the pet&rsquo;s subcutaneous fat layer to exterminate flea eggs and adult fleas.</li>
<li>Bathing the dogs too fast before applying the spot-on treatment will wash off the natural oils which help carry the bug-killing chemicals.
In addition, bathing the dogs shortly after the flea treatment will wash off the chemicals.
But if you used oral treatments for the dogs like bravecto you don&rsquo;t have to worry about bathing them too soon.
I recommend the immediate application of the flea killers if you notice adult fleas in the vicinity.</li>
<li>For example, Capstar flea killer will exterminate the fleas on your dog in 6 hours.
Luckily some of the flea killers like sentinel will also exterminate other pests like heartworms.</li>
<li>However, as regards the use of shampoos to kill fleas - avoid over-using them as they may overdry the dog&rsquo;s skin.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="step-3-flea-treat-the-house-or-home">Step 3: Flea-Treat the House or Home</h3>
<p>Next, I recommend that you vacuum the house using a vacuum cleaner and make sure to get to those hard surfaces.</p>
<ul>
<li>After vacuuming the surfaces remember to seal that vacuum bag in some plastic container and dispose of it.
They are homeowners that will tell you to put a flea collar into that vacuum bag to help kill the flea eggs and the adult fleas as you are vacuuming.</li>
<li>However, some experts discourage the use of flea collars in vacuum cleaners since these devices have many chemicals.
Prior to beginning the vacuuming process,
sprinkle some borax
on the carpets that could be flea-infested - and leave it overnight.</li>
<li>Vacuum the various services on the next day and use hot water to wash the best bed but you can also or to dry the fabrics.
But if the fleas continue attacking and appearing in your spaces, consider contracting a professional exterminator since they will use powerful but safe chemicals.</li>
<li>If you&rsquo;ll be doing the flea extermination as a DIY Project remember some of the chemicals that you might use may be hazardous to your kids, fish, and birds.
Related:
<a href="https://pestpolicy.com/diatomaceous-earth/">Diatomaceous Earth</a></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>So in summary please can jump onto your dog through various ways including coming from the yard, wild animals, carpets and rugs, or even other pets such as cats.</p>
<ul>
<li>Monthly treatment of dogs for fleas is highly recommended and you may use devices such as flea collars when the pet is outdoors.
In addition, you can use free shampoos to bathe your dogs.</li>
<li>You can still bathe the dogs with castile soap (unscented) but you should add some essential oils (just a few drops) such as citronella, tea tree, lavender, or eucalyptus
Cheers!</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Do Dogs Get Fleas</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-do-dogs-get-fleas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-do-dogs-get-fleas/</guid>
      <description>Fleas are a harsh pest when they attack your pets including dogs and cats. The bloodsuckers (fleas) will bite the dogs, causing irritation, scratching, pai...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="/posts/best-dog-backpack-carrier-for-hiking/">Fleas</a> are a harsh pest when they attack your pets including dogs and cats. The bloodsuckers (fleas) will bite the dogs, causing irritation, scratching, pain, and even diseases. But how do dogs get fleas?
<strong>In brief, dogs may get fleas from places such as the backyard, the park,�</strong>
<strong>Pet facilities,�</strong>
<strong>or when they come into contact with animals such as wildlife and pets. Outdoor animals that may bring fleas to dogs include foxes, raccoons, deer, rabbits, opossum, skunks, squirrels, ferrets, birds, and rodents.�</strong></p>
<h2 id="details-how-do-dogs-get-fleas">Details: How Do Dogs Get Fleas?</h2>
<h3 id="1-dogs-can-get-fleas-from-wild-animals">1. Dogs Can Get Fleas From Wild Animals</h3>
<p>Despite that, you may be keeping your dogs in a domesticated way and they&rsquo;re the only pets using the yard, fleas may still jump onto them from wild critters like rabbits, deer, and
squirrels
.</p>
<ul>
<li>Dogs could pick up those fleas when they come into contact with various wild animals; this is because they&rsquo;re sociable animals that&rsquo;ll move around the yards, parks, or even come near various pets.
You&rsquo;ll notice that dogs will wander in areas where wild animals that carry fleas are equally frequent. In the backyard or during their daily walk dogs will get into contact with animals such as
deer, raccoons, rodents, squirrels, rabbits, and birds.
Thus as the dogs take social activities, they may contact fleas via contact with the wild animals. Notably, fleas will jump onto dogs or humans and get carried to other locations where they&rsquo;ll build up their colony.</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="preventing-dogs-from-getting-fleas-and-ticks-from-wild-animals">Preventing Dogs from Getting Fleas and Ticks from Wild Animals</h4>
<p>To prevent fleas from jumping onto dogs from the wild animals, it&rsquo;s important to hinder the wildlife from getting into your backyard or garden.</p>
<ul>
<li>While at it, ensure to remove all objects or things that may attract the wild animals such as seeds, nuts, and other dogs.
Further, remove garbage and garbage bins from your backyard as they could attract wildlife. For example, removing garbage may help prevent the coming of hungry
raccoons and foxes - this could have brought fleas to your dogs.
However, dogs may still socialize with various wildlife and other pets -which implies that the most critical control of fleas will be using an effective and regular flea treatment.
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WCagGpFKdh0">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WCagGpFKdh0</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="2-contact-with-domestic-animals">2. Contact with Domestic Animals</h3>
<p>Flea-infested domestic animals and pets may also pose a risk to making dogs get fleas. For example, dogs may also get fleas through contact with feral animals and other domestic pets such as cats.</p>
<ul>
<li>You&rsquo;d note that Ctenocephalides canis (<a href="/posts/best-dog-beds/">dog</a> fleas) may not just attack and suck blood from cats but could also jump onto and bite dogs and their puppies.
Fleas have back legs that are very strong that&rsquo;ll allow them to jump onto the tail or body of the dog from other domestic pets that are in the house or backyard.
Dogs will also get fleas from grass - fleas will jump onto the dog and suck its blood - and then they&rsquo;ll jump off back to the grass waiting for other hosts.</li>
<li>You may notice that the dog is spending hours scratching themselves around the yard - maybe after picking those fleas from the grass or other pets.
However, humans too may pick fleas from the yard and the bugs will jump onto your pant legs, socks, and shoes - and
<a href="https://pestpolicy.com/can-humans-carry-fleas-from-one-home-to-another/">you&rsquo;ll carry fleas to your house</a>
.
Unfortunately, fleas could also get into your house in different ways and develop into a colony to finally attack your dogs. For example, fleas could into the house by
hitching pets and clothes worn by humans or even climbing onto mice - they&rsquo;ll come in and lay many eggs.</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="preventing-dogs-from-getting-fleas-and-ticks-from-pets-and-house">Preventing Dogs from Getting Fleas and Ticks from Pets and House</h4>
<p>You can prevent the fleas from hitting your pets and your house by adopting effective flea treatment for your
furry friends and the home area.</p>
<ul>
<li>For example, if there is a mice or rodent problem in the house, you may require to take up appropriate control for these animals from the home.
Wash and flea treat the pet bedding - washing should be done at 50 degrees Celsius as this will be appropriate to exterminate the flea eggs and also the adult fleas.
Also, I recommend that you vacuum the carpets and other such flooring materials to remove all the flea stages - and ultimately dispose of that dangerous vacuum bag.</li>
<li>I also advise you to steam clean the floor and carpet to help kill those flea larvae.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="3pet-service-facilities">3.<strong>Pet Service facilities�</strong></h2>
<p>Dogs may also get flea some pets&rsquo; facilities; these may include
boarding kennels, grooming facilities, and dog&rsquo;s daycare facilities.</p>
<ul>
<li>Thus, dogs may stick fleas from these facilities even with the strict flea-free regulations and rules being adhered to strictly.
For example, dogs may also get fleas from the facilities of the pet groomer - fleas may hike the pet and come reproduce fast in your house, pet house, or yard.</li>
<li>In addition, fleas could also have jumped onto the groomer&rsquo;s clothes and gear that have become flea-infected.
So, ensure that the service provider in the pet care facility adheres strictly to all pest prevention
protocols as this may guarantee that the dog is protected from fleas.
Further, check how the pet service facility responds or helps whenever a bug infection is found in any other pets that are attended there.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="treating-dogs-from-fleas--treatment">Treating Dogs From Fleas -<strong>Treatment</strong></h2>
<p>Treating the dogs and the surrounding off fleas will be an appropriate step to undertake for prevention and control of those blood-suckers.</p>
<ul>
<li>An appropriate and initial step that you must take is to flea-treat the dog using a suitable flea shampoo - especially one that&rsquo;s prescribed for the age of your dog.
Use a flea comb that is fine-toothed for dogs that have long hair as this will help remove the fleas, their eggs, and also flea dirt from the fur.</li>
<li>Additional flea treatment that you may use must be approved or prescribed by the veterinarian - and these must control all fleas in various life stages including larvae and adult fleas.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>Summers come with heat and many fleas - which might land on your dog. We&rsquo;ve outlined that dogs may get fleas from various places including the wildlife, backyard, other pets, the house, or the pet care facilities if appropriate flea-control measures are not adopted.</p>
<ul>
<li>Inspect the dog&rsquo;s tail, underbelly, and fur for the presence of any adult fleas - check with your vet for appropriate and great flea control techniques to use on your dog.
Cheers!</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Keep Dogs Off Lawn</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-to-keep-dogs-off-lawn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-to-keep-dogs-off-lawn/</guid>
      <description>For many homeowners, a lush, green lawn is a point of pride, a beautiful backdrop for outdoor living. However, this verdant carpet can quickly become a pat...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For many homeowners, a lush, green lawn is a point of pride, a beautiful backdrop for outdoor living. However, this verdant carpet can quickly become a patchwork of yellow spots, divots, and worn paths when active dogs are in the picture. While our beloved canine companions bring joy to our lives, their natural behaviors � from urinating and defecating to digging and running � can pose significant challenges to maintaining a healthy and attractive lawn.</p>
<p>The damage caused by dogs is not merely cosmetic; concentrated urine can scorch grass, digging can destroy root systems, and repetitive traffic can compact soil and create bare spots. Whether you&rsquo;re dealing with your own playful pup or neighborhood dogs frequently visiting your property, finding effective and humane ways to deter them is essential for preserving your green oasis. This guide will explore the various ways dogs impact your lawn, offer a range of solutions from commercial and DIY repellents to physical barriers and <a href="/posts/best-dog-backpack-carrier-for-hiking/">dog</a>-repelling plants, and delve into training strategies to encourage more desirable behavior, ultimately helping you achieve a harmonious balance between pet ownership and lawn care.</p>
<h2 id="how-dogs-damage-your-lawn">How Dogs Damage Your Lawn</h2>
<p>Dogs can damage lawns in several distinct ways, each requiring a slightly different understanding to address effectively:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Urine Burn (Nitrogen Burn):</strong> This is perhaps the most common and recognizable form of damage. Dog urine is highly concentrated in nitrogen, along with other salts. While nitrogen is a key nutrient for grass, an excessive, concentrated dose acts like an over-application of fertilizer in a small spot, &ldquo;burning&rdquo; the grass.
<ul>
<li><strong>Appearance:</strong> Yellow or brown spots with a dark green ring around the perimeter. The ring indicates where the nitrogen concentration was diluted enough to act as a beneficial fertilizer.</li>
<li><strong>Cause:</strong> Female dogs tend to squat and urinate in one spot, leading to more concentrated damage. Male dogs may spray smaller, less damaging amounts over a wider area.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Digging:</strong> Dogs dig for a variety of reasons: burying treasures, hunting underground pests (voles, moles, grubs), seeking cooler soil, or simply out of boredom or anxiety.
<ul>
<li><strong>Appearance:</strong> Distinct holes, often with excavated soil scattered around. Can range from small scrapes to large pits.</li>
<li><strong>Cause:</strong> Instinctual behavior, sometimes indicating an underlying pest problem or lack of mental/physical stimulation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Compaction and Wear:</strong> Repeated running, playing, or patrolling the same areas of the lawn can compact the soil and wear down grass.
<ul>
<li><strong>Appearance:</strong> Worn paths, bare spots, especially along fence lines or popular running routes.</li>
<li><strong>Cause:</strong> Physical stress on the turf, preventing air, water, and nutrients from reaching grass roots.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Feces Damage:</strong> While less direct than urine, dog feces can also damage grass, particularly if left for extended periods. It can smother grass, introduce bacteria, and contribute to nutrient imbalances.
<ul>
<li><strong>Appearance:</strong> Browned or dead patches where feces lingered.</li>
<li><strong>Cause:</strong> Smothering and chemical concentration from waste.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
<p>Understanding the specific type of damage your lawn is experiencing will help you select the most appropriate deterrent strategy.</p>
<h2 id="commercial-dog-repellents">Commercial Dog Repellents</h2>
<p>A quick trip to your local garden or pet supply store will reveal a variety of commercial dog repellents designed to keep Fido off your grass. These typically work through scent or taste.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Scent-Based Repellents:</strong> These often contain ingredients like capsaicin (chili pepper extract), essential oils (e.g., citrus, eucalyptus, peppermint), or predator urine. Dogs find these scents unpleasant and will avoid the treated area.
<ul>
<li><strong>Application:</strong> Available as granular products to sprinkle or liquid sprays to apply to the lawn perimeter or specific problem spots.</li>
<li><strong>Effectiveness:</strong> Varies greatly by product, dog, and consistency of application. They often need frequent reapplication, especially after rain.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Taste-Based Repellents:</strong> Some products make the grass taste bitter or unpleasant to discourage chewing or digging.
<ul>
<li><strong>Application:</strong> Sprayed directly onto the grass.</li>
<li><strong>Effectiveness:</strong> Primarily for dogs that chew or dig. Less effective for urination.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Considerations for Commercial Repellents:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Safety:</strong> Always check labels to ensure they are safe for pets, children, and plants.</li>
<li><strong>Reapplication:</strong> Most require regular reapplication, which can be costly and time-consuming.</li>
<li><strong>Dog Specificity:</strong> What repels one dog may not deter another.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="diy-dog-repellents">DIY Dog Repellents</h2>
<p>For a more natural or cost-effective approach, several household items can be repurposed as dog repellents:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Citrus Peels:</strong> Dogs dislike the strong scent of citrus. Scatter orange, lemon, or grapefruit peels around the perimeter of your lawn or in problem areas. Replace them regularly as the scent fades.</li>
<li><strong>Vinegar:</strong> A diluted solution of white vinegar (1 part vinegar to 1 part water) can be sprayed around the edges of your lawn. The strong smell is a deterrent, but use sparingly as it can potentially harm some plants if over-applied.</li>
<li><strong>Cayenne Pepper/Chili Powder:</strong> Dogs find the smell and taste of spicy peppers highly unpleasant. Sprinkle a light dusting around boundaries.
<ul>
<li><strong>Caution:</strong> This can irritate a dog&rsquo;s nose and eyes. Use with extreme care, especially if dogs (or children) might ingest it, and avoid using in windy conditions. Not recommended for areas where dogs are likely to walk or lie down.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Coffee Grounds:</strong> The strong scent and slightly acidic nature of coffee grounds can deter some dogs. Sprinkle used grounds in areas you want them to avoid.</li>
<li><strong>Ammonia-Soaked Rags:</strong> Place rags soaked in ammonia in strategic locations. The pungent smell mimics predator urine and can deter some animals.
<ul>
<li><strong>Caution:</strong> Keep out of reach of pets and children.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>General DIY Caution:</strong> Always test a small, inconspicuous area first to ensure the repellent doesn&rsquo;t damage your grass or other plants. Reapply frequently, especially after rain.</p>
<h2 id="plants-that-repel-dogs">Plants That Repel Dogs</h2>
<p>Incorporating certain plants into your landscaping can act as a natural, living barrier or deterrent. Dogs generally dislike strong-smelling or prickly plants.</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Coleus Canina (Scaredy Cat Plant):</strong> This plant is specifically marketed as a dog and cat repellent. It emits a pungent, skunk-like odor that humans usually only detect when close up or when the leaves are brushed.</li>
<li><strong>Rue:</strong> A perennial herb with a strong, unpleasant aroma that many dogs dislike. It can cause skin irritation in some people, so handle with gloves.</li>
<li><strong>Lavender:</strong> While pleasant to humans, its strong essential oil scent can be a deterrent to dogs when planted in dense borders.</li>
<li><strong>Prickly Plants:</strong> Planting thorny or spiky shrubs along your lawn&rsquo;s edge can create a physical barrier that dogs won&rsquo;t want to cross. Examples include barberry, roses (with caution for thorns), or juniper.</li>
<li><strong>Hot Pepper Plants:</strong> Growing hot peppers (like cayenne or jalape�o) in pots around sensitive areas can deter some curious dogs due to the capsaicin, but ensure the dogs don&rsquo;t actually eat the peppers.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Strategic Planting:</strong> Create dense borders or hedges with these plants around your lawn or garden beds to form a deterrent zone.</p>
<h2 id="other-ways-to-keep-dogs-off-your-lawn">Other Ways To Keep Dogs off Your Lawn</h2>
<p>Beyond repellents, physical and technological barriers can be highly effective:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Fencing:</strong> The most foolproof method. A physical fence around your entire yard or specific sections (like a front lawn) will prevent access. For aesthetic reasons, consider low, decorative fencing for garden beds or specific lawn areas.</li>
<li><strong>Temporary Barriers:</strong> Use garden stakes and string, chicken wire, or temporary mesh fencing to cordon off newly seeded areas, delicate flower beds, or sections of lawn you want to protect.</li>
<li><strong>Motion-Activated Sprinklers:</strong> These devices attach to a hose and spray a burst of water when motion is detected. They are highly effective at startling and deterring dogs (and other wildlife) without causing harm.</li>
<li><strong>Designated Potty Area:</strong> For your own dog, creating a designated &ldquo;potty patch&rdquo; can redirect their waste. This could be a small area of mulch, gravel, or even a patch of tough grass in a less visible spot. Encourage its use with positive reinforcement and by leading your dog there on a leash.</li>
<li><strong>Diluting Urine:</strong> If you witness your dog urinating, immediately douse the spot with a large amount of water to dilute the nitrogen and minimize grass burn.</li>
<li><strong>Increase Lawn Health:</strong> A healthy, dense lawn is more resilient and can recover better from minor damage. Ensure proper watering, fertilization, and mowing practices.</li>
<li><strong>Address Underlying Pest Problems:</strong> If your dog is digging extensively, they might be hunting grubs, moles, or voles. Addressing these pest infestations can reduce digging behavior.</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="training-and-behavior-modification">Training and Behavior Modification</h2>
<p>For your own dog, direct training and behavior modification are the most sustainable long-term solutions. For neighborhood dogs, communication with their owners is key.</p>
<h3 id="for-your-own-dog">For Your Own Dog:</h3>
<ol>
<li><strong>Leash Training:</strong> Always walk your dog on a leash, especially during potty breaks, and guide them to designated areas.</li>
<li><strong>Positive Reinforcement:</strong> Reward your dog heavily with treats and praise when they eliminate in the desired spot (e.g., the potty patch or non-lawn area).</li>
<li><strong>Supervision:</strong> Supervise your dog when they are in the yard, especially during peak digging times (early morning, late evening, or when bored).</li>
<li><strong>Exercise and Mental Stimulation:</strong> A tired dog is a good dog. Ensure your dog gets enough physical exercise and mental stimulation (e.g., puzzle toys, training sessions) to reduce boredom-related digging or restless wandering.</li>
<li><strong>Consistent Commands:</strong> Teach &ldquo;leave it&rdquo; or &ldquo;off&rdquo; commands for when they approach forbidden areas.</li>
<li><strong>Enrichment for Diggers:</strong> If your dog is a natural digger, consider providing a designated digging pit filled with sand or loose soil, encouraging them to dig there instead of the lawn. Bury toys or treats in it to make it appealing.</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="for-neighbors-dogs">For Neighbor&rsquo;s Dogs:</h3>
<ol>
<li><strong>Polite Communication:</strong> The best first step is always to have a friendly conversation with your neighbor. Explain the damage and kindly ask them to keep their dog off your lawn. They might not even be aware of the problem.</li>
<li><strong>Suggest Alternatives:</strong> If appropriate, suggest they leash their dog or walk them on the sidewalk.</li>
<li><strong>Signage:</strong> A polite &ldquo;Please keep dogs off lawn&rdquo; sign can be effective for some.</li>
<li><strong>Physical Barriers:</strong> If communication fails or isn&rsquo;t possible, discreet temporary fencing or motion-activated sprinklers are usually the next best step.</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="conclusion-a-harmonious-yard---balancing-pet-ownership-with-lawn-care">Conclusion: A Harmonious Yard - Balancing Pet Ownership with Lawn Care</h2>
<p>Maintaining a beautiful lawn while living with or alongside dogs requires a multi-faceted approach. There&rsquo;s no single magic bullet, but rather a combination of deterrence, physical barriers, and, crucially, understanding and managing canine behavior. From utilizing a strategically placed &ldquo;scaredy cat plant&rdquo; to diligent training and prompt cleanup, each effort contributes to minimizing damage and fostering a healthier green space.</p>
<p>The ultimate goal is to create a harmonious outdoor environment where both your lawn can thrive and dogs can safely enjoy their outdoor time without causing irreparable damage. By implementing these strategies consistently and patiently, you can reclaim your pristine lawn, ensuring it remains a source of enjoyment and pride for years to come, free from the tell-tale signs of canine mischief.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Tell If Your Dog Has Fleas</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-to-tell-if-your-dog-has-fleas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-to-tell-if-your-dog-has-fleas/</guid>
      <description>How do I know if my dog has fleas?</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>How do I know if my dog has <a href="/posts/can-dog-fleas-transfer-to-humans/">fleas</a>?</p>
<p>Well, the vet says it&rsquo;s if you notice your dog scratching, shaking their head, biting themselves, and then scratching some more.�But how do you know for sure?</p>
<p>In this article, I&rsquo;ll tackle this question: how to tell if your dog has fleas?</p>
<ul>
<li>**Dogs with fleas will usually have at least one of the following: excessive scratching or licking; black specks around the base of their tail, head, ears, or paws; an irritated red skin rash. **
If your dog is exhibiting any of these symptoms then it may very well have fleas.</li>
</ul>
<p>[amazon bestseller=&ldquo;Best <a href="/posts/dog-has-fleas-and-sleeps-in-my-bed/">Flea</a> Killers&rdquo; items=&ldquo;2&rdquo; template=&ldquo;table&rdquo;]</p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s get into the details!</p>
<p>Read Also:
The 6 Signs that Cat Has Fleas</p>
<h2 id="what-are-dog-fleas-comparison-with-cats-fleas">What are Dog Fleas? Comparison with Cats Fleas?</h2>
<p>Dog fleas are ectoparasites - they inhabit and live outside their host&rsquo;s body on the fur. They&rsquo;re roughly 1/8 inch long, thin, reddish-brown.
<em>Are dog fleas visible to the human eye?</em>
It can be difficult to spot dog fleas on a dog&rsquo;s fur (they&rsquo;re 1/8 inch long) with the human eye. Though it may seem easier on light-colored fur, or if you use a microscope or magnifying glass.</p>
<ul>
<li>Dogs frequently have parasites. One type, known as dog fleas, lives, feeds, and reproducing on the blood of its hosts.
If you&rsquo;re confused between cat fleas and dog fleas, you might want to check
our guide on cat fleas vs dog fleas
.
*In summary: *
Cat fleas and dog fleas species are different and they mainly inhabit and live on cats and dogs respectively.</li>
<li>But without the use of laboratory equipment, it can be difficult to tell these two species apart.
Since Cat fleas suck blood from many mammals (
<a href="https://ohioline.osu.edu/factsheet/HYG-2081-11"><strong>plus on dogs too</strong></a>
), they&rsquo;re a more prevalent species compared to dog fleas.</li>
</ul>
<p>Do dog fleas bite humans? Generally no; but it can happen if your dog has a massive infestation or if you have a pet that is not house-trained to mainly keep to its dog bed.</p>
<p>If your dog has signs of being infested with parasites, there are medications available for the treatment of canine flea infections from veterinarians or online retailers like Amazon.</p>
<h2 id="how-did-my-indoor-dog-get-fleas">How Did My Indoor Dog Get Fleas?</h2>
<p>Maybe you&rsquo;ve cleaned up the dog and
flea-treated the yard
, but they&rsquo;re still scratching - a sign that it still has fleas.</p>
<p>Well, dogs will pick up fleas in different ways. Your dog could have picked up fleas from:</p>
<ul>
<li>Walking on dirt or grass with an infested animal nearby.</li>
<li>Sharing a bed, carpet, or furniture that has flea eggs near the surface of it.</li>
<li>Licking and interacting with other dogs or<a href="https://schoolipm.ifas.ufl.edu/newtp5.htm">flea-infested animals</a>such as rodents, ferrets,squirrels,opossums, andraccoons.</li>
<li>Going to a flea-infested place such as the dog park or grooming salon.</li>
<li>Licking their paws from contact with flea-infested items in your home, like carpets, bedding, furniture fabric, carpeting,
Dogs might also be attacked by fleas outside the home, on the street, in the backyard, or even on the porch.</li>
</ul>
<p>Also, the fleas can find their way onto your dog from your trip abroad - through lagguage, and if they are left untreated then pets will become infested with them in no time at all.</p>
<p>Related:
How to Treat Fleas in the Yard</p>
<h2 id="what-are-the-signs-that-my-dog-has-fleas">What Are The Signs That My Dog Has Fleas?</h2>
<p>Fleas are scary tiny bloodthirsty bugs that will literally drink more than their weight in blood. They&rsquo;ll be a life threat (after causing anemia) to your sickly/ old dogs and even puppies.</p>
<p>Fleas will leave tiny bites all over your dog&rsquo;s body that are hard to see and also cause restlessness and allergic reactions.</p>
<p>This is a list of the signs you should look out for to know that your dog has a flea infestation.</p>
<h3 id="sign-1---restlessness-in-the-dog">Sign 1 - Restlessness in the Dog</h3>
<p>The constant flea bites and possible allergic reactions from the parasite&rsquo;s saliva often cause dogs to appear irritated and restless.</p>
<p>If the dog is flea-infested, it will likely keep licking, biting, and scratching itself in order to relieve itself of the discomfort.</p>
<p>Signs that show the dog has been scratching itself to relieve skin irritation will typically have hair loss in patches, composed of bald spots with &ldquo;dirt&rdquo; underneath them, usually found at a dog&rsquo;s lower back end.</p>
<p>This type of infestation can make your pet start to smell bad as well because it won&rsquo;t be able to clean itself properly due to all those irritating bugs biting away.</p>
<ul>
<li>This means you should take precautions such asusing flea shampooor sprays to get rid of these bloodthirsty pests before they do any more damage!
A person might notice the dog chewing and scratching the body area in an effort to ease that discomfort from the fleas.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="sign-2---flea-dirt-and-flea-eggs">Sign 2 - Flea Dirt and Flea Eggs</h3>
<p>Inspect the dog&rsquo;s fur and skin - if you notice specks like black pepper (finely ground), then this is flea &ldquo;dirt&rdquo; (flea droppings) that denotes a flea infestation.</p>
<p>When you see tiny black dots on the dog or on your carpet, it&rsquo;s probably not pepper. It could be flea dirt or eggs.</p>
<p>Dog fleas lay eggs (20 - 50 eggs daily) and produce this waste while feeding. Flea eggs are white and oval-shaped.</p>
<ul>
<li>To confirm if it&rsquo;s flea dirt use some white paper towel to drop the dirt collected from<a href="https://pestpolicy.com/best-flea-combs-for-dogs/">the dog&rsquo;s grooming</a></li>
<li>Next, sprinkle that dirt with some water and check its color change. If anything like red or reddish-brown emerges then the dirt is flea droppings or flea dirt.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="sign-3---anemia---pale-gums">Sign 3 - Anemia - Pale Gums</h3>
<p>Fleas will suck massive amounts of blood from the canines (dogs) and this could lead to
<a href="https://muschealth.org/medical-services/ddc/patients/symptoms-and-conditions/anemia"><strong>anemia</strong></a>
in the puppies or the sickly dogs.</p>
<p>As fleas are heavy blook suckers, when they&rsquo;re in an area with more than just a couple of them, your dog&rsquo;s blood can get dangerously low.</p>
<p>The gums are usually pale in appearance and the dog will have a hard time breathing due to low levels of hemoglobin.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iiSRHPxDsOs">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iiSRHPxDsOs</a></p>
<p>Anemia is when there are not enough red blood cells. The hemoglobin in blood is a protein molecule inside the red blood cells that moves oxygen to all parts of your body.</p>
<p>There are three causes of anemia</p>
<ul>
<li>Blood loss</li>
<li>Destruction of red blood cells also called hemolytic anemia</li>
<li>Insufficient production of red blood cells also called aplastic anemia
Dogs mainly get anemia from blood loss. The symptoms of anemia in your dog can include</li>
<li>Weakness</li>
<li>Elevated heart rate and Rapid breathing</li>
<li>Pale mucous membranes which is usually the gum color.</li>
<li>Sometimes the tongue can become pale pink to white</li>
<li>A loss of appetite</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="sign-4---hair-loss-and-allergic-reactions">Sign 4 - Hair Loss and Allergic Reactions</h3>
<p>Dogs that are allergic to the flea&rsquo;s saliva may experience severe itching, hair loss, and red sores.</p>
<p>Allergic dermatitis caused by flea bites will mainly develop among older dogs or younger puppies.</p>
<p>The flea allergies are found on the dog&rsquo;s hindquarters - those may be skin rashes or hair loss patches found on the dog&rsquo;s tail or its back legs.</p>
<ul>
<li>The allergic reaction to flea saliva is hypersensitivity and can be seen in many dogs.
Signs that your dog has fleas include sores caused by scratching as well as excessive licking at these areas mentioned above.</li>
<li>Dogs who have been bitten by fleas may start itching excessively around their rear end while other symptoms for this condition are redness about the anus region and hair loss around the genital area.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="sign-5---tapeworms-in-the-dog-feces">Sign 5 - Tapeworms in the Dog Feces</h3>
<p>Tapeworms may appear in your dog&rsquo;s fecal matter as tiny white segments or rice-like pieces.</p>
<p>Dogs get the tapeworms after swallowing fleas that have tapeworm eggs in their feces.</p>
<p>The worst type is a &ldquo;dogal&rdquo; tapeworm that enters through an infected flea bite on its skin then travels to where it becomes embedded within muscle tissue next to his spinal column.</p>
<p>Fleas can carry tapeworms, which your dog may ingest as it scratches its itchy skin.</p>
<p>The tapeworms will grow in the dog&rsquo;s intestines, shedding tapeworm eggs into the dog&rsquo;s feces.</p>
<ul>
<li>If you see little white droppings that look like rice then you can be certain that there is a problem with this type of parasite too.
Dog owners should also watch out for red bumps on the skin (called dermatitis).</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="use-that-flea-comb-to-catch-fleas">Use that Flea Comb to Catch Fleas</h2>
<p>Many pet owners have had a stressful experience with fleas and it&rsquo;s not the feeling you want to repeat! Use your flea comb to catch fleas!</p>
<p>Dog fleas can be difficult to detect.</p>
<p>Start at the head of your dog and run a flea comb through the hair in the direction of hair growth, then dump them into soapy water.</p>
<ul>
<li>You can find flea combs quickly and easily at your local pet store.
Fleas like to hide in a variety of locations, including the base of the tail, the base of the ear, around the neck and groin area.</li>
</ul>
<p>Flea combs can be used to catch fleas and prevent them from jumping onto your furniture or home.</p>
<p>Over the past few days, my roommate&rsquo;s dog has been scratching a lot. I bought some flea medicine today - just in case this is an issue.</p>
<ul>
<li>But while waiting for it to arrive, I wanted to see if there were any fleas on him first.</li>
<li>We did not have a lint brush or comb lying around, so instead of washing his fur with shampoo and then inspecting him like vet advised we foamed his coat up first and then combed an area of skin followed by another area of skin nearby.</li>
<li>Our goal was to rinse him repeatedly throughout until no more soap was coming out and also catch any flea beings that were hitching a ride on our pup!</li>
<li>**We got them! **</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>In summary, on how to tell if your dog has fleas; check the following signs.</p>
<ul>
<li>Signs of scratching or biting at themselves constantly</li>
<li>You find flea dirt around your pup&rsquo;s paws or fur</li>
<li>They start licking and chewing excessively</li>
<li>Extremely short hair all over, especially near ears and eyes</li>
<li>Pale skin in certain areas from lack of circulation during times when it was warm enough
We hope that this post was helpful and will help you determine if your dog has fleas!</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soundproof Dog Crate</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/soundproof-dog-crate/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/soundproof-dog-crate/</guid>
      <description>Did you know that your dog could be stressed or mentally detailed by boom sounds and noises like road traffic, trains, thunder, and fireworks?</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Did you know that your <a href="/posts/best-dog-backpack-carrier-for-hiking/">dog</a> could be stressed or mentally detailed by boom sounds and noises like road traffic, trains, thunder, and fireworks?</p>
<p>Is your dog frequently hiding, howling, barking, drooling, whining, shaking, or panting?
Does this really get on your nerves?�Well, youll need to soundproof the dogs crate, closet, or room - to�reduce the
<a href="https://ehs.yale.edu/sites/default/files/files/decibel-level-chart.pdf">noise levels</a>
.</p>
<h2 id="whats-asoundproof-dog-crate">What&rsquo;s a�Soundproof Dog Crate?</h2>
<p>I approve using�moving blankets to soundproof�the dog crates.�But, also keep
<a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B077GZ5Z8H/?tag=p-policy-20">ZenCrates</a>
for the�dog to�retreat away from the upsetting noises.
This will provide safety for your dog automatically whether you&rsquo;re home or away. Related:
<a href="https://pestpolicy.com/how-to-soundproof-a-room-cheaply/">Soundproof your Room</a>
A Soundproof dog crate is a special pet created from materials good in absorbing upsetting external sounds and your dog&rsquo;s barking. Thus, your dog will sleep sound&hellip;.easy.
This will also help cut the reverberations and equally the disturbing going into or out of the dog crate - for comfort.� Below I&rsquo;ve discussed another way you can soundproof the dog crate you have.</p>
<h2 id="you-leave-dogs-in-bathroom">You Leave Dogs in Bathroom?</h2>
<p>I discourage pet owners from leaving any of your dog pets in your bathroom. Sadly, most of us homeowners, that&rsquo;s what we&rsquo;ve grown up knowing.
But why? Well, bathroom materials are not truly soundproof and thus won&rsquo;t absorb harsh sounds from getting into or outside the space.�Related:
<a href="https://pestpolicy.com/soundproof-barn-doors/">How to Soundproof Barn Doors</a>
.
However, ensure to Soundproof the dog crate in the warm months e.g. August (in Southwestern U.S.) as thiss when firestorms and thunderstorms will be frequent.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
