<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Point on Pest Policy</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/point/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Point on Pest Policy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/point/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Best Point and Shoot Camera Under 100</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/best-point-and-shoot-camera-under-100/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/best-point-and-shoot-camera-under-100/</guid>
      <description>Most smartphone cameras have</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Most smartphone <a href="/posts/best-compact-cameras-under-300/">cameras</a> have
<a href="https://www.cnet.com/news/10-ways-a-point-and-shoot-camera-beats-your-phones/">inadequate shooting features</a>
.</p>
<p>But any
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Point-and-shoot_camera">point and shoot camera</a>
have optical zoom (changing the perspective of shots), larger in-built sensor, and a powerful flash (great for backlit/ low light environments).
I&rsquo;ve reviewed the <a href="/posts/best-drones-for-still-photography/">best</a> point and shoot camera under 100. Summary: I recommend
<a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B004HYFX0C/?tag=p-policy-20">Sony DSC-HX9V</a>
or
<a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B00I8BIBCW/?tag=p-policy-20">Sony DSCW800/B 20.1 MP</a>
as the
best point and shoot camera under 100
.</p>
<h2 id="reviews-7-best-point-and-shoot-camera-under-100-in-2025">Reviews: 7 Best Point and Shoot Camera Under 100 in 2025</h2>
<h3 id="1-sony-cyber-shot-dsc-hx9v-162-mp-exmor-r-cmos-camera---1-pick"><strong>1. Sony Cyber-shot DSC-HX9V 16.2 MP Exmor R CMOS Camera - #1 Pick</strong></h3>
<p>They allow multi-shot image processing, high-speed burst filming, and slow-motion video. Forget the &lsquo;okay&rsquo; smartphone images (noisy, blurry &amp; soft) that&rsquo;ll look bad on large screens.</p>
<p>Read Also:
Laptops for FL Studio</p>
<h3 id="2-sony-cyber-shot-dsc-w800-digital-camera-360-sweep-panorama--2-pick"><strong>2. Sony Cyber-Shot DSC-W800 Digital Camera (360 sweep panorama)- #2 Pick</strong></h3>
<p>Next up is the Sony Cyber-Shot DSC-W800. Its an amazing kit thatll help you capture those treasurable memories.</p>
<p>With 5 times zoom, this camera will take great detailed 20 megapixel photos with its CCD sensor. Its easy to use and you can easily pick up the settings youll require to use.
Next up is the Sony Cyber-Shot DSC-W800. Its an amazing kit thatll help you capture those treasurable memories. With 5 times zoom, this camera will take great detailed 20 megapixel photos. Its easy to use and you can easily pick up the settings youll require to use.
This point and shoot camera can also comfortably sit on your tripod. It&rsquo;s so small that you can just fit into your pocket as you move out or travel. But it doesn&rsquo;t have WIFI or dynamic range.
Further, if you deem that photo wont serve the required purpose, you can shoot a high-definition video with sound, and using the panoramic shots, you can capture your 360 degrees in a single sweep at a touch of a single button.
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=70V2IgDKaVY">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=70V2IgDKaVY</a>
Read Also:
Bass Compressor Pedal</p>
<h3 id="3-nikon-coolpix-a10-with-5x-optical-zoom-720p-hd-videos---3-pick"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B01MRCWQRM/?tag=p-policy-20">3. Nikon COOLPIX A10 with 5x optical zoom (720p HD videos) - #3 Pick</a></h3>
<p>This Nikon COOLPIX A10 comes with the 16.1MP CCD sensor and 5 times optical zoom lens and has an ergonomic build.</p>
<p>It works on 3 AA batteries (luckily the conventional AA batteries that can take about 700 shots), has, a 230k-dot LCD monitor, Smart Portrait mode and shoots 720p HD video.
Ergonomically, this camera is relatively light (about 160g), ultra-compact, has the textured thumb rest and its video record button is raised. It has a native ISO range that ranges from 80  1600 sensitivity (for low-light environments) with a 4608 x 3456-pixel resolution.
With the 16.1MP CCD sensor, you can easily record HD 720p video and still high-resolution images. In addition, it has a 5 times Optical Zoom Lens that you can extend using a 4 times digital zoom.
Read Also:
49 Key MIDI Controller</p>
<h3 id="4-kodak-pixpro-friendly-zoom-fz53-rd-16mp-with-5x-optical-zoom"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B019XLL4F6/?tag=p-policy-20">4. Kodak PIXPRO Friendly Zoom FZ53-RD 16MP with 5X Optical Zoom</a></h3>
<p>This Pixpro FZ53 is a budget-friendly point-and-shoot camera that comes with a 5x zoom lens for any casual photo shooter. However, this camera has no wireless connectivity and could disappoint relatively on video and image quality.</p>
<p>The camera comes with plastic body build (230k-dot design) and is lightweight (about 3.7 ounces) with ISO sensitivity. Despite that most of us casual photographers may mainly tend to use the fully automatic mode, the camera also has manual controls.
Through the EV compensation, its possible to darken or brighten your scenes. On digital stabilization, Kodak Pixpro FZ53 has the all-important anti-shake. In addition, it has Panorama, Movie, and Portrait among other modes.
With the auto mode activated, its possible to toggle macro focusing after switching off the cameras flash. However, this camera only comes with a 2.7-inch LCD  which is relatively small, compared to other point and shoot cameras reviewed above.
Sadly, for continuous image shooting (particularly at 16 megapixels) youll have a 3.3 seconds wait time between the shots. Further, the cameras autofocus is slow. Read Also:
<a href="https://pestpolicy.com/best-soundproof-earmuffs-for-sleeping/">Soundproof Earmuffs For Sleeping</a>
.</p>
<h3 id="5-nikon-l35af-camera---point-and-shoot"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B00YM6HJSY/?tag=p-policy-20">5. Nikon L35AF Camera - Point and Shoot</a></h3>
<p>Nikon L35AF Camera (popularly as Pikaichi  like great quality) is also a budget-friendly, portable, &amp; durable point and shoot camera.</p>
<p>It comes with a 35mm F/2.8 lens thats multi-functional, sharp and fast.</p>
<p>Also, it has an auto pop-up flash and an auto-focus system.
I found it simple to use the L35AF camera  including using flash, focusing, or aperture setting. It has the AF spot at the model of its viewfinder  that also has the analog lever &amp; diagram in showing the focus distance.
You can set its ASA/ISO through turning the ring around the cameras lens. Its interestingly powered by 2 economical AA batteries  not the specialized types of batteries.
Read Also:
Laptop for Music Production</p>
<h3 id="6-polaroid-iex29-red-hd-18-mp-optical-zoom-digital-camera"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0177QDN5I/?tag=p-policy-20">6. Polaroid IEX29-RED HD 18 MP Optical Zoom Digital Camera</a></h3>
<p>It comes with a large LCD screen, image stabilization in-built flash and the red-eye reduction thatll allow you to take high-quality snapshots.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
