<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Throat on Pest Policy</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/throat/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Throat on Pest Policy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/throat/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Best Throat Lozenges for Singers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/best-throat-lozenges-for-singers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/best-throat-lozenges-for-singers/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;#39;s the</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>What&rsquo;s the
best throat lozenges for singers?
Whether you&rsquo;re a beginner or an elite singer, you&rsquo;ll (at one time) need the best throat lozenges for singers to fine-tune your loud voice.</p>
<p>The tablets will dissolve into a liquid to generate a cooling effect to heal strained, swollen, or scratchy vocal cords - regardless if you&rsquo;re singing for short or long periods.
Some tablets contain cut thew production of phlegm - which would otherwise dry-out your voice. So, is it herb-rich Ricola
<a href="https://europepmc.org/abstract/med/30761819">gummy lozenges</a>
or peppermint?
Related:
English horn vs. Oboe</p>
<h2 id="reviews-9-best-throat-lozenges-for-singers-2025">Reviews: 9 Best Throat Lozenges for Singers 2025</h2>
<h3 id="1-cepacol-honey-lemon-benzocaine-sore-throat-relief-lozenges"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B00DORUVLO/?tag=p-policy-20">1. Cepacol Honey Lemon Benzocaine Sore Throat Relief Lozenges</a></h3>
<p>Cepacol Honey Lemon is a fast-acting lozenge for sore-throat relief and bad cough plus other adverse singing symptoms. So, Cepacol helps you get your throat back into shape, ready for the stage performance.</p>
<p>Cepacol Lozenges will ease the discomfort and dryness when you&rsquo;re swallowing, singing, or talking  it&rsquo;ll also heal any apparent cold. Its time you did away with the pains, aches, runny nose, and headache that might affect your stage performance.
Cepacol Lozenges is lemon-honey flavored that&rsquo;ll give you an extraordinary amount of sore throat relaxation  for both singers and generally for anyone who&rsquo;s using their voice but is experiencing some vocal challenges.
Cepacol Lozenges will clear any coughs, ease the throat pain, and enable better singing. Luckily, the Lozenges come in tablets (quick-dissolving) and amazing sprays, which means that you&rsquo;ll get more favorable results.
Cepacol Lozenges is excellent for both kids (over 5 years) and adults. Benzocaine works on the pain receptors to ease your hurting while youre talking or singing. Consult with your medical specialist for advice but you wont require a doctor&rsquo;s prescription.
Pros:</p>
<ul>
<li>Great cough relief for even night times</li>
<li>Wont need a doctor&rsquo;s prescription</li>
<li>Heals allergies, throat and mouth irritations</li>
<li>Offers instant relief to throat pain</li>
</ul>
<p>Cons:</p>
<ul>
<li>Most people wont love the artificial ingredients</li>
<li>May cause a numbing feeling</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rAgY1WA6Qag">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rAgY1WA6Qag</a></p>
<p>Related:
9 Best Laptops for Drawing</p>
<h3 id="2-luden"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B005GECIAU/?tag=p-policy-20">2. Luden&rsquo;s Deliciously Soothing Throat Drops (Wild Cherry)</a></h3>
<p>Ludens Lozenges are excellent cough drops that are packaged or wrapped in a great re-seal-able bag. The have a candy feeling and thus will be your great alternative to people who can&rsquo;t stand menthol.</p>
<p>Its a great remedy for dingers who dont like menthol but still want to relief their sore mouths and throats. Many singers like the taste and smell of these Ludens Lozenges  some do actually consume them just like candy!
It contains sucrose, soybean oil, sodium chloride, sodium acetate, magic acid, flavors, coloring, corn syrup, citric acid, water, and ascorbic acid - relieves your sore and scratchy mouth and throat - you&rsquo;ll love the available variety of flavors!
Luden&rsquo;s Lozenges comes with a fantastic flavor (wild cherry) while still soothing your sore throat. It&rsquo;s an oral demulcent and Pectin lozenge.
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Demulcent">Demulcent</a>
is its main active ingredient, and it&rsquo;ll soothe your sore throat  all this with no adverse effects caused by menthol.
However, some people complain that Luden&rsquo;s Lozenges have sweeteners like corn syrup and artificial ingredients. Therefore, some singers may consider the Lozenges to be too sweet for themselves.
So, how good are ludens cough drops? Luden has demulcent  pectin thatll coat the mucous membranes thatre otherwise irritated and hence return you to the mood and form for perfect stage performance.
Pros:</p>
<ul>
<li>Excellent cough drops for singers</li>
<li>Has a variety of flavors like watermelon, berry, and peach</li>
<li>Will quickly soothe your dry sore throats</li>
<li>Lacks the irritating menthol</li>
</ul>
<p>Cons:</p>
<ul>
<li>None</li>
</ul>
<p>Related:
<a href="https://pestpolicy.com/what-is-piccolo/">What is Piccolo?</a></p>
<h3 id="3-secrets-lozenges-for-pain-and-sore-throat-relief-wild-cherry"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B000XE70LU/?tag=p-policy-20">3. Secrets Lozenges for Pain and Sore Throat Relief (Wild Cherry)</a></h3>
<p>Secrets
<a href="https://dailymed.nlm.nih.gov/dailymed/drugInfo.cfm?setid=da4967c7-ee18-42e7-8c97-8919f3bb1b7d">Lozenges</a>
will kill the sore throat that has even lasted for weeks - wild cherry flavor. They&rsquo;ll numb your throat excellently while healing the irritating cough.</p>
<p>Sucrets contain dyclonine, which is an oral anesthetic to suppress the cough while decreasing sore throat and nasal passages pain. The zinc and vitamin C additions will also boost the singer&rsquo;s immune system.
Sucrets tablets are known to equally help with the singer&rsquo;s dry mouth while also relieving severe coughs and sore throat. Luckily, Sucrets won&rsquo;t offer a temporary relief like other lozenges available in the market.
Sucrets has a vapor cherry flavor that&rsquo;ll give any singer a great and cooling effect  this thus will work well on your dry coughs and irritating throat tissues. Further, to quickly enhance your stage performance, Sucrets works instantly on your sore throat.
Granted, you might experience a dry cough or sore throat while you&rsquo;re traveling to the music studio or the performance stage. SO, just take a pack of Sucrets lozenges with you, and it&rsquo;ll help you ease the burning sensation in your throat.
Equally critical to note is that you&rsquo;ll need to talk to a medical professional if you&rsquo;re to give these Sucrets lozenges to a kid under three years. However, Sucrets don&rsquo;t require a medical prescription for adults, either singers or everyone else.
Sucrets have a great taste and sweet flavor that&rsquo;ll complement its working fast on your inflamed sore-throat tissues. This comes from the cherries and honey ingredients that are included in the Sucrets lozenges.
Pros:</p>
<ul>
<li>Will readily calm your irritating cough.</li>
<li>It containszinc and vitamin C for boosting the singer&rsquo;s immune system.</li>
<li>Will cool down your nasal passages</li>
<li>Offers fast and excellentsore throat and nasal passages pain relief</li>
<li>Has a great wild cherry flavor</li>
</ul>
<p>Cons:</p>
<ul>
<li>Offers only temporary pain relief</li>
</ul>
<p>Related:
<a href="https://pestpolicy.com/what-is-an-oboe/">What is an oboe?</a></p>
<h3 id="5-halls-sugar-free-lozenges--honey-lemon-flavored"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07QZCKWVK/?tag=p-policy-20">5. HALLS Sugar-Free lozenges -Honey Lemon Flavored</a></h3>
<p>HALLS Sugar-Free lozenges work like cough suppressants and come in various mountain menthol, citrus blend, and black cherry. Great for sore throats, coughs, and allergies.</p>
<p>The main active ingredient in these HALLS lozenges in 5.8 mg menthol in every drop while Water, Sodium Carboxymethylcellulose, Isomalt,
<a href="https://www.thieme-connect.com/products/ejournals/abstract/10.1055/s-0031-1296669">Lidocaine,</a>
Aspartame plus Acesulfame Potassium are the Inactive Ingredients.
The HALLS lozenges offer vitamin C in addition to giving the singer an excellent cooling effect for your sore throat. It&rsquo;ll relieve any irritation in air and sound passage  which is a superb lozenge for a great nasal area.
The HALLS lozenges will an addition suppress your cough while also nourishing the singer&rsquo;s mouth. It has a sweet taste  with a honey flavor. For the dusty time and harvest seasons, these HALLS lozenges are great against allergies.
Pros:</p>
<ul>
<li>Excellent against allergies</li>
<li>Has a great honey taste</li>
<li>Will relief your dry mouth - nourishing the singer&rsquo;s mouth.</li>
<li>Offers vitamin C</li>
</ul>
<p>Cons:</p>
<ul>
<li>None</li>
</ul>
<p>Related:
<a href="https://pestpolicy.com/best-mac-for-music-production/">Mac for Music Production</a></p>
<h2 id="sources">Sources:</h2>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/j.1742-1241.2009.02230.x">Rapid relief of acute sore throat with AMC/DCBA throat lozenges: randomised controlled t</a><a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/j.1742-1241.2009.02230.x">rial</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.ajol.info/index.php/safp/article/view/76190">Sprays and lozenges for sore throats</a></li>
<li><a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/ijcp.13002">Efficacy of AMC/DCBA lozenges for sore throat: A systematic review and metaanalysis</a></li>
</ol>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
