<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>No-See-Ums on Pest Policy</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/no-see-ums/</link>
    <description>Recent content in No-See-Ums on Pest Policy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/no-see-ums/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Best No See Ums Repellent</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/best-no-see-ums-repellent/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/best-no-see-ums-repellent/</guid>
      <description>Whether you&amp;#39;re hiking, camping, or just enjoying your backyard,</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Whether you&rsquo;re hiking, camping, or just enjoying your backyard,
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ceratopogonidae">No-see-ums</a>
may
invade and leave you with itchy bites, and red welts that&rsquo;ll spoil the fun in your outdoor activities.</p>
<p>In this article, I&rsquo;ve reviewed the best no-see-ums repellents to ensure you can savor your time outdoors without the annoyance.</p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s dive right in!</p>
<h2 id="top-5-no-see-ums-repellents-in-2025">Top 5 No-See-Ums Repellents in 2025</h2>
<h3 id="1-bug-soother-deet-free-natural-spray"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B072Z2CW3L?&amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;tag=p-policy-20&amp;linkId=acba6c2788e48e4707cc28952ebb3536&amp;language=en_US&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl">1. Bug Soother DEET-Free Natural Spray</a></h3>
<p>This DEET-free spray repels no-see-ums and other insects such as biting gnats, black flies, and mosquitoes. It&rsquo;s safe for your skin and pets, making it an excellent choice for family use.</p>
<p>Its natural ingredients ensure that you are not exposed to harmful chemicals, providing peace of mind while enjoying your outdoor activities.
<strong>Pros</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Natural Ingredients</strong>: Safe for adults, children, and pets; gentle on the skin.</li>
<li><strong>Effective <a href="/posts/best-gnat-repellent/">Repellent</a></strong>: Works against mosquitoes, gnats, and flying insects.</li>
<li><strong>Pleasant Scent</strong>: Enjoyable smell compared to chemical repellents.</li>
<li><strong>Versatile Use</strong>: Suitable for outdoor activities, pets, and livestock.
<strong>Cons</strong></li>
<li><strong>Cost</strong>: Potentially more expensive than chemical-based options.
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UScC2Y2DhOE">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UScC2Y2DhOE</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Related:
Spiders versus mosquitoes bites
.</p>
<h3 id="2-sawyer-sp657-bug-repellent-with-permethrin-for-tents--clothing"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B001ANQVYU?th=1&amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;tag=p-policy-20&amp;linkId=43e263c2ba5eea075dd08b47ea74ae4f&amp;language=en_US&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl">2. Sawyer SP657 Bug Repellent with Permethrin for Tents &amp; Clothing</a></h3>
<p>Sawyer SP657 uses permethrin to repel and kill <a href="/posts/natural-repellants-for-no-see-ums/">no-see-ums</a>, mosquitoes, ticks, and other insects. It&rsquo;s particularly effective when applied to clothing and gear, offering Long-lasting (extended) protection.</p>
<p>This makes it a great choice for campers and hikers who need reliable protection over long periods - Ideal for treating clothing and camping gear. The non-greasy and odorless formula ensures comfort and ease of use.
<strong>Pros</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Long-Lasting</strong>: Up to 6 weeks or 6 washings.</li>
<li><strong>Effective</strong>: Kills and repels mosquitoes, ticks, and more.</li>
<li><strong>Versatile</strong>: For clothing, tents, sleeping bags, and gear.</li>
<li><strong>Safe for Fabrics</strong>: Doesnt damage materials; odorless after drying.</li>
<li><strong>Disease Prevention</strong>: Protects against Lyme disease and West Nile virus.
<strong>Cons</strong></li>
<li><strong>Chemical Exposure</strong>: Harmful to cats when wet; inhalation risk during application.</li>
<li><strong>Not for Skin</strong>: Only for gear and clothing, not direct skin use.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="3-pick-avon-sss-bug-guard-plus-picaridin-deet-free"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B007WFRX6A?&amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;tag=p-policy-20&amp;linkId=c1eb1ff1a6f560eba60bc161590deb6f&amp;language=en_US&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl">3. Pick Avon SSS Bug Guard-Plus Picaridin (DEET-free)</a></h3>
<p>This
<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4173961/">DEET-free repellent</a>
is gentle on sensitive skin. The 20% Picaridin is a powerful yet safe ingredient that repels a variety of insects, including
<a href="https://pestpolicy.com/how-to-get-rid-of-no-see-ums/">no-see-ums away</a>
, mosquitoes, and ticks.</p>
<p>The addition of Vitamin E and Aloe not only helps to repel insects but also moisturizes your skin, making it a perfect choice for those with sensitive skin.</p>
<p>The dual-action formula ensures that you are protected for up to 12 hours, allowing you to enjoy your outdoor activities without worry.
<strong>Pros</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>DEET-Free</strong>: Safe for use on children and those with sensitive skin.</li>
<li><strong>Effective</strong>: Repels mosquitoes, ticks, and other insects.</li>
<li><strong>Non-Greasy</strong>: Leaves skin feeling smooth and non-sticky.</li>
<li><strong>Pleasant Scent</strong>: Has a mild, pleasant fragrance.</li>
<li><strong>Versatile</strong>: Suitable for both indoor and outdoor use.
<strong>Cons</strong></li>
<li><strong>Frequent Reapplication</strong>: May need to be reapplied more often than DEET-based repellents.</li>
<li><strong>Limited Duration</strong>: Effectiveness can wear off faster in heavily infested areas.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="4-repel-lemon-eucalyptus-natural-deet-free"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B001EUGBQC?&amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;tag=p-policy-20&amp;linkId=76151f224260033f849b2e982aae12cf&amp;language=en_US&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl">4. Repel Lemon Eucalyptus Natural (DEET-free)</a></h3>
<p>Repel&rsquo;s Lemon Eucalyptus spray is a natural alternative to chemical repellents. It effectively keeps no-see-ums and other biting insects at bay, providing a safe and natural option for outdoor enthusiasts.</p>
<ul>
<li>The natural formula ensures that you are not exposed to harmful chemicals, while still providing effective protection.
This repellent is ideal for those who prefer natural products and want to avoid potential side effects of chemical repellents.
<strong>Pros</strong></li>
<li><strong>Natural Ingredients</strong>: DEET-free and derived from lemon eucalyptus oil.</li>
<li><strong>Effective</strong>: Repels mosquitoes for up to 6 hours.</li>
<li><strong>Pleasant Scent</strong>: Refreshing lemon eucalyptus smell.</li>
<li><strong>Eco-Friendly</strong>: Safer for the environment and biodegradable.</li>
<li><strong>Skin-Friendly</strong>: Gentle on the skin, suitable for sensitive users.
<strong>Cons</strong></li>
<li><strong>Frequent Reapplication</strong>: Requires more frequent reapplication compared to DEET-based products.</li>
<li><strong>Potential Allergies</strong>: Some individuals might be sensitive to essential oils.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="5-repel-94101-40-percent-deet-max-for-no-see-ums"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0054NFYDG?&amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;tag=p-policy-20&amp;linkId=7ec30d57ee88ac5bfecca12c2a594481&amp;language=en_US&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl">5. Repel 94101 40-Percent DEET Max for No See Ums</a></h3>
<p>Repel 94101 offers robust protection with 40% DEET, making it suitable for numerous outdoor activities. It effectively repels no-see-ums, mosquitoes, and other biting insects.</p>
<ul>
<li>The non-greasy formula ensures that it is comfortable to wear, and the lack of a strong scent makes it ideal for those who are sensitive to odors.
This repellent provides protection for up to 8 hours, making it perfect for long outdoor activities such as hiking, camping, and sports.</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="pros">Pros</h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>High DEET Content</strong>: Provides strong protection against biting insects like no see ums.</li>
<li><strong>Long-Lasting</strong>: Effective for up to 8 hours.</li>
<li><strong>Wide Application</strong>: Suitable for outdoor activities in heavily infested areas.</li>
<li><strong>Water-Resistant</strong>: Works well even with sweat or rain exposure.</li>
<li><strong>Proven Effectiveness</strong>: Trusted formula for mosquito and insect repellency.</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="cons">Cons</h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Odor</strong>: Strong chemical odor that some users may find unpleasant.</li>
<li><strong>Potential Damage</strong>: Can damage plastics and synthetic fabrics if not used cautiously.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="additional-tips-for-no-see-ums-protection">Additional Tips for No-See-Ums Protection</h2>
<dl>
<dt><strong>1. Wear Protective Clothing</strong></dt>
<dd>Long sleeves, pants, and hats can help protect your skin from bites.
<strong>2. Avoid Peak Activity Times</strong></dd>
<dd>No-see-ums are most active during dawn and dusk. Plan your outdoor activities accordingly.
<strong>3. Use Insect Screens</strong></dd>
<dd>Install fine mesh screens on windows and doors to keep no-see-ums out of your home.
<strong>4. Eliminate Standing Water</strong></dd>
<dd>No-see-ums breed in stagnant water. Regularly empty and clean bird baths, pet water dishes, and other containers that can collect water.</dd>
</dl>
<p>These additional measures can help reduce your risk of no-see-um bites and make your outdoor experiences more enjoyable.</p>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>Protecting yourself from no-see-ums and other biting insects is essential for enjoying outdoor activities. Using the best no-see-ums repellent will help you stay bite-free and comfortable.</p>
<ul>
<li>From natural options like Bug Soother DEET-Free Natural Spray and Repel Lemon Eucalyptus Natural to powerful chemical repellents like Repel 94101 40-Percent DEET Max, there are plenty of effective products to choose from.
Share your experiences with no-see-ums and the reviewed products in the comments below!</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Repellants for No See Ums</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/natural-repellants-for-no-see-ums/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/natural-repellants-for-no-see-ums/</guid>
      <description>No-see-ums, also known as biting midges or sandflies, can be quite bothersome with their itchy bites. While there&amp;#39;s no foolproof method to completely eradi...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="/posts/best-no-see-ums-repellent/">No-see-ums</a>, also known as biting midges or sandflies, can be quite bothersome with their itchy bites. While there&rsquo;s no foolproof method to completely eradicate them, there are some natural repellents you can try to keep them at bay:</p>
<h2 id="1-geranium-rose-oil-">**1. Geranium rose oil: **</h2>
<p>Geranium oil is a good ingredient in repellents for insects that bite like ticks and no see ums.
Geraniums are made of organic ingredients (organic and pure rose geraniums) which are not toxic to humans. It has a pleasant smell that will stay with you for hours and is also used in many other bug repellents on the market today.
They balance skin pH levels and open up skin pores so they work well with repellents.</p>
<ul>
<li>Geranium oil can be applied as an insect repellent or diluted into your skincare products such as lotions and shampoos, which will provide protection for either two or four hours.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="2-citronella-oil-">**2. Citronella oil: **</h2>
<p>Citronella oil is made from the leaves and stems of lemongrass. Lemongrass usually has a lot of geraniol, citronellol, and citronellal.</p>
<ul>
<li>It&rsquo;s great to use when you are making no see-ums repellent and<a href="https://pestpolicy.com/essential-oils-for-bed-bugs/">bed bug repellents</a>.
You can use citronella oil to protect yourself from bugs. But it is not as good as DEET.
<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/21481108/">Vanilla</a>
can help extend the protection time. It is often found in vanilla beans or in the CO2 extract.
If you like making candles, this is something to explore. If not, consider buying no see um repellents with citronella such as</li>
<li>Cutter-Citroguard Triple-Wick</li>
<li>TIKI-1418014 Brand 17</li>
<li>Murphys-Naturals Mini</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="3-lemongrass-oil-">**3. Lemongrass oil: **</h2>
<p>You can try burning lemongrass oil using
<strong>oil</strong>
lamps to see if it will help keep the no-see-ums and Sand Flies away - that is one reason why it is in some mosquito repellents.
<em>Preparation:</em>
Mix  cup of witch hazel together with  cup of distilled water and Lemongrass Essential Oil (Aura Cacia Organic - 21 to 26 drops).
This can be sprayed on your clothing, body, or exposed skin surfaces in order to repel insects from biting you - as noted by the
<a href="http://entnemdept.ufl.edu/creatures/aquatic/biting_midges.htm">Entomology &amp; Nematology Department.</a></p>
<h2 id="4-special-garments-">**4. Special garments: **</h2>
<p>To avoid insects from getting into your
<a href="https://pestpolicy.com/can-fleas-live-on-clothes/">clothes and biting</a>
, you should wear special clothes that have a net that keeps them out.
When your vacuum cleaner is not enough to keep the critters away, you can protect yourself with long pants and long shirts, as well as by switching on the air conditioner.</p>
<h2 id="6small-mesh-screening">6.<strong>Small Mesh Screening</strong></h2>
<p>Mosquitos can get into your home through open windows. You can stop them with screens on all the windows in your house.
The small mesh screens can stop tiny bugs that people can&rsquo;t see including no see ums.</p>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>Remember to perform a patch test before applying any essential oil directly to your skin, as some people may have sensitivities or allergies. Also, reapply these repellents frequently, especially if you&rsquo;re sweating or swimming, as they may wear off over time.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
