<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Season on Pest Policy</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/season/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Season on Pest Policy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/season/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Navigating Rainy Season in Seattle Protect Your Home from Seasonal Pests</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/navigating-rainy-season-in-seattle-protect-your-home-from-seasonal-pests/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/navigating-rainy-season-in-seattle-protect-your-home-from-seasonal-pests/</guid>
      <description>Seattle&amp;#39;s rainy season creates an ideal environment for pests. Increased moisture drives them indoors and provides breeding grounds around your home. Heres...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<dl>
<dt>Seattle&rsquo;s rainy season creates an ideal environment for pests. Increased moisture drives them indoors and provides breeding grounds around your home. Heres how to protect your home from common pests during this time:</dt>
<dt><strong>Seal Entry Points</strong></dt>
<dd>Inspect and seal cracks and gaps in windows, doors, and the foundation with caulk or weather stripping. Install door sweeps to block entry through gaps under doors.
<strong>Maintain Your Yard</strong></dd>
<dd>Remove debris like leaf piles and fallen branches. Trim shrubs, trees, and grass to keep them away from your home&rsquo;s exterior, reducing potential habitats for pests -
<a href="https://pestpolicy.com/best-flea-spray-for-yard/">well-maintained yard</a>
.
<strong>Address Moisture Issues</strong></dd>
<dd>Fix plumbing and roof leaks promptly. Ensure proper drainage around your home, keeping gutters and downspouts clear to prevent water pooling.
<strong>Store Food Properly</strong></dd>
<dd>Use airtight containers for food storage. Regularly clean kitchen areas, wipe down counters, and take out the trash to avoid attracting pests.
<strong>Use Pest Control Solutions</strong></dd>
<dd>Set up baits and traps for pests like rodents,
<a href="https://pestpolicy.com/how-to-get-rid-of-spiders/">spiders</a>
, and ants. Consider hiring professional pest control services for regular inspections and treatments.
<strong>Keep Firewood and Mulch Away</strong></dd>
<dd>Store firewood at least 20 feet from your home and elevate it off the ground. Use mulch sparingly near your homes foundation to prevent attracting pests.
<strong>Monitor and Inspect</strong></dd>
<dd>Conduct regular inspections, focusing on basements, attics, and crawl spaces. Use sticky traps to detect early signs of infestations.
<strong>Professional Pest Control</strong></dd>
<dd>Consider professional services for expert solutions. They offer customized plans, eco-friendly options, and year-round protection to keep your home pest-free.</dd>
</dl>
<p>By taking these steps, you can minimize the risk of pest infestations during Seattles rainy season and keep your home safe and comfortable. Contact a pest control service for tailored expert solutions if needed.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
