<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Flea-Control on Pest Policy</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/flea-control/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Flea-Control on Pest Policy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/flea-control/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Diatomaceous Earth Vs Borax for Fleas</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/diatomaceous-earth-vs-borax-for-fleas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/diatomaceous-earth-vs-borax-for-fleas/</guid>
      <description>A comprehensive, real-talk guide comparing Diatomaceous Earth (DE) and Borax for fleas. As a pet owner, here&amp;#39;s my experience on which powder is safer and more effective for your home.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You saw it, didn&rsquo;t you? That tiny black speck that jumped. Maybe it was on your ankle, or maybe you saw it on your pet’s white fur. That single moment sends a wave of dread through any homeowner, and it leads to the same frantic, late-night internet search: &ldquo;how to get rid of fleas FAST.&rdquo; That search will inevitably lead you to two popular DIY solutions: white powders that promise to end the infestation in your carpets. One of them is likely the familiar box of <span style="color:red;">[20 Mule Team <a href="/posts/borax-flea-killer/">Borax</a>](<a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B000R4L32E/?tag=p-policy-20">https://www.amazon.com/dp/B000R4L32E/?tag=p-policy-20</a>)</span> from the laundry aisle, a product you&rsquo;ve seen for years.</p>
<p>The other contender is a powder you may have heard of but don&rsquo;t know as well, called <span style="color:red;">[Food-Grade Diatomaceous <a href="/posts/diatomaceous-earth/">Earth</a>](<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Harris-Diatomaceous-Earth-Powder-Duster/dp/B072J8Z28F?th=1&amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;tag=p-policy-20&amp;linkId=f7253eb7f0f22c7858d1c74cbccc18e7&amp;language=en_US&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl">https://www.amazon.com/Harris-Diatomaceous-Earth-Powder-Duster/dp/B072J8Z28F?th=1&amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;tag=p-policy-20&amp;linkId=f7253eb7f0f22c7858d1c74cbccc18e7&amp;language=en_US&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl</a>)</span>. Both are inexpensive, and countless forums and articles claim they’re the secret to winning the war against fleas. On the surface, they seem interchangeable. But they are not. As someone who has navigated the stress of a flea infestation with pets in the house, I can tell you that the difference between these two powders is profound. It’s not just about what works—it’s about what’s safe for the family you’re trying to protect.</p>










  <div class="pinnable-container" style="text-align: center; margin: 2rem 0;">
    <figure>
      
      <img src="/posts/diatomaceous-earth-vs-borax-for-fleas/diatomaceous-earth-vs-borax-for-fleas.jpg" alt="A comparison of Diatomaceous Earth and Borax powders side-by-side, used for DIY flea control." style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 8px;">

      
        <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #6c757d; margin-top: 0.5em;">Are you using the right flea powder? This honest guide for pet owners breaks down the real difference between Diatomaceous Earth and Borax, and why one is a much safer choice. #fleacontrol #diatomaceousearth #petsafety #naturalpestcontrol</figcaption>
      
    </figure>
  </div>

<h3 id="understanding-the-real-enemy-why-fleas-are-so-hard-to-kill">Understanding the Real Enemy: Why Fleas Are So Hard to Kill</h3>
<p>Before we even talk about powders, you have to understand that the adult fleas you see are only about 5% of the total problem. The other 95% of the infestation is hiding in your carpets, furniture, and pet bedding as eggs, larvae, and pupae. This is why a single treatment rarely works; you have to break the entire life cycle. Any effective solution must address not only the biting adults but also the next generation waiting to emerge.</p>
<h3 id="what-is-diatomaceous-earth-the-natural-assassin">What is Diatomaceous Earth? The Natural Assassin</h3>
<p>The easiest way to picture Diatomaceous Earth (DE) is as microscopic, jagged fossils. It’s a natural powder made from the fossilized remains of tiny aquatic organisms called diatoms. While it feels soft like flour to us, on a microscopic level, it’s incredibly sharp and abrasive. This is its secret weapon. DE is a <em>mechanical</em> killer, not a chemical one. It doesn’t poison fleas. Instead, when a flea walks through the powder, the sharp particles physically scrape away the waxy, protective outer layer of its exoskeleton. This process fatally dehydrates the flea, killing it from the outside in. Because this is a physical attack, fleas can&rsquo;t develop a resistance to it like they can with chemical pesticides.</p>
<p>The most important thing you need to know is that you <strong>must</strong> use <strong>food-grade DE</strong>. This grade is mined from freshwater sources and is purified to be safe for mammals. It&rsquo;s so safe, in fact, that it’s often used as a health supplement and in animal feed to control internal parasites. This is the powder you want in your home. (Do not confuse it with &ldquo;pool-grade&rdquo; DE, which is chemically treated and dangerous to inhale).</p>
<h3 id="what-is-borax-the-common-household-chemical">What is Borax? The Common Household Chemical</h3>
<p>You probably have Borax in your laundry room right now. It’s a naturally occurring mineral salt, and there’s no question that it is an effective insecticide. Borax works as both a desiccant (like DE) and, more potently, as a stomach poison. As fleas move through a treated carpet, the small crystals get stuck to their bodies. When they groom themselves, they ingest the Borax, which shreds their insides and kills them. It’s brutally effective.</p>
<p>However—and for me, this is the deal-breaker—<strong>Borax is toxic if ingested by pets or children.</strong> If your dog or cat licks the powder from their paws or grooms it out of their fur after walking on a treated carpet, they can suffer from skin irritation, digestive distress, vomiting, and in severe cases, even more serious health consequences.</p>
<h3 id="the-verdict-for-pet-owners-its-not-even-a-debate">The Verdict: For Pet Owners, It’s Not Even a Debate</h3>
<p>When I weigh the options, the choice becomes crystal clear. Why would I introduce a known toxin into my home to solve one problem, only to create a potential health emergency for my pet? It&rsquo;s a risk I&rsquo;m not willing to take.</p>
<p>For any household with pets or small children, <strong>food-grade Diatomaceous Earth is the only responsible choice.</strong> It&rsquo;s just as effective at killing fleas over time, but it comes without the scary risks. The peace of mind you get from knowing your pets are safe while you treat your home is worth everything.</p>
<h3 id="my-complete-step-by-step-battle-plan-for-using-de">My Complete Step-by-Step Battle Plan for Using DE</h3>
<p>Just sprinkling some powder around won&rsquo;t cut it. You need a strategy. Here is the exact method I use to successfully eradicate fleas.</p>
<p><strong>Step 1: The All-Important Prep Work</strong>
Before you even open the bag of DE, you have to prepare the environment. Start by treating your pet with a veterinarian-approved flea treatment. Then, wash all of your pet&rsquo;s bedding, blankets, and any washable fabrics in hot water. Finally, you need to vacuum. Vacuum everything—carpets, rugs, sofas, chairs, and especially the corners and edges of rooms. This not only sucks up some of the existing fleas and eggs but the vibration also encourages the dormant pupae to hatch, exposing the new adult fleas to the treatment you&rsquo;re about to lay down.</p>
<p><strong>Step 2: The Application</strong>
Now it&rsquo;s time to apply the DE. I highly recommend wearing a simple dust mask for this part, as the fine powder can be irritating if you breathe it in. You want to apply a <strong>light, even dusting</strong>, not a thick pile. A heavy application can actually deter fleas from walking through it. Use a powder duster for a fine mist, or simply use your hand to gently shake it over your carpets and furniture. Make sure to get it along baseboards, under cushions, and into all the dark, hidden places where fleas love to hide.</p>
<p><strong>Step 3: The Waiting Game</strong>
This is the hardest part: patience. DE does not kill instantly. You need to leave the powder down for at least <strong>48 to 72 hours</strong>. This gives the fleas ample time to move through the powder and begin the dehydration process. During this time, it’s best to limit activity in the treated rooms if possible.</p>
<p><strong>Step 4: The Final Clean-Up</strong>
After a few days, it&rsquo;s time to vacuum again. Use a vacuum with a good filter and go over all the treated areas thoroughly. This will remove the DE along with the dead fleas. Immediately after you finish, take the vacuum canister or bag outside to empty it into a sealed garbage bag. You don&rsquo;t want any survivors crawling back out of your vacuum.</p>
<p>Because new fleas can continue to hatch for a couple of weeks, you should <strong>repeat this entire process once a week for at least two to three weeks.</strong> This persistence is the key to breaking the life cycle completely.</p>
<p>For a reliable and safe product, I always point people towards something like the <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Harris-Diatomaceous-Earth-Powder-Duster/dp/B072J8Z28F?th=1&amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;tag=p-policy-20&amp;linkId=f7253eb7f0f22c7858d1c74cbccc18e7&amp;language=en_US&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl">Harris Food Grade Diatomaceous Earth with Duster</a></strong>. It&rsquo;s an effective tool in your arsenal that lets you fight back against fleas without compromising the safety of your home.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flea Bombs Vs Flea Sprays</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/flea-bombs-vs-flea-sprays/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/flea-bombs-vs-flea-sprays/</guid>
      <description>Standing in the pest control aisle? I&amp;#39;ve been there. Here’s my honest, real-world comparison of flea bombs and flea sprays to help you choose the best treatment for your home.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There&rsquo;s a unique sinking feeling that hits you the moment you realize fleas have invaded your home. It’s a mix of disgust and urgency that sends you straight to the store, standing in the pest control aisle with one mission: to end this <em>now</em>. In your hands, you’ll likely hold the two most common weapons in this war: a <span style="color:red;"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0054NFWH4/?tag=p-policy-20">flea bomb (or fogger)</a></span> and a can of flea spray. The bomb promises total annihilation, a &ldquo;set it and forget it&rdquo; solution. The spray seems more targeted, more controlled. So, which one should you choose?</p>
<p>I’ve been in your shoes, and I can tell you that the choice you make in that moment is critical. One path often leads to lingering frustration and a re-infestation, while the other leads to lasting peace of mind. To truly solve a flea problem, you need to think beyond just killing the adult fleas you see hopping around. The real enemy is the 95% of the infestation you <em>can&rsquo;t</em> see: the eggs and larvae hiding deep in your carpets and furniture. A good home treatment, like the popular <span style="color:red;"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B00JN9H50M/?tag=p-policy-20">Adams Flea &amp; Tick Home Spray</a></span>, is designed to tackle this entire life cycle, which is the secret to winning the war for good. Let’s break down the real-world difference between these two approaches.</p>










  <div class="pinnable-container" style="text-align: center; margin: 2rem 0;">
    <figure>
      
      <img src="/posts/flea-bombs-vs-flea-sprays/flea-bombs-vs-sprays.jpg" alt="A side-by-side comparison of a flea bomb canister and a flea spray bottle to treat a home infestation." style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 8px;">

      
        <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #6c757d; margin-top: 0.5em;">Flea bombs vs. flea sprays: which one should you use? This honest guide breaks down the pros, cons, and safety to help you choose the right treatment to eliminate fleas for good. #fleacontrol #fleas #pestcontrol #homecare</figcaption>
      
    </figure>
  </div>

<h3 id="the-flea-bomb-a-grenade-that-misses-the-target">The Flea Bomb: A Grenade That Misses the Target</h3>
<p>On paper, the flea bomb seems like the perfect solution. You press a button, leave the house, and come back a few hours later to a flea-free paradise. It’s marketed as a powerful, hands-off approach to pest control.</p>
<p>But here’s the problem I’ve learned the hard way: <strong>flea bombs are fundamentally flawed.</strong></p>
<p>Think of a flea bomb as a grenade. It explodes and sends a cloud of pesticide mist into the air. This mist then slowly settles downwards, coating every exposed surface in the room—the top of your couch, your coffee table, your kitchen counters. It’s great at killing any unlucky fleas that happen to be out in the open.</p>
<p>The issue is that fleas are smart survivors. They don&rsquo;t hang out in the middle of the room. They hide. They live deep within the fibers of your carpet, under the cushions of your sofa, in the back of your closets, and in the tiny cracks along your baseboards. The fog from a flea bomb simply can&rsquo;t penetrate these hidden sanctuaries where the eggs and larvae are developing. So, while you might kill a portion of the adult population, you’re leaving the next generation completely untouched, virtually guaranteeing the problem will return in a few weeks.</p>
<p>On top of being ineffective, flea bombs require a massive amount of prep work and raise significant safety concerns. You have to remove or cover all food, dishes, and pet supplies. You have to evacuate your family and pets for hours. And because the aerosol can be flammable, you have to extinguish all pilot lights. After all that, you&rsquo;re left with a chemical residue on every surface that needs to be wiped down. It’s a lot of hassle for a solution that doesn&rsquo;t even solve the root problem.</p>
<h3 id="the-flea-spray-a-sniper-rifle-for-where-fleas-actually-live">The Flea Spray: A Sniper Rifle for Where Fleas Actually Live</h3>
<p>Now, let&rsquo;s talk about flea sprays. If a flea bomb is a grenade, a targeted flea spray is a sniper rifle. It puts the pesticide exactly where you need it and nowhere you don&rsquo;t.</p>
<p>With a spray, you can directly treat the areas where fleas, eggs, and larvae are actually hiding. You can spray deep into carpets, under furniture, on your pet&rsquo;s bedding (after washing it, of course), and along the baseboards and crevices that foggers can&rsquo;t reach. This targeted approach is immediately more effective because you’re taking the fight directly to the enemy&rsquo;s stronghold.</p>
<p>But the real power of a modern flea spray lies in a key ingredient: an <strong>Insect Growth Regulator (IGR)</strong>.</p>
<p>An IGR is a miracle of science. It doesn&rsquo;t kill adult fleas, but it does something even more important: it acts as a form of birth control for fleas, preventing their eggs from hatching and their larvae from maturing into biting adults. This is how you <strong>break the life cycle</strong>. When you use a spray with an IGR, you&rsquo;re not just killing the fleas of today; you&rsquo;re preventing the fleas of tomorrow, next week, and next month from ever existing. Many of these sprays provide residual protection for up to seven months.</p>
<p>From a safety perspective, you have much more control. You&rsquo;re not filling your entire home with a chemical fog. You apply the product to specific surfaces and, by following the directions to keep pets and kids away until it dries, you can use it responsibly and with peace of mind.</p>
<h3 id="the-verdict-its-no-contest">The Verdict: It&rsquo;s No Contest</h3>
<p>After dealing with this issue myself, my recommendation is strong and clear: <strong>for almost every single home infestation, a high-quality flea spray with an IGR is vastly superior to a flea bomb.</strong></p>
<p>The flea bomb is an outdated technology that sells a promise of convenience but ultimately fails to deliver a real solution. A targeted flea spray is a more effective, safer, and ultimately more permanent way to reclaim your home from these pests.</p>
<p>For most situations, a product like the <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B00JN9H50M/?tag=p-policy-20">Adams Flea &amp; Tick Home Spray</a></strong> is my top recommendation because it contains an IGR and is proven to be effective. If you prefer an all-natural approach and are dealing with a lighter infestation, a product like <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B01M8GFPXG/?tag=p-policy-20">Wondercide Flea &amp; Tick Spray</a></strong>, which uses essential oils, is a popular and pleasant-smelling alternative.</p>
<p>The only time I would even consider a flea bomb is for a truly catastrophic infestation in an empty room or space, and even then, I would <em>immediately</em> follow it up with a thorough IGR spray treatment to handle the survivors. Don&rsquo;t waste your time, money, and effort on a solution that only solves half the problem. Choose the right tool for the job and get rid of fleas for good.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Check Your Home for Fleas</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-to-check-your-home-for-fleas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-to-check-your-home-for-fleas/</guid>
      <description>Think you might have fleas? This friendly guide walks you through a simple 5-point inspection to find out for sure, starting with the famous &amp;#39;white sock test&amp;#39;.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It starts with a nagging feeling, doesn&rsquo;t it? A tiny black speck you thought you saw jump. A pet that seems to be scratching just a little more than usual. The suspicion that you might have fleas is enough to make anyone&rsquo;s skin crawl. Before you can declare war, you need to be sure. You have to gather intelligence and confirm that the enemy is actually present. The absolute first place to check is the most likely source: <a href="/posts/growing-chrysanthemums-in-your-garden/">your</a> pet. A quick but thorough combing with a specialty tool like a <span style="color:red;"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0002AQS0I/?tag=p-policy-20">Safari Flea Comb</a></span> will give you your first definitive clue. The fine-toothed metal bristles are designed to trap live fleas and their tell-tale &ldquo;flea dirt.&rdquo;</p>
<p>But what if your pet comes up clean? That doesn&rsquo;t mean you&rsquo;re in the clear. The majority of a flea population lives in the environment, not on your pet. They hide in your carpets, your furniture, and your pet’s bedding, waiting for their next meal. To find out if you have a larger environmental problem, you need a way to monitor these areas. Setting up a simple, non-toxic device like the <span style="color:red;"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B000668Z96/?tag=p-policy-20">Victor Flea Trap</a></span> near your pet&rsquo;s favorite sleeping spot is the perfect next step. The gentle warmth and light attract fleas from the surrounding area onto a sticky pad, giving you undeniable proof of an infestation. Finding fleas early is the key to stopping a small issue from exploding into a full-blown nightmare. This guide will walk you through a simple 5-point inspection to find out for sure.</p>










  <div class="pinnable-container" style="text-align: center; margin: 2rem 0;">
    <figure>
      
      <img src="/posts/how-to-check-your-home-for-fleas/check-for-fleas-guide.jpg" alt="A guide showing a homeowner checking for fleas in carpets and on pet bedding." style="max-width: 100%; height: auto; border-radius: 8px;">

      
        <figcaption style="font-size: 0.9em; color: #6c757d; margin-top: 0.5em;">Think you have fleas? This simple 5-point inspection, including the famous 'white sock test', will help you confirm a flea infestation in your home today. #fleacontrol #hometips #pestcontrol #petsafety #fleas</figcaption>
      
    </figure>
  </div>

<h3 id="your-5-point-inspection-plan-for-fleas">Your 5-Point Inspection Plan for Fleas</h3>
<p>Let&rsquo;s get methodical. By checking these five sneaky hiding spots, you&rsquo;ll know one way or another if you have a flea problem.</p>
<h4 id="1-the-famous-white-sock-test">1. The Famous &ldquo;White Sock Test&rdquo;</h4>
<p>This is the classic, go-to method for a reason—it works, and it’s incredibly simple. Fleas are attracted to three things: warmth, vibration, and carbon dioxide (your breath). When you walk through a room, you&rsquo;re a walking, talking flea magnet. The white socks just make the dark-colored fleas incredibly easy to spot.</p>
<p><strong>Here&rsquo;s how to do it right:</strong> Pull on a pair of clean, white, calf-high socks. Now, walk slowly and deliberately through the areas you suspect might have fleas. Shuffle your feet as you go to create more vibration. Make sure to cover the carpets, area rugs, and especially the spots where your pets love to lounge. Do this for about ten minutes, then go stand in a well-lit area (like your kitchen or bathroom) and closely examine your socks, all the way up to your calves. If fleas are present, you will likely see a few small black or dark reddish-brown specks clinging to the fabric.</p>
<h4 id="2-ground-zero-your-pets-bedding-and-favorite-spots">2. Ground Zero: Your Pet’s Bedding and Favorite Spots</h4>
<p>If you have fleas in your home, it&rsquo;s almost a guarantee that they are living and breeding where your pet sleeps and rests. This is the heart of the infestation. Get a flashlight and get ready to look closely. You&rsquo;re searching for three things: live fleas, &ldquo;flea dirt,&rdquo; and flea eggs.</p>
<p>Live fleas are small, dark, and move incredibly fast, often disappearing into the fabric before you can get a good look. What&rsquo;s often easier to spot is <strong>&ldquo;flea dirt.&rdquo;</strong> This is actually flea feces, and it looks like tiny specks of black pepper scattered on the bedding. To confirm if it&rsquo;s flea dirt or just regular house dust, wipe some of it onto a damp white paper towel. If it dissolves and leaves a reddish-brown smear (from the digested blood), you&rsquo;ve found your proof. Flea eggs are harder to see; they are tiny, oval, and white, often mistaken for dandruff or salt grains.</p>
<h4 id="3-the-flea-paradise-deep-within-your-carpets-and-rugs">3. The Flea Paradise: Deep Within Your Carpets and Rugs</h4>
<p>Your carpets are a flea&rsquo;s best friend. The dense fibers provide the perfect cover for adults, larvae, and eggs, protecting them from light, predators, and even the vacuum cleaner.</p>
<p>To check your carpets, you need to get on your hands and knees. Use your fingers to part the carpet fibers and look deep down at the base. Pay special attention to the areas where your pets frequently lie down, as this is where the most &ldquo;flea dirt&rdquo; and eggs will fall off their bodies. Also, check the edges of the room along the baseboards, as this is a common place for fleas to hide.</p>
<h4 id="4-the-nursery-along-baseboards-and-in-floor-cracks">4. The Nursery: Along Baseboards and in Floor Cracks</h4>
<p>Fleas are secretive and prefer to lay their eggs in dark, undisturbed areas. The tiny cracks and crevices along your baseboards and between hardwood floor planks are perfect incubation zones.</p>
<p>Take a flashlight and get close to the floor. Carefully inspect the gap where the wall meets the floor, looking for live fleas or flea dirt. If you have hardwood floors, pay close attention to the spaces between the boards, especially in low-traffic corners or under furniture. It&rsquo;s these hidden spots that allow an infestation to persist even when you think you&rsquo;ve treated everything.</p>
<h4 id="5-the-ambush-zone-in-and-under-your-upholstered-furniture">5. The Ambush Zone: In and Under Your Upholstered Furniture</h4>
<p>Your sofa, armchairs, and other upholstered furniture are prime real estate for fleas. They offer warmth, shelter, and plenty of places to hide before they jump onto their next host—you or your pet.</p>
<p>Start by removing all the cushions and pillows. Using a flashlight, inspect all the seams, crevices, and corners of the furniture frame. Don&rsquo;t forget to check the fabric skirts at the bottom of chairs and couches, as well as the dark, protected space underneath the furniture itself. This is a common &ldquo;ambush zone&rdquo; for fleas.</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="confirmed-you-have-fleas-heres-the-crucial-next-step">Confirmed You Have Fleas? Here’s the Crucial Next Step.</h3>
<p>Finding adult fleas is one thing; eliminating them completely is another. The real challenge, and the key to winning this fight, is destroying their eggs and larvae. These are notoriously resistant to many common sprays and powders and can lie dormant for weeks, just waiting to hatch and start the cycle all over again.</p>
<p>If you find fleas, the most effective way to kill the <em>entire</em> flea life cycle on contact is with a powerful steam cleaner. While sprays can kill some adult fleas, the superheated steam penetrates deep into carpets, furniture, and pet bedding to kill everything from the adults to the resilient eggs. It&rsquo;s the most effective way to ensure they are gone for good.</p>
<p><strong>See our review of the <a href="/best-steam-cleaner-for-fleas/">best steam cleaners for fleas here</a> to find the right model to solve your problem.</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
