<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Door on Pest Policy</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/door/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Door on Pest Policy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/door/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Best Paint for Interior Doors</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/best-paint-for-interior-doors/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/best-paint-for-interior-doors/</guid>
      <description>The interior of your house can be a high traffic zone, especially if you have more occupants who must move from one room to another.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="/posts/how-to-paint-a-metal-interior-door/">interior</a> of your house can be a high traffic zone, especially if you have more occupants who must move from one room to another.</p>
<p>During such movement, hands interact a lot with doors, thus staining and making them dirty.
It is for such reasons that your doors need a regular touch by the Best Paint for Interior Doors to keep them neat and attractive. See Also:
<a href="https://pestpolicy.com/how-to-paint-a-metal-interior-door/">Painting your Metal Interior Door</a>
.</p>
<h2 id="s-top-7-best-paint-for-interior-doors-in-2025">s: Top 7 Best Paint for Interior Doors in 2025</h2>
<h3 id="1-the-spruce-best-kilz-15121001-interior-eggshell-paint"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07QJ7TMTZ/?tag=p-policy-20">1. The Spruce Best KILZ 15121001 Interior Eggshell Paint</a></h3>
<p>Buying this product means that you are going to kill two birds with one stone. In other words, it comprises both paint and primer in one product.</p>
<p>This eliminates the need to use another primer coat to paint over porous substrates even on
playsets
. It is available in thirty-two foolproof designer colors which include bold statement colors and timeless neutral shades.
The Spruce Best KILZ is incredibly low on Volatile Organic Compounds and odor. Whats more, it is a premium, fully acrylic product that is easy to apply and clean as well. To clean, you only need soap and water, and your doors will be super clean.
Although one coat is enough, an additional one may give you greater durability. Typically, one gallon covers 250 - 400 square feet, but coverage largely depends on the painting method you apply.
It is quite easy to apply since all you need is a roller, brush, or
airless sprayer
. After painting, you will only have to wait for one hour to touch and recoat after two hours. You also have 3 sheens to choose from which are Semi-Gloss, Satin, and Matte.
Pros:</p>
<ul>
<li>Mildew resistant</li>
<li>Ideal for kitchens, kids rooms, and dining rooms</li>
<li>Available in 32 designer colors</li>
</ul>
<p>Cons:</p>
<ul>
<li>Has paused some cleaning challenges</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0vHaKWYsVE8">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0vHaKWYsVE8</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>See Also:
Time To Paint a House Interior</p></blockquote>
<h3 id="2-diamond-brite-paint-31600"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B00AENFLMK/?tag=p-policy-20">2. Diamond Brite Paint 31600</a></h3>
<p>As you sample out the different types of interior paints for doors, it is important to settle for one that can give them extra protection from the effects of human fingerprints and other forms of stains.</p>
<p>The Diamond Brite Paint 31600 is just the right paint for such purposes because it is formulated with an extraordinary capacity to protect interior doors and other surfaces against human oils, dirt, and cracking.
This is a professionally manufactured paint that comes with excellent high-hide and stain removal properties. It creates a long-lasting gloss enamel to protect your interior doors and other surfaces against household chemicals, rust, and different forms of abrasion.
Typically, the Diamond Brite Paint dries really hard to enable the surface to withstand high traffic. Such a quality makes it an excellent fit for commercial purposes, especially in industries.
The ideal surfaces for this product include wood, Aluminum, well-bonded wallpaper, stucco, cinder block, brick, drywall, metal, masonry, and plaster.
It has an average dry time of 6-8 hours and can take a recoat after 24 hours. A single gallon covers approximately 300 square feet depending on the method of application.
Pros:</p>
<ul>
<li>Works on many surfaces</li>
<li>High hide and stain removal properties</li>
<li>Dries hard</li>
</ul>
<p>Cons:</p>
<ul>
<li>May emit some odor after application.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4qJd1yA4rTc">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4qJd1yA4rTc</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>See Also:
Interior vs Exterior Paint</p></blockquote>
<h3 id="3-diamond-brite-paint-80000-1-quart-latex"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B00AENH66O/?tag=p-policy-20">3. Diamond Brite Paint 80000 1-Quart Latex</a></h3>
<p>The Diamond Brite Paint 80000 comes with a sure promise to give a bold yet refreshing look to your interior doors, cabinets, furniture, toys, and antique accessories.</p>
<p>It is formulated to give your surfaces a shiny finish that would easily be mistaken for plastic or enamel.
This paint has the full capacity to resist dirt, stain, and human oils in ways that most other paints have failed or performed poorly.
The presence of pets and children in the house means that most surfaces, including doors, will take stains now and then. However, cleaning a door painted by the Diamond Brite Paint 80000 is easy because all you need is water and some soap.
Thankfully, you can easily clean such stains without ever damaging the paint.
If you settled for this product as your paint of choice, ensure to prepare the door carefully before applying. Such preparation involves acts like thorough sanding.
The application is easy since all you need is a brush and
roller
. It is highly resistant to moisture and humid environments.
Pros:</p>
<ul>
<li>Easy to clean</li>
<li>It is a gloss paint</li>
<li>Resists moisture</li>
</ul>
<p>Cons:</p>
<ul>
<li>Needs some bit of preparation (sanding) before you apply it</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>See Also:
Paint Roller Cover for Interior Walls</p></blockquote>
<h3 id="4-rust-oleum-7798502"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0030DB2LK/?tag=p-policy-20">4. Rust-Oleum 7798502</a></h3>
<p>The Rust-Oleum 7798502 is an oil-based formula that gives you a long-lasting coating with a tremendous rust prevention capability.</p>
<p>Being an Oil-based product, it has highly effective corrosion and weather-resistant properties.
This also means that it is perfectly resistant to chipping, fading, and abrasion.
Rust-Oleum paint is the number one rust-preventive product that gives you durable beauty and protection in different colors and finishes. Additionally, it is formulated to give you more coverage and superb color retention.
Sometimes you just want a surface that is shiny but not in the screaming sense. If this is your case, then you have the option of going for a semi-gloss version of the product. This element is crucial, especially when you wouldn&rsquo;t want to over-shine reflective surfaces.
While I recommend Rust-Oleum for interior and exterior doors, it&rsquo;s formulated to apply on plenty more surfaces including masonry, metal, and
concrete
.
One gallon covers approximately 100square feet, and after painting, you can comfortably touch it after two to four hours.
Pros:</p>
<ul>
<li>Perfectly resistant to fading</li>
<li>Comes with a semi-gloss version for a subtle shine</li>
<li>Very durable</li>
</ul>
<p>Cons:</p>
<ul>
<li>Not for sale in some places like the Catalina Island</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>See Also:
White Paints for Interior Walls</p></blockquote>
<h3 id="5-valspar-65004-premium-interior"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0030BKTAC/?tag=p-policy-20">5. Valspar 65004 Premium Interior</a></h3>
<p>If you are looking for some excellent reflection on your interior and exterior doors, then think seriously about going for high gloss paint.</p>
<p>Besides the excellent shine that it creates on the interior surfaces, the higher gloss paint also makes some types of door materials to show their natural beauty.
This exactly what you should expect when you buy Valspar 65004 because it ranks among the most efficient high-gloss finishes. This is due to the ease of application and its super protection abilities.
It is an interior and exterior enamel paint that is formulated to give extraordinary wear resistance. And when dry, its high-gloss finish is not only scrubbable but nontoxic as well.
Since most oil-based paints emit volatile organic compounds, Valspar 65004 is made to dry to touch just after one hour. And once dry, the risk of toxicity is eliminated.
It is scratch resistant.
When applying it, ensure to be in a well-ventilated area and wear the proper personal protective gear because of its high levels of VOCs, s while wet.
Feel confident to use this product on furniture, trim, primed metal, wood and many other craft items
Pros:</p>
<ul>
<li>Dries fast</li>
<li>High gloss finish</li>
<li>Scratch-resistant</li>
</ul>
<p>Cons:</p>
<ul>
<li>May emit some odor while wet.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>See Also:
Paint Sprayer for Interior Walls</p></blockquote>
<h3 id="6-rust-oleum-253611-metallic-accents-paint"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B003EELN1Y/?tag=p-policy-20">6. Rust-Oleum 253611 Metallic Accents Paint</a></h3>
<p>If you are shopping for neat metallic paint to add a special touch to your interior doors, then this is your product. Aside from doors, it also does wonders on furniture, trim, doors, ceilings,
walls
, and more.</p>
<p>It features some real mica beads to give you an excellent shimmering effect, especially when the coated surface is hit by light. With just two coats of this product, you can introduce an amazing touch of luxury, style, and elegance to your interior doors.
Being a water-based formula, it is quite low on odor and volatile organic compounds as well. This means you dont have to wear heavy protective gear when painting.
It is featured with a one-step application that is relatively easy to clean using soap and water. Rust-Oleum 253611 dries to the touch in just thirty minutes, and one gallon covers roughly 105 square feet.
Whats more, it presents in several distinct and conspicuous colors. Although it is associated more with automotive finishes, it will give you magical a 3-D effect when applied on doors.
Pros:</p>
<ul>
<li>Low on Odor and VOCs</li>
<li>It takes 30 minutes to dry to the touch.</li>
<li>Comes in unique colors</li>
<li>Has real mica beads</li>
</ul>
<p>Cons:</p>
<ul>
<li>None</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>See Also:
Oil Based Primer for Cabinets</p></blockquote>
<h3 id="7-kilz-2-multi-surface-stain-blocking"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0013FE5R0/?tag=p-policy-20">7. KILZ 2 Multi-Surface Stain Blocking</a></h3>
<p>If you are expecting the best results after a painting exercise, it is essential to use a sealer. In case your interior doors have earlier paint layers, it will be critical to bringing in a primer so the paint can stick well to the existing layers.</p>
<p>This is one of the best sealers on the market today because it provides high adhesion for both exterior and interior surfaces. It hides previous colors most effectively and has some of the best stain blocking properties.
The KILZ 2 Multi-Surface serves as a perfect glue between the new and old paints as it offers water-tight protection against the light stains that may attempt to percolate through the wet primer.
Some of the stains that this product can block include water staining, ink, grease, felt marker, and more.
Other than doors, it works perfectly on more surfaces including plaster, masonry, drywall, stucco, paneling, brick, and more.
For the best outcomes, it is important to prepare your doors well ahead of time. You can do this by sanding to remove dust and such as impurities before picking the sprayer, roller, or
brush
.
Like most other water-based paints, KILZ 2 dries in a record 30 minutes paving the way for a recoat in less than one hour.
A single gallon covers roughly 300-400 square feet.
Pros:</p>
<ul>
<li>Works well on different surfaces</li>
<li>Dries fast to the touch</li>
<li>Easy to clean</li>
<li>Provides water-tight protection against stains</li>
</ul>
<p>Cons:</p>
<ul>
<li>May not cover completely if not applied according to instructions.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>See Also:
<a href="https://pestpolicy.com/best-primer-for-rusted-metal/">Primer for Rusted Metal</a></p></blockquote>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>This is a non-exhaustive list of the Best Paint for Interior Doors. Keep reading my next blog posts to get more updates on this list.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Door Rack Painter Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/door-rack-painter-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/door-rack-painter-review/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;#39;re looking for an efficient way to paint doors and other vertical surfaces, the Door Rack Painter is a product worth considering. This innovative to...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you&rsquo;re looking for an efficient way to paint doors and other vertical surfaces, the <a href="/posts/best-paint-for-interior-doors/">Door</a> Rack Painter is a product worth considering. This innovative tool helps painters achieve a smooth, even finish without the hassle of handling heavy doors or worrying about drips. In this review, we&rsquo;ll break down the features, pros, cons, and performance of the Door Rack Painter.</p>
<h2 id="features-of-the-door-rack-painter">Features of the Door Rack Painter</h2>
<h3 id="1-adjustable-design">1. Adjustable Design</h3>
<p>The Door Rack Painter comes with an adjustable design that accommodates different door sizes. Whether you&rsquo;re working with standard interior doors or larger exterior doors, this tool can be customized to fit the door securely, making the painting process much easier.</p>
<h3 id="2-360-degree-rotation">2. 360-Degree Rotation</h3>
<p>One of the standout features of the Door Rack Painter is its 360-degree rotation. This allows you to paint every side of the door without having to flip it over or move it around constantly. The rotation feature ensures that you can achieve an even coat of paint, all while keeping the door in place.</p>
<h3 id="3-sturdy-construction">3. Sturdy Construction</h3>
<p>The Door Rack Painter is built with durable materials, ensuring that it can withstand the weight of heavy doors. The sturdy construction also means that it will last for many painting projects without losing its functionality or performance.</p>
<h2 id="how-the-door-rack-painter-performs">How the Door Rack Painter Performs</h2>
<h3 id="1-ease-of-use">1. Ease of Use</h3>
<p>The Door Rack Painter is easy to use, even for those with minimal experience in painting. Its adjustable design allows for quick setup, and the 360-degree rotation helps make the painting process faster and more efficient. Whether you&rsquo;re painting doors, shutters, or other flat surfaces, this tool will save you time and effort.</p>
<h3 id="2-quality-of-finish">2. Quality of Finish</h3>
<p>Using the Door Rack Painter ensures a high-quality finish. The 360-degree rotation feature allows for a consistent application of paint, reducing the chances of streaks or uneven areas. Additionally, since you don&rsquo;t have to handle the door as much, you minimize the risk of accidental smudges or fingerprints on the freshly painted surface.</p>
<h2 id="pros-and-cons">Pros and Cons</h2>
<h3 id="pros">Pros:</h3>
<ul>
<li>Adjustable design fits a wide range of door sizes.</li>
<li>360-degree rotation ensures even painting on all sides.</li>
<li>Durable and sturdy construction for long-term use.</li>
<li>Easy to set up and use, even for beginners.</li>
<li>Reduces the chances of paint drips and uneven finishes.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="cons">Cons:</h3>
<ul>
<li>May be bulky for smaller door sizes.</li>
<li>Requires some space for setup and storage.</li>
<li>May not be suitable for doors with intricate designs or details.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>The Door Rack Painter is an excellent tool for anyone looking to improve the efficiency and quality of their door painting projects. Its adjustable design, 360-degree rotation, and sturdy construction make it an ideal choice for both amateur and professional painters. If you&rsquo;re tired of dealing with drips, uneven finishes, and the hassle of flipping doors over, the Door Rack Painter is worth considering for your next project.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
