<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Monkey on Pest Policy</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/monkey/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Monkey on Pest Policy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/monkey/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How and When to Trim a Monkey Grass Border</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-and-when-to-trim-a-monkey-grass-border/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-and-when-to-trim-a-monkey-grass-border/</guid>
      <description>Monkey grass, often admired for its lush, evergreen foliage and neat clumping or spreading habits, is a staple in many landscape designs. Whether used as a...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="/posts/how-and-when-to-trim-monkey-grass-border/">Monkey</a> grass, often admired for its lush, evergreen foliage and neat clumping or spreading habits, is a staple in many landscape designs. Whether used as a border, groundcover, or accent plant, its low-maintenance nature is a significant draw for gardeners. However, even the most low-maintenance plants benefit from occasional care, and monkey grass is no exception. Trimming, while not a frequent requirement, plays a crucial role in rejuvenating old growth, maintaining a tidy appearance, and promoting healthy new foliage.</p>
<p>Knowing when and how to trim your monkey grass border can make the difference between a tired, ragged edge and a vibrant, well-defined landscape feature. This guide will delve into the different types of monkey grass, the tools you&rsquo;ll need, and the simple steps to effectively trim your borders for optimal health and aesthetics.</p>
<h2 id="types-of-monkey-grass">Types of Monkey Grass</h2>
<p>The term &ldquo;monkey grass&rdquo; is commonly used to refer to two distinct, yet similar, genera of evergreen, grass-like perennials: <em>Liriope</em> and <em>Ophiopogon</em>. While both are popular for similar landscape uses and share a similar common name, they have subtle differences that can influence their growth habit and how you might approach their maintenance.</p>
<h3 id="liriope-liriope-muscari-and-liriope-spicata">Liriope (<em>Liriope muscari</em> and <em>Liriope spicata</em>)</h3>
<p>Often called &ldquo;Lilyturf,&rdquo; <em>Liriope</em> is perhaps the most common plant referred to as monkey grass.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong><em>Liriope muscari</em> (Clumping Liriope):</strong> This species grows in dense clumps and tends to stay where it&rsquo;s planted, making it ideal for neat borders, edgings, or as an accent plant. It typically grows 10-18 inches tall and produces spikes of lavender or white flowers in late summer, followed by black berries. Popular cultivars include &lsquo;Big Blue&rsquo;, &lsquo;Monroe White&rsquo;, and &lsquo;Variegata&rsquo; (which has variegated foliage). Its clumping habit makes it relatively easy to maintain a defined border.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong><em>Liriope spicata</em> (Creeping Liriope):</strong> Also known as &ldquo;Creeping Lilyturf&rdquo; or &ldquo;Creeping Monkey Grass,&rdquo; this variety spreads aggressively by rhizomes, forming a dense groundcover. While excellent for erosion control or filling large areas, its spreading nature means it can become invasive in garden beds if not contained. It generally grows shorter than <em>L. muscari</em>, around 6-12 inches, with less prominent flowers. Due to its aggressive spread, it requires more vigilance to keep its borders in check.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="ophiopogon-ophiopogon-japonicus-and-ophiopogon-planiscapus">Ophiopogon (<em>Ophiopogon japonicus</em> and <em>Ophiopogon planiscapus</em>)</h3>
<p>Known as &ldquo;Mondo Grass,&rdquo; <em>Ophiopogon</em> species are typically smaller and have a finer texture than <em>Liriope</em>.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong><em>Ophiopogon japonicus</em> (Dwarf Mondo Grass):</strong> This is the most common Mondo Grass, growing in very dense, low clumps, typically 4-6 inches tall. It has fine, dark green, almost wire-like foliage. It spreads slowly by rhizomes, forming a very tight groundcover or border. It produces inconspicuous white to pale lavender flowers that are often hidden by the foliage, followed by blue-black berries. Its slow, contained growth makes it ideal for precise, low borders and between stepping stones.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong><em>Ophiopogon planiscapus</em> &lsquo;Nigrescens&rsquo; (Black Mondo Grass):</strong> A striking cultivar of Mondo Grass, famous for its nearly black foliage. It grows similarly to <em>O. japonicus</em> but tends to be slightly taller (up to 8-12 inches) and spreads slowly. It produces pale pinkish-white flowers in summer, followed by black berries, which stand out against its dark leaves. Like other Mondo Grass varieties, it&rsquo;s slow-growing and maintains a neat border easily.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Impact on Trimming:</strong> The primary difference relevant to trimming is their growth habit. Clumping <em>Liriope muscari</em> and all <em>Ophiopogon</em> varieties generally maintain their form better, requiring less frequent and less aggressive trimming. Creeping <em>Liriope spicata</em>, on the other hand, might require more frequent trimming or root pruning to keep its spreading nature in check and prevent it from encroaching on other plants.</p>
<h2 id="tools-for-trimming-monkey-grass">Tools For Trimming Monkey Grass</h2>
<p>The right tools make trimming monkey grass borders easier, more efficient, and result in a cleaner cut that promotes healthier regrowth.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Hedge Shears (Manual or Electric):</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Manual Hedge Shears:</strong> Excellent for smaller borders, precise shaping, and when you want quiet operation. They provide good control but require more physical effort.</li>
<li><strong>Electric/Battery-Powered Hedge Trimmers:</strong> Ideal for longer borders or larger areas. They make quick work of trimming but are less precise for fine details and might be overkill for very small patches. They are best for a uniform, straight cut.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Hand Pruners/Bypass Shears:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Useful for removing individual brown or damaged blades, or for making precise cuts around obstacles. Not practical for trimming entire borders.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>String Trimmer (Weed Eater):</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Can be used for a quick trim of a border, but it&rsquo;s generally less precise than shears and can shred the foliage, leading to ragged edges. If using a string trimmer, ensure it has a sharp line and use a very steady hand. Best for quick rejuvenation cuts rather than precise shaping.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Leaf Rake/Hand Rake:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Essential for raking out old debris and clippings after trimming. A hand rake is particularly useful for getting into the dense clumps.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Garden Gloves:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Always wear sturdy garden gloves to protect your hands from sharp blades and potentially abrasive foliage.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Tarp or Drop Cloth (Optional but Recommended):</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Lay this down alongside your border to catch clippings, making cleanup significantly easier.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Blade Sharpness:</strong> Regardless of the tool, ensure its blades are sharp. Dull blades tear and damage the grass, leaving ragged edges that turn brown and make the plant more susceptible to disease. Sharpen your shears or replace trimmer line regularly.</p>
<h2 id="trimming-monkey-grass">Trimming Monkey Grass</h2>
<p>The timing and technique of trimming monkey grass are crucial for its health and appearance. The goal is typically to remove old, tired, or brown foliage to make way for fresh, green growth.</p>
<h3 id="when-to-trim-monkey-grass">When to Trim Monkey Grass:</h3>
<p>The best time to trim monkey grass is in <strong>late winter or very early spring</strong>, just before new growth begins to emerge.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Late Winter (February - March in most temperate climates):</strong> This timing is ideal because:</p>
<ul>
<li>The grass is dormant or semi-dormant, minimizing stress to the plant.</li>
<li>The old foliage has already served its purpose through winter, protecting the crown.</li>
<li>You remove the old growth before the new, vibrant green blades begin to push through. If you wait until new growth is well underway, you risk cutting off new shoots, which can set the plant back and look unsightly.</li>
<li>This ensures the new season&rsquo;s growth is fresh, uniform, and vigorous.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Avoid Summer Trimming:</strong> Do not trim monkey grass during the active growing season (late spring through fall). Cutting it back during hot weather can stress the plant, lead to browning, and make it more susceptible to disease. The new growth won&rsquo;t have enough time to establish before intense heat or cold.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Exception for Appearance:</strong> If you have an isolated patch of heavily browned or damaged foliage in the summer (e.g., from severe drought or a specific localized issue), you can selectively snip out those individual dead blades with hand pruners, but avoid a widespread cut-back.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="how-to-trim-monkey-grass">How to Trim Monkey Grass:</h3>
<p>The process is straightforward, but consistency is key for a uniform look.</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p><strong>Prepare the Area:</strong> Lay down a tarp or drop cloth along the border to catch clippings. This will save a significant amount of cleanup time.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Determine Your Cut Height:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>For most <em>Liriope</em> varieties, aim to cut back to about <strong>2-4 inches above the ground</strong>. This removes the majority of the old foliage without damaging the crown.</li>
<li>For shorter <em>Ophiopogon</em> (Mondo Grass) varieties, cut back to about <strong>1-2 inches above the ground</strong>. Since they are naturally shorter, a very low cut is fine.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Use the Right Tool:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>For long, straight borders:</strong> Electric or manual hedge shears are the most efficient. Hold the shears parallel to the ground or at a slight angle to create a consistent height. Take small, steady passes.</li>
<li><strong>For curved borders or precision:</strong> Manual hedge shears or even sharp bypass pruners (for very small areas) will give you more control.</li>
<li><strong>For rejuvenation (less precision):</strong> A string trimmer can be used, but be aware it might result in a rougher cut. Keep it moving to avoid shredding.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Cut Uniformly:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Maintain a consistent height across the entire border. Step back periodically to assess your work and make adjustments.</li>
<li>Cut straight across the top. You don&rsquo;t need to shape the sides much, as monkey grass naturally grows in a tidy form.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Clean Up:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Once you&rsquo;ve finished trimming, rake up all the clippings from the border and the surrounding area. Leaving old clippings can smother new growth and potentially encourage fungal issues.</li>
<li>Inspect the border for any missed spots or remaining brown blades and snip them out with hand pruners.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Water and Fertilize (Optional but Recommended):</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>After trimming, a good watering will help new growth emerge.</li>
<li>You can apply a light, balanced fertilizer (e.g., a slow-release granular fertilizer) to encourage vigorous new growth. Follow product instructions carefully.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="what-about-trimming-for-creeping-liriope-liriope-spicata">What About Trimming for Creeping Liriope (<em>Liriope spicata</em>)?</h3>
<p>For <em>Liriope spicata</em>, in addition to the annual cut-back, you might need to address its spreading habit.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Edging:</strong> Install a physical border edge (plastic, metal, or brick) sunk at least 4-6 inches into the ground to contain its rhizomes.</li>
<li><strong>Root Pruning:</strong> If it&rsquo;s spreading beyond its bounds, use a sharp spade to cut through the rhizomes along the desired border edge. This can be done annually or as needed.</li>
<li><strong>Dividing:</strong> Every few years, you may need to dig up and divide overgrown clumps of <em>Liriope spicata</em> to prevent it from taking over.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="trimming-monkey-grass-its-simple">Trimming Monkey Grass: It&rsquo;s Simple</h2>
<p>While &ldquo;simple&rdquo; might seem understated for landscape maintenance, trimming monkey grass truly is one of the more straightforward tasks, primarily due to the plant&rsquo;s resilience and low-fuss nature. The key takeaway is less about complex techniques and more about proper timing and sharp tools.</p>
<p>By consistently cutting back your monkey grass in late winter or early spring, you remove the faded, old foliage, which not only dramatically improves its aesthetic appeal but also provides the impetus for a flush of healthy, vibrant new growth. This annual rejuvenation ensures your monkey grass borders remain dense, lush, and a crisp, attractive feature in your landscape, serving their purpose beautifully year after year with minimal effort. It&rsquo;s a simple step that yields significant rewards for the overall health and visual impact of your garden.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How and When to Trim Monkey Grass Border</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-and-when-to-trim-monkey-grass-border/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-and-when-to-trim-monkey-grass-border/</guid>
      <description>Monkey grass, a common name for plants like Liriope (Liriope muscari) and Mondo Grass (Ophiopogon japonicus), is a popular choice for borders, ground cover...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="/posts/how-and-when-to-trim-a-monkey-grass-border/">Monkey</a> grass, a common name for plants like Liriope (<a href="https://plants.ces.ncsu.edu/plants/liriope-muscari/">Liriope muscari</a>) and Mondo Grass (<a href="https://plants.ces.ncsu.edu/plants/ophiopogon-japonicus/">Ophiopogon japonicus</a>), is a popular choice for borders, ground cover, and accent planting due to its lush, evergreen foliage and low-maintenance nature. While these resilient plants require minimal care, proper trimming at the right time is key to keeping them looking their best, promoting healthy new growth, and preventing them from becoming unruly. Trimming removes old, discolored, or damaged foliage, giving the border a fresh, clean appearance and improving air circulation to prevent disease. This guide will walk you through exactly how and when to trim your monkey grass border for optimal health and aesthetics.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="types-of-monkey-grass">Types of Monkey Grass</h2>
<p>Before diving into trimming, it&rsquo;s helpful to understand the two main types often referred to as &ldquo;monkey grass&rdquo;:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Liriope (Liriope muscari):</strong> Also known as Lilyturf, this is the most common variety. It has wider, strappy leaves, often forms clumps, and produces spikes of purple or white flowers in late summer, followed by black berries. Varieties like &lsquo;Big Blue&rsquo; or &lsquo;Royal Purple&rsquo; are popular.</li>
<li><strong>Mondo Grass (Ophiopogon japonicus):</strong> This typically has finer, darker green, almost grass-like leaves and grows more slowly than liriope. It also produces small white or lavender flowers, often hidden among the foliage, followed by blue-black berries. Dwarf varieties are also available.</li>
</ul>
<p>Both are incredibly versatile and relatively drought-tolerant once established.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="tools-for-trimming-monkey-grass">Tools For Trimming Monkey Grass</h2>
<p>Having the right tools is essential for a clean and efficient trimming job. Ensure all tools are clean and sharp before you begin, as dull blades can tear foliage and invite disease.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>For Small to Medium Borders:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharp Hand Shears:</strong> Ideal for precise cuts on smaller clumps or for shaping.</li>
<li><strong>Hedge Shears:</strong> Both manual and electric hedge shears are excellent for larger sections, providing a quicker, more uniform cut.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>For Large Borders or Ground Cover:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Lawnmower:</strong> A rotary lawnmower is highly effective for extensive areas, allowing you to cover ground quickly. Ensure it&rsquo;s set to its highest cutting height.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Essential Safety &amp; Cleanup:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Gloves and Safety Glasses:</strong> Always recommended to protect your hands and eyes from clippings and debris.</li>
<li><strong>Rake or Leaf Blower:</strong> For efficient cleanup of cut foliage.</li>
<li><strong>Tarp:</strong> Optional, but useful for collecting clippings as you work, making cleanup easier.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h2 id="trimming-monkey-grass">Trimming Monkey Grass</h2>
<p>Proper timing and technique are crucial for maintaining the health and appearance of your monkey grass border.</p>
<h3 id="when-to-trim-monkey-grass">When to Trim Monkey Grass</h3>
<p>Timing is critical for successful monkey grass trimming to avoid damaging new growth and to protect the plant from harsh weather conditions.</p>
<p>The ideal window for trimming monkey grass is in <strong>late winter to early spring</strong>, typically from <strong>February to March</strong> in most temperate climates, or just before new growth begins to emerge.</p>
<p><strong>Why this time is best:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Dormancy:</strong> The plants are still relatively dormant, so you won&rsquo;t be cutting off active new shoots.</li>
<li><strong>Protection:</strong> The old foliage has offered some winter protection against cold and frost.</li>
<li><strong>Easy Cleanup:</strong> The old leaves are often dry and easier to cut and rake away.</li>
<li><strong>Quick Rebound:</strong> The warming temperatures and impending growing season mean the plants will quickly send up new, lush green blades shortly after trimming, covering up the cut stubs.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>When to Avoid Trimming:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Late Spring/Summer:</strong> Avoid trimming once new growth has actively started or during the growing season. You&rsquo;ll be cutting off the very leaves the plant needs for photosynthesis and growth, weakening it.</li>
<li><strong>Fall/Early Winter:</strong> While tempting to tidy up before winter, trimming too late in the year (after early fall) can expose the plant&rsquo;s crown to freezing temperatures and frost damage, as the old foliage provides a layer of insulation.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="how-to-trim-monkey-grass">How to Trim Monkey Grass</h3>
<p>Once you&rsquo;ve chosen the right time and gathered your tools, you&rsquo;re ready to trim. The method you use depends on the size of your border.</p>
<h4 id="manual-shearing-for-precision--smaller-areas">Manual Shearing (For Precision &amp; Smaller Areas)</h4>
<ol>
<li><strong>Clear Debris:</strong> Remove any leaves, sticks, or other debris that may have accumulated in the monkey grass.</li>
<li><strong>Cut Back Foliage:</strong> Using your hand or hedge shears, cut the monkey grass back to approximately <strong>2 to 4 inches from the ground</strong>. Aim for a uniform height across the border. You can collect handfuls of grass and shear them, or just sweep the shears across the top.</li>
<li><strong>Clean Up:</strong> Rake up all the cut foliage. Leftover clippings can smother new growth or harbor pests/diseases.</li>
<li><strong>Optional: Fertilize and Redefine:</strong> Once cleared, you can apply a balanced, slow-release granular fertilizer formulated for ornamental grasses or shrubs. You can also take this opportunity to redefine the edge of your border with a sharp spade or edger for a crisp look.</li>
</ol>
<h4 id="mowing-for-large-areas--efficiency">Mowing (For Large Areas &amp; Efficiency)</h4>
<ol>
<li><strong>Set Mower Height:</strong> Crucially, set your lawnmower to its <strong>highest possible cutting height</strong> (typically 3-4 inches). You want to cut the monkey grass back, but not scalp it.</li>
<li><strong>Ensure Dryness:</strong> It&rsquo;s best to mow when the monkey grass is dry. Wet foliage can clump and clog the mower.</li>
<li><strong>Clear Debris:</strong> Before mowing, clear the area of any large sticks, rocks, or other objects that could be thrown by the mower or damage it.</li>
<li><strong>Mow the Area:</strong> Carefully mow over the monkey grass. Go slowly to ensure an even cut. You might need to make a couple of passes to get all the old foliage.</li>
<li><strong>Clean Up:</strong> Immediately rake or blow away all the clippings.</li>
<li><strong>Optional: Fertilize and Redefine:</strong> As with manual shearing, consider fertilizing lightly and cleaning up the border edges.</li>
</ol>
<hr>
<h2 id="trimming-monkey-grass-its-simple">Trimming Monkey Grass: It&rsquo;s Simple</h2>
<p>Don&rsquo;t let the idea of trimming monkey grass intimidate you. With the right timing and basic tools, it&rsquo;s a straightforward task that offers significant benefits for your plants and landscape. The key is to act in late winter or early spring before new growth kicks in, using sharp tools and cutting back the old foliage to a few inches from the ground.</p>
<p>By following these simple steps, your monkey grass will rebound quickly with fresh, vibrant growth, maintaining that neat, healthy border you desire. Remember these quick tips for ongoing success:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Always use sharp tools.</strong> <a href="https://extension.umd.edu/resource/pruning-trees-and-shrubs">Sharp blades make clean cuts</a> that heal faster and look better.</li>
<li><strong>Never cut too low.</strong> Leave at least 2-4 inches of stubble to protect the plant&rsquo;s crown.</li>
<li><strong>Consider dividing overgrown clumps</strong> during this trimming period. It&rsquo;s an excellent opportunity to <a href="https://hort.extension.wisc.edu/articles/dividing-ornamental-grasses/">rejuvenate and multiply your plants</a>.</li>
<li><strong>Clean up thoroughly</strong> after trimming to prevent new growth from being smothered and to deter pests.</li>
</ul>
<p>With a little annual effort, your monkey grass borders will continue to be a beautiful, low-maintenance feature in your garden for years to come.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lifetime Monkey Bar 9 Foot Wavy Slide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/lifetime-monkey-bar-9-foot-wavy-slide/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/lifetime-monkey-bar-9-foot-wavy-slide/</guid>
      <description>Let your children have fun and enjoy your cool backyard with the Lifetime Monkey Bar swing set with a 9 Foot Wavy Slide.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Let your children have fun and enjoy your cool backyard with the Lifetime Monkey Bar swing set with a 9 Foot Wavy Slide.
The swing set is favorable or kids between ages 3 to 12. Read Also:
Compression Socks For Standing All Day
.</p>
<h2 id="lifetime-monkey-bar---9-foot-wavy-slide">Lifetime Monkey Bar - 9 Foot Wavy Slide</h2>
<p>The metal swing set will be safer as compared to the wooden options, as the kids will not get cuts from wood chips. Read Also:
Stain For Cedar Swing Set
.
The heavy-duty swing set has belt swings and trapeze bar having gym rings. Also, do not worry about your kids pinching their fingers as the Monkey Bar swing set comes with rubber grips on the swings.
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TZABHu81Yfo">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TZABHu81Yfo</a>
Also, the swings are securely secured using the chain clips at the top of the frame. You kids will love the monkey bars as they will allow have an unending adventure.
The swing set has passed the safety standard requirements. Therefore, the set lacks any hard edges and its chains are covered and rounded to avoid pinching or scratching.
Further, the swing set is UV-protected and thus you dont have to worry about fading, staining, or losing color. Read Also:
<a href="https://pestpolicy.com/best-%5Bswing-sets%5D(/posts/best-baby-swings-for-sleeping/)-for-small-backyards/">Swing Sets for Small Backyards</a>
.
Due to the high-density polyethylene and galvanized steel construction, the Lifetime <a href="/posts/how-and-when-to-trim-a-monkey-grass-border/">Monkey</a> Bar swing set is resistant from heat and is smooth.�Since the swings set frame is constructed from heavy-duty gauge steel, you dont have to worry about it losing its shape and design over time.
Read Also:
<a href="https://pestpolicy.com/best-tree-swing/">Tree Swings Reviews</a>
Also, the set has strong support bases that will allow easy installation and will not require cement or the process. Therefore, you can easily move the swing set later to another location.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
