<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Ned on Pest Policy</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/ned/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ned on Pest Policy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/ned/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ned Stevens Gutter Cleaning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ned-stevens-gutter-cleaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ned-stevens-gutter-cleaning/</guid>
      <description>Ned Stevens Gutter Cleaning has been a prominent name in the home maintenance industry for decades, specifically known for its focus on gutter care. Founde...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ned Stevens Gutter Cleaning has been a prominent name in the home maintenance industry for decades, specifically known for its focus on gutter care. Founded in 1965, the company has grown to offer a wide array of exterior home services, building a reputation for professional, guaranteed work. For homeowners seeking a reliable and hands-off approach to gutter maintenance, Ned Stevens often comes up as a leading option.</p>
<p>This article provides an in-depth look at Ned Stevens Gutter Cleaning, covering their services, pricing approach, service area, and ultimately, whether their offerings represent a worthwhile investment for your home.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="our-take-on-ned-stevens-gutter-cleaning">Our Take on Ned Stevens Gutter Cleaning</h2>
<p>Ned Stevens Gutter Cleaning stands out as a highly specialized and established provider in the gutter maintenance sector. Unlike many general home service companies that offer gutter cleaning as one of many services, Ned Stevens has made gutters their core expertise. This specialization means their crews are typically well-versed in diagnosing and addressing a range of gutter issues, not just clogs.</p>
<p>Their emphasis on <strong>service plans</strong> is a defining feature, designed to provide year-round, proactive gutter maintenance rather than one-off cleanings. This approach can significantly reduce the risk of major clogs and associated water damage by ensuring gutters are regularly inspected and cleared. While their pricing structure isn&rsquo;t transparently listed online, this is common for customized home services.</p>
<p>Customer reviews often highlight their professionalism, responsiveness, and the convenience of not needing to be home for service appointments. However, some common complaints revolve around aggressive marketing tactics post-service and, occasionally, higher pricing compared to smaller, local competitors.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="pros-and-cons-of-ned-stevens-gutter-cleaning">Pros and Cons of Ned Stevens Gutter Cleaning</h2>
<h3 id="pros">Pros:</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Specialized Expertise:</strong> Being gutter specialists, their crews are highly trained in gutter cleaning, repair, and installation. This depth of knowledge can be invaluable for complex or recurring issues.</li>
<li><strong>Comprehensive Service Plans:</strong> Their subscription-based service plans (Diamond, Platinum Plus, Platinum) ensure regular, scheduled cleanings throughout the year, preventing major clogs and offering peace of mind.</li>
<li><strong>Guaranteed Service:</strong> Ned Stevens offers a 100% satisfaction guarantee on their services, ensuring gutters are cleaned and free-flowing through the next rainstorm. They are fully insured, and their technicians are direct employees, not subcontractors.</li>
<li><strong>Convenience:</strong> Homeowners typically do not need to be present for service appointments, which is a major convenience for busy schedules. They often provide same-day or next-day emergency services for plan members.</li>
<li><strong>Additional Benefits for Plan Members:</strong> Service plans often include perks like free re-nailing of loose gutters/leaders, priority scheduling during peak seasons, and discounts on other services (e.g., power washing, new gutter installations).</li>
<li><strong>Wide Range of Services:</strong> While specializing in gutters, they offer a broad suite of complementary home exterior services.</li>
<li><strong>Established Reputation:</strong> With over 50 years in business, they have a long track record and an A+ rating with the Better Business Bureau in many locations.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="cons">Cons:</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Higher Cost:</strong> Compared to some local, independent cleaners, Ned Stevens can be on the higher end of the price spectrum, particularly for single, one-off cleanings.</li>
<li><strong>No Gutter Guards Offered:</strong> Notably, Ned Stevens explicitly states they do not recommend or sell gutter guards, believing regular cleaning is the most effective solution. This might be a downside for homeowners looking for a low-maintenance solution that includes gutter guards.</li>
<li><strong>Sales/Marketing Intensity:</strong> Some past customers report aggressive follow-up calls or marketing attempts after using their services or declining plans.</li>
<li><strong>Occasional Service Issues:</strong> While many reviews are positive, some customers have reported issues such as missed debris, communication problems, or scheduling difficulties, though the company appears to have mechanisms for addressing these.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h2 id="what-services-does-ned-stevens-offer">What Services Does Ned Stevens Offer?</h2>
<p>Ned Stevens has expanded its offerings significantly beyond just gutter cleaning. Their services fall into several key categories:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Gutter Services:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Gutter Cleaning:</strong> Their flagship service, which involves removing all debris (leaves, twigs, shingle grit) from gutters and ensuring downspouts are clear.</li>
<li><strong>Gutter Installation:</strong> Replacement of old gutter systems with new ones, often offering various materials and colors.</li>
<li><strong>Gutter Repair:</strong> Addressing leaks, sagging, loose hangers, and other damage to existing gutters.</li>
<li><strong>Ice Dam Removal:</strong> Professional removal of ice buildup that can damage gutters and roofs.</li>
<li><strong>Underground Drain Snaking:</strong> Clearing clogs in underground drainage systems connected to downspouts.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Exterior Home Cleaning:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Power Washing:</strong> Cleaning of siding, decks, patios, walkways, and fences.</li>
<li><strong>Roof Cleaning:</strong> Removal of moss, algae, and stains from roofs to extend their lifespan.</li>
<li><strong>Window Cleaning:</strong> Professional cleaning for sparkling windows.</li>
<li><strong>Siding Cleaning:</strong> Thorough cleaning to remove dirt, grime, and mold.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Pest Control:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Mosquito and Tick Control:</strong> Seasonal treatments to reduce pest populations.</li>
<li><strong>General Pest Control:</strong> Addressing common household pests.</li>
<li><strong>Wildlife Removal:</strong> Humane removal of unwanted wildlife.</li>
<li><strong>Termite Prevention/Control.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Rodent Control.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Bee Removal.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Lawn Care:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Residential and Commercial Lawn Treatment.</li>
<li>Lawn Aeration &amp; Seeding.</li>
<li>Lawn Disease Control.</li>
<li>Tree &amp; Shrub Care.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Other Home Services:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Dryer Vent Cleaning.</li>
<li>Chimney Cap Installation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
<p>Their emphasis is on providing a comprehensive &ldquo;Ned&rsquo;s Home&rdquo; solution for exterior maintenance, allowing homeowners to consolidate various services with one provider.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="ned-stevens-general-contracting-services">Ned Stevens General Contracting Services</h2>
<p>While Ned Stevens is primarily known for its extensive range of home exterior maintenance services, including gutter work, pest control, and landscaping, their official entity sometimes includes &ldquo;General Contracting&rdquo; in its registered name (e.g., &ldquo;Ned Stevens Gutter Cleaning &amp; General Contracting&rdquo;).</p>
<p>However, it&rsquo;s important to clarify that this does not typically mean they act as full-scale general contractors for large-scale home renovations or construction projects (like building additions, kitchen remodels, or major structural work). Instead, their &ldquo;general contracting&rdquo; aspect usually refers to their ability to manage and perform the various, interconnected exterior maintenance and repair services they offer, such as gutter installation, substantial gutter repairs, fascia board repair associated with gutter work, and other related exterior improvements that fall within their specialized service categories. Essentially, they are &ldquo;general contractors&rdquo; for exterior home maintenance rather than broad construction.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="how-much-does-ned-stevens-gutter-cleaning-cost">How Much Does Ned Stevens Gutter Cleaning Cost?</h2>
<p>Ned Stevens does not publish specific pricing for individual gutter cleanings or their service plans online. This is customary for many home service providers who provide customized quotes based on specific property factors.</p>
<p>However, based on customer experiences and industry averages, here&rsquo;s what to expect:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Single Gutter Cleaning:</strong> A one-time cleaning typically ranges from <strong>$120 to $250</strong>, but can be higher for larger homes or those with significant debris.</li>
<li><strong>Service Plans:</strong> These are designed for regular, scheduled cleanings throughout the year (e.g., 4, 5, or 6 cleanings per year). While the upfront cost for a year-long plan might seem higher than a single cleaning, the per-cleaning cost is often reduced, and the plan includes valuable benefits like priority service, free minor repairs (re-nailing, re-attaching leaders), and discounts on other services. You often pay for these plans upfront.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Factors Influencing Cost:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Size of Home:</strong> Larger homes with more linear feet of gutters will cost more.</li>
<li><strong>Number of Stories:</strong> Multi-story homes require more specialized equipment and safety measures, increasing labor costs.</li>
<li><strong>Amount of Debris:</strong> Heavily clogged gutters with significant build-up will take longer to clean.</li>
<li><strong>Type of Debris:</strong> Pine needles, seeds, and shingle grit can be more challenging to remove than large leaves.</li>
<li><strong>Accessibility:</strong> Difficult-to-reach gutters or complex rooflines can increase labor time and cost.</li>
<li><strong>Location:</strong> Pricing can vary based on regional labor costs and local market demand.</li>
</ul>
<p>To get an accurate quote, you need to contact Ned Stevens directly for a free estimate.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="what-is-ned-stevens-service-area-and-availability">What Is Ned Stevens&rsquo; Service Area and Availability?</h2>
<p>Ned Stevens Gutter Cleaning operates across a significant portion of the Eastern and Midwestern United States. They have a strong presence in states such as:</p>
<ul>
<li>Connecticut</li>
<li>Delaware</li>
<li>Georgia</li>
<li>Illinois</li>
<li>Maine</li>
<li>Maryland</li>
<li>Massachusetts</li>
<li>New Jersey</li>
<li>New York (especially Long Island)</li>
<li>North Carolina</li>
<li>Pennsylvania</li>
<li>Rhode Island</li>
<li>South Carolina</li>
</ul>
<p>Their service is typically available seven days a week, with office hours generally from 6 AM to 8 PM Monday through Thursday, and slightly reduced hours on weekends. They are known for offering quick scheduling, including same-day or next-day emergency service for plan customers, weather permitting.</p>
<p>To confirm if they serve your specific address, it&rsquo;s best to visit their website and use their location finder or contact their customer service line directly.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="is-ned-stevens-gutter-cleaning-worth-it">Is Ned Stevens Gutter Cleaning Worth It?</h2>
<p>For many homeowners, <strong>Ned Stevens Gutter Cleaning is indeed worth the investment</strong>, especially if:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>You prioritize convenience and safety:</strong> Avoiding hazardous ladder work and relying on professionals saves time and prevents potential injuries.</li>
<li><strong>You have a large or multi-story home:</strong> These types of properties are more challenging and dangerous for DIY cleaning.</li>
<li><strong>You live in an area with heavy tree coverage:</strong> Frequent debris means frequent clogs, making a regular service plan highly beneficial.</li>
<li><strong>You want proactive maintenance:</strong> Their service plans ensure your gutters are cleaned regularly, significantly reducing the risk of costly water damage to your foundation, siding, and landscaping.</li>
<li><strong>You value guarantees and professional handling:</strong> Their 100% guarantee and use of insured employees provide peace of mind.</li>
<li><strong>You appreciate a single provider for multiple exterior needs:</strong> If you also need power washing, roof cleaning, or pest control, bundling services can be efficient.</li>
</ul>
<p>While the upfront cost for their plans might be higher than a single DIY cleaning or a very cheap local service, the long-term benefits of preventative maintenance, reduced risk of water damage, and conserved personal time and effort often justify the expense. For those who do not wish to deal with gutter maintenance at all, Ned Stevens offers a comprehensive and reliable solution. However, if cost is your absolute primary concern and your home has minimal trees or a simple layout, exploring local, independent cleaners might offer a more budget-friendly, albeit potentially less comprehensive, alternative.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
