<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Kitchen on Pest Policy</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/kitchen/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kitchen on Pest Policy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/kitchen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Best Bonding Primer for Kitchen Cabinets</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/best-bonding-primer-for-kitchen-cabinets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/best-bonding-primer-for-kitchen-cabinets/</guid>
      <description>For most DIY painters, purchasing the best bonding primer for kitchen cabinets is a challenging task.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For most DIY painters, purchasing the best bonding primer for <a href="/posts/best-primer-for-kitchen-cabinets/">kitchen</a> cabinets is a challenging task.</p>
<p>There are many brands and varieties of kitchen cabinet primers allowing excellent home improvement.
As a sidenote, oil-based primers will work great for oak cabinets since they&rsquo;ll quickly fill the grain compared to your regular primers.
See Also: Check these
stains for swings sets
.</p>
<h2 id="s-7-best-bonding-primer-for-kitchen-cabinets-2025">s: 7 Best Bonding Primer for Kitchen Cabinets 2025</h2>
<h3 id="1-kilz-restoration-primer-maximum-odor-and-stain-blocking"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B007XH9PKO/?tag=p-policy-20">1. KILZ Restoration Primer Maximum Odor and Stain Blocking</a></h3>
<p>KILZ Restoration Primer is an effective odor and stain blocker, sealer, and water-base primer that&rsquo;ll work just like shellac- and oil-based products.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;ll easily handle tough stains, including tannin, grease, nicotine, smoke, rust, and water damage. INSL-X Prime Lock is an excellent primer since its resin-based plus a
wood sealer
preventing bleeding.
KILZ Restoration Primer worked excellently under the carpet when the cat urinated to the fabric. This primer is excellent for glass, ceramic tile, painted metal, brick, masonry, plaster, and woodwork.
The prime creates an excellent seal on different porous surfaces allowing better <a href="/posts/best-chalk-paint-for-kitchen-cabinets/">paint</a> application. Further, you may top-coat the primer using oil-base or latest paint.
It offers excellent coverage at nearly 300-400 sqFt. For each gallon. Apply the primer on well-prepared surfaces devoid of peeling paint, rust,
mold (check mold preventing stains)
, chalk, grease, and dust.
KILZ Restoration Primer will also effectively cover any of your past works of art. They&rsquo;ll block the various graffiti, felt pen, crayon, and permanent marker - an alternative for
spray paints for graffiti
.
Pros:</p>
<ul>
<li>The primer may be applied usingsprayers, rollers, and brushes.</li>
<li>Further, it&rsquo;ll dry quickly in just 30 minutes to touch, and it allows recoating within 1 hour.</li>
<li>The bonding primer tackles the different water stains, including severe and heavy ones.</li>
<li>Ensure to dry the surface thoroughly before applying the primer and avoid using it on active leaks.</li>
</ul>
<p>Cons:</p>
<ul>
<li>None found</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dG9kY0KOb8M">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dG9kY0KOb8M</a>
See Also:
Acrylic Paint for Professional Artists</p>
<h3 id="2-insl-x-ps800009a-01-bonding-prime-lock-plus-alkyd-primer"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07KXP4C4M/?tag=p-policy-20">2. INSL-X PS800009A-01 Bonding Prime Lock-Plus Alkyd Primer</a></h3>
<p>INSL-X PS800009A-01 is a stain blocker, sealer, and bonding primer that I would term as alkyd-based and high hiding suitable for interior projects - particularly with the kitchen cabinets.</p>
<p>The primer is suitable for wood, drywall, and plaster that had been varnished and painted. But you may also top-coat the surfaces using
latex paint ( with these sprayers)
or oil paint.
The primer gives a great enamel holdout with excellent adhesion and doesn&rsquo;t raise the surface&rsquo;s wood grain. It&rsquo;s suitable for sealing charred or burned wood.
It allows you to lock different stains from grease and food. Consider too this
acrylic aerosol
. It offers excellent adhesion on surfaces such as tiles, PVC, marlite, tile,
bricks
, Formica, and glossy paint.
The
Alkyd-based primer is multi-purpose and fast-drying too (within 1 hour) that&rsquo;ll both prime and seal different stains and substrates. It&rsquo;ll fill the colors from smoke and water damage.
Pros:</p>
<ul>
<li>This bonding primer effectively renovates different old oak vanities.</li>
<li>The INSL-X PS800009A-01 primer offers excellent coverage (about300 - 350 sq. ft. for every gallon).</li>
<li>Take caution not to apply the primer at under7.2 C (45 F).</li>
</ul>
<p>Cons:</p>
<ul>
<li>No spray gun recommended</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4NFrDUTEB5g">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4NFrDUTEB5g</a></p>
<h3 id="3-zinsser-b-i-n-bonding-shellac-base-primer"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B000C02C68/?tag=p-policy-20">3. Zinsser B-I-N Bonding Shellac-Base Primer</a></h3>
<p>Zinsser B-I-N Bonding is an excellent house-primer and
stain sealer
that&rsquo;ll effectively paint your kitchen cabinets, including
spot exterior nor interior application.</p>
<p>Zinsser B-I-N Bonding is effective for use in removing
musty odors, smoke, and seals pet. Luckily, the bonding primer will stick on
different surfaces with no sanding required.
On consistency, the primer is milk-thin, and thus it&rsquo;ll easily spray over your kitchen cabinets but may cause splatter with
rolling (even for textured walls
) or brushing.
For sanded and cleaning cabinet surfaces, the primer will easily layout and nice. While you&rsquo;re spraying the door horizontally, this primer creates a grainy oak with excellent seepage into the cracks.
The kitchen cabinet primer is also great as a wood sealer with a faster drying time. Within an hour, you can sand lightly and thus go-ahead to the second coating.
I must note that this primer is among my top-recommended products in its class for painting varnished or stained trim and wood, including doors, spindles, stair risers, baseboards, and casings.
Pros:</p>
<ul>
<li>Quick-drying bonding primer</li>
<li>Cleaning is your sprayer after priming is comfortable with just denatured alcohol or ammonia.</li>
<li>Finally, the bonding primer is budget-friendly and hence will work great (price-wise) for your kitchen cabinets.</li>
</ul>
<p>Cons:</p>
<ul>
<li>None</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="4-zinsser-03504-oil-primer-sealer-cover-stain-interior"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B000BZX6B4/?tag=p-policy-20">4. Zinsser 03504 Oil-Primer Sealer/ Cover Stain Interior</a></h3>
<p>Zinsser 03504 is an oil-based bond coat, primer, or cover stain for your kitchen cabinets. Buy this one is budget-friendly, but you may require to use a respirator and gloves for rolling and spraying.</p>
<p>Comparatively, Zinsser 03504 is thicker compared to shellac, and thus you&rsquo;ll require to apply a lighter coat to prevent heavy texturing that would demand surface sanding.
While using an
airless sprayer
, the primer will give you a fine spray. But you can use spray tip that&rsquo;s sized about 0.015 - 0.017 to get a better-atomized spray and hence reduce fingering during spraying.
This Zinsser 03504 is also an o
il-based sealer, primer, or stain killer that&rsquo;ll give your kitchen cabinets that fantastic shine. When used on
exteriors, the primer allows for incredible
flexibility and full penetration.
Zinsser 03504 won&rsquo;t level excellently compared to the shellac-based primers. However, for rolling and brushing, you&rsquo;ll have longer drying time.
The bonding primer will generate a suitable
enamel undercoating while also drying quickly for the interior surfaces. I love this one for
priming, repainting, remodeling, and new constructions.
Pros:</p>
<ul>
<li>The product is excellent in hiding various formal blocks caused bynicotine stains and smoke while also sealing water.</li>
<li>Further, it&rsquo;ll sand easily and stick evenly onto the exterior and interior surfaces.</li>
</ul>
<p>Cons:</p>
<ul>
<li>Slower drying co0maprd to shellac primer</li>
</ul>
<p>See Also:
Spray Paints for Plastic</p>
<h2 id="considerations-in-best-bonding-primer-for-kitchen-cabinets">Considerations in Best Bonding Primer for Kitchen Cabinets</h2>
<h3 id="1-stain-blocking-primer">1. Stain-blocking Primer</h3>
<p>The primer types will block stain that would tend to bleed through your paint on your furniture and kitchen cabinets. The leaking can happen on water stains and water rings for dressers and tabletops.
Further, the stain-blocking primer will work well for bare or unfinished wood, including on furniture such as cabinets doors that could have noticeable knots.</p>
<h3 id="2-oil-based-primers">2. Oil-Based Primers</h3>
<p>Next is the oil-based primers that&rsquo;ll have more pungent odor compared to the stain-blocking primers. Therefore, you must avoid these primers when you&rsquo;re painting on rooms with closed windows.
Further, the oil-based primers will be challenging to clean up, and thus you&rsquo;ll require using
paint thinners
or mineral spirits. One of the excellent oil-based furniture primers is the Zinsser Cover Stain.</p>
<h3 id="3-shellac-based-primer">3. Shellac-Based Primer</h3>
<p>These shellac-based primers will excellent cover various types of odors and stains, leaving a transparent and white surface on your kitchen surfaces.
But this model won&rsquo;t be as stinky like your oil-based primers, and thus it&rsquo;ll be simple to clean with just denatured alcohol and some water mixed.
This clear shellac primer will be great for priming you&rsquo;re furniture, particularly for bleeding wood. Finally, sanding the wood will allow the wood to reveal.
See Also:
<a href="https://pestpolicy.com/best-clear-coat-for-snowboard/">Clear Coat for Snowboard</a>
.</p>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>Tried the best bonding primer for kitchen cabinets? The primers will also be great for cupboards or other furniture created from knotty pine, cedar, mahogany, or cherry. These are the wood types that&rsquo;ll allow the paint to bleed through.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Chalk Paint for Kitchen Cabinets</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/best-chalk-paint-for-kitchen-cabinets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/best-chalk-paint-for-kitchen-cabinets/</guid>
      <description>With any of the best chalk paint for kitchen cabinets and the right tool, you can quickly revive the beauty of the kitchen cabinets</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With any of the best chalk paint for <a href="/posts/best-bonding-primer-for-kitchen-cabinets/">kitchen</a> cabinets and the right tool, you can quickly revive the beauty of the kitchen cabinets
<a href="https://www.familyhandyman.com/kitchen/diy-kitchen-cabinets/surprising-tips-for-painting-kitchen-cabinets/">by painting them</a>
.</p>
<p>Luckily, <a href="/posts/best-chalk-paint-for-furniture/">chalk</a> paints are thick but will also dry quickly, and thus you can add another coating immediately.
I noted that one could adequately cover all the flaws or holes like oak grains using about three coats - but you may require to sand lightly using some 600 grit dry or wet sandpaper.</p>
<h2 id="s-7-best-chalk-paint-forkitchen-cabinets-2025">s: 7 Best Chalk Paint forKitchen Cabinets 2025</h2>
<p>Unlike the
oil-based and latex paint
, chalk paint may require limited furniture and ends up giving the furniture items vintage or rustic appearance.</p>
<h3 id="1-rust-oleum-285144-ultra-matte-chalk-paint-for-indoors"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B00YSK2MVI/?tag=p-policy-20">1. Rust-Oleum 285144 Ultra-Matte Chalk Paint for Indoors</a></h3>
<p>Rust-Oleum 285144 will give your kitchen cabinets a sheen finish with low VOC and limited odour. It offers 150+ square-feet coverage on
canvas
, glass, ceramic, metal, and wood for some
vintage look.</p>
<p>Rust-Oleum 285144 is approved for just interior use, and you&rsquo;ll simply need to clean up the surfaces of your kitchen cabinets using water and soap.
The
latex and low-odour paint are natural to clean with just water and soap. The
1-coat coverage will also be quick-drying bein today for touching in only 0.5 hours.
So, if you&rsquo;re considering furniture and interior painting, you can choose from colours ranges with your chalk paint with
cabinets paint sprayers
.
Rust-Oleum 285144 requires
minimal preparation and has an easy and quick application process to give a
smooth and ultra-matte velvety surface finish.
The chalk paint is also an automotive component-approved for excellent &lsquo;Transformations&rsquo;. With a single coat, you&rsquo;ll get 150 feet+ surface coverage.
The paints will come out like a deeper matte compared to what you get with Annie Sloan or Renaissance - and it&rsquo;s the suitable
spray can
.
Rust-Oleum 285144 offers great coverage plus its a thin-consistency chalk paint that&rsquo;ll be suitable for your kitchen cabinets leading to saying in effort and time needed.
Finally, this paint is quick-drying plus odour-free, and thus it&rsquo;ll be great for your kitchen with a deep-matte finish at some relatively low budget price and excellent coverage.
Pros:</p>
<ul>
<li>Thin consistency but excellent coverage for the chalk paint</li>
<li>Budget-friendly model</li>
<li>The latex cabinet paint is suitable for most furniture and other material like ceramic.</li>
<li>Rust-Oleum 285144 has some thin consistency, and thus you can utilize aspray gunwith excellent coverage.</li>
<li>Great for noob and profesioanl DIYers</li>
<li>Excellent surface adherence plus quick-drying to give some soft-matte finish</li>
</ul>
<p>Cons:</p>
<ul>
<li>Requires surface priming</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-HoyYjvEoE8">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-HoyYjvEoE8</a></p>
<p>See Also:
Pressure Washer for Paint Removal</p>
<h3 id="2-spruce-besthome-from-kilz-14604-chalk-cabinet-paint"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07QC4KGFT/?tag=p-policy-20">2. Spruce BestHome from KILZ 14604 Chalk Cabinet Paint</a></h3>
<p>Spruce Best-home offers excellent colour
Selection as top chalk paint for kitchen cabinets. Also, the
dusty blue paint will
refurbish your tables, old dresser,
upcycling furniture,
or dining room chairs.</p>
<p>Spruce Best-home is suitable for painting
wicker, metal, glass, concrete, cast stone, and wood. It produces an
antique outlook that&rsquo;s also very durable after drying.
Spruce Best-home has a concentrated formula that&rsquo;ll easily over the surfaces (only one coat) to give the cabinets some beautiful finish. However, you may thin the paint using water.
For example, I found the brand&rsquo;s &ldquo;warm linen&rdquo; shade that pretty being more yellow-toned but with a shape of white tone. It&rsquo;s great for painting the old table, kitchen hutch, and dressers.
However, it might require some thin primer and will give the cabinets a good cover if you apply a second coat. But you may still need to spot-treat any areas for better paint coverage.
Spruce Best-home will make the texture of your kitchen cannet&rsquo;s wood beautiful and shiny mainly if you use some fine-grit sandpaper for a weathered and rustic finish.
The beautiful cabinet paint holds up for long even on camper cabinets producing a wax topcoat that&rsquo;s adequately clear and clean.
Excellent chalk paint even for refurbishing the finish of your large mirror either in the bedroom or in your dining room. The chalk paint will also get a perfect &lsquo;pop&rsquo; on your hallway doors.
Pros:</p>
<ul>
<li>On the colour range, these paints for your kitchen cabinets come in deep blues and anything towards soft neutrals.</li>
<li>Everyquart will cover about 60 sq. Ft. to 100 sq. Ft. of your kitchen cabinets.</li>
<li>It&rsquo;s also quick-drying since you can recoat within 2 hours while it&rsquo;ll be dry to touch within only 1 hour.</li>
<li>However, you can get a smooth feel and protect the paint using the Clear Sealing Wax.</li>
</ul>
<p>Cons:</p>
<ul>
<li>None</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0vHaKWYsVE8">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0vHaKWYsVE8</a></p>
<h3 id="3-retique-furniture-chalk-eco-friendly-kitchen-cabinet-paint"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B075WYGJ51/?tag=p-policy-20">3. Retique Furniture Chalk Eco-Friendly Kitchen Cabinet Paint</a></h3>
<p>Retique Furniture Paint also offers great coverage in 1-2 coatings and required no proming or sanding for application. Its a less known chalk paint, but has a range of 40 colors with good coverage.</p>
<p>This model is a little thicker with great adherence and hence needs no priming or sanding. You&rsquo;ll have a smooth and chalky coating to get a finish considered as shabby-chic.
Retique Furniture Paint is made by a company offering an extensive colour palette for the cabinet chalk paints. Retique Furniture Paint has ultra-low VOC with excellent finish quality.
However, this paint model won&rsquo;t work well with your spray gun but will be applied with a brush or
roller (particularly for textured walls)
, and you may dilute to avoid clumping.
Besides, due to having some thick consistency, Retique Furniture Paint will cover less surface compared to other best chalk paints for kitchen cabinets and various furniture.
With just some simple standing, this paint model will produce an excellent finish, something I would consider silky smooth. The cabinets, despite being wear-prone, will thus need less maintenance.
You&rsquo;ll love that Retique Furniture Paint is budget-friendly, has ultra-low VOC, and comes in an excellent color palette with great paint quality.
Pros:</p>
<ul>
<li>Great surface adherence with limited priming</li>
<li>Has ultra-kiw paint VOC</li>
<li>Comes in a variety of can or container sizes</li>
<li>Offers broad level of color palette</li>
</ul>
<p>Cons:</p>
<ul>
<li>Limited coverage due to thickness.</li>
</ul>
<p>See Also:
Concrete Rust Remover</p>
<h3 id="4-folkart-furniture-decor-chalk-craft-and-furniture-paint"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B00RGFXSGU/?tag=p-policy-20">4. FolkArt Furniture Decor Chalk Craft and Furniture Paint</a></h3>
<p>FolkArt Furniture Decor produced by Arts &amp; Crafts is a wonderful chalk paint that&rsquo;ll amazizingly pimp your kitchen cabinets. The paint is top on the quality chart for an excellent finish.</p>
<p>FolkArt Furniture Decor comes in a smaller bottle but it&rsquo;s also budget-friendly and an elaborate color palette (42 colors) with excellent quality.
The chalk paint is relatively thick (more drying time) creating some excellent deep-matte finish and requiring no priming and it&rsquo;s thus comparable to the Rustoleum model.
Due to the larger thickness, the FolkArt Furniture Decor will thus take some longer drying time. Therefore,m the second coating might require waiting before getting to it.
FolkArt is loved by homeowners or DIYers who like their chalk paint coming in small cans. Luckily, the small size will be implemented by the high quality of this great paint brand.
Pros:</p>
<ul>
<li>Great adherence due to its comparatively thick nature</li>
<li>Offers non-toxic finish - its also deep matte</li>
<li>Excellent color palette - about 42 colors m</li>
<li>Great price for the excellent quality</li>
<li>The containers or cans are small-sized and hence awesome for small furniture</li>
</ul>
<p>Cons:</p>
<ul>
<li>Lower coverage - about 20 sq. feet per can</li>
<li>Longer time of cabinet paint drying</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="5-kilz-00003904-indoor-chalk--decorative-paint"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07CPPFBK8/?tag=p-policy-20">5. KILZ 00003904 Indoor Chalk &amp; Decorative Paint</a></h3>
<p>KILZ 00003904 Indoor is the
ultra-matte kind of finish paint that&rsquo;s considered a Decorative model that&rsquo;s suitable for interior paijing like kcthen cabinets or upcycling furniture.</p>
<p>KILZ 00003904 require limited preparation before applying this chalk paint. It offers
coverage but also thick
it&rsquo;ll easily while incorporating character yto your cabinet surfaces.
To clean, simply use regular water plus soap to wipe off the dirt just like it&rsquo;s also simple to apply the fantastic paint on various surfaces including metal,
concrete, cast stone, and wood.
The ultra-flat KILZ 00003904 chalk paint is described as decorative and is recommended for your small DIY painting that requires small paint quantities.
You can choose from a variety of chalk paint colours available including Red Flare, Authentic Navy, Basic Teal, Swedish Blue, Toasted Poppyseed, or Smokey Eyes e.t.c.
You can seal the surface using KILZ Wax after the chalk paint dries up - use a clean rag or brush. This will give the painted surface a beautiful and inviting vintage outlook.
You can refresh the look of your kitchen cabinets or other furniture. After waxing the surface, you may sand (using a 200- to 220-grit sandpaper) the item&rsquo;s edges to achieve the rustic outlook.
You can use this chalk paint on various items like mason jars, wicker baskets, clay pots, mirror frames, and paint pictures. Use water to thin the chalk paint to achieve the required consistency.
Pros:</p>
<ul>
<li>KILZ 00003904 has a thick consistency and cover large surface area (100 sq. ft. for each quart).</li>
<li>As noted earlier, the chalk paint won&rsquo;t require priming both on metal, concrete, cast stone, and wood.</li>
<li>It&rsquo;ll give the ultra-matte finish on your kitchen cabinets and other furniture pieces.</li>
<li>There&rsquo;s also colour variety including platinum ring, International grey, Chalk grey, and Cameo Coral.</li>
</ul>
<p>Cons:</p>
<ul>
<li>None</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="considerations-in-best-chalk-paint-for-kitchen-cabinets">Considerations in Best Chalk Paint for Kitchen Cabinets</h2>
<h3 id="1-drying-time-and-finish">1. Drying Time and Finish</h3>
<p>Many models of the chalk paints will dry quickly. However, for pattern and different complicated painting, chalk paint might not be helpful compared to
<a href="https://pestpolicy.com/best-acrylic-paint-for-professional-artists/">acrylic wet paints</a>
.
Homeowners and DIYers equally must get some quick-drying time depending on the current kitchen cabinet project. So, check the paint&rsquo;s drying time on the label instructions.
On the surface finish, remember that the chalk paint will give you a matte look after drying - may be reliable and smooth. So, what will vary is the colour and thus choose from the colour palette available.</p>
<h3 id="2-surface-coverage-an-eco-friendly">2. Surface Coverage an Eco-friendly?</h3>
<p>So, next, consider the coverage per supposed price. The chalk paint must give you an excellent cost per coverage. The model must also be
high-quality concerning the coverage.
Further, you must be environmentally conscious by checking of the chalk paint is eco-friendly. For example, check if the paint has ultra-low VOC and this must be outlined on the label instructions.</p>
<h3 id="3-chalk-paint-consistency">3. Chalk Paint Consistency</h3>
<p>The paint&rsquo;s consistency will affect how smooth the cabinets will be and how easy or difficult the product will be to apply for an excellent matte finish.
It&rsquo;s possible to use stencils and patterns among different paint techniques for decoration for various to allow the project to have an excellent finish at the end of the restoration.</p>
<h3 id="4-adhesive-qualities">4. Adhesive Qualities</h3>
<p>For renovating your kitchen cabinets, you&rsquo;ll require to first clean, risen, and dry the surfaces before starting the spray painting process - some may require priming or sanding.
So, check the adhesive features of the chalk paint that&rsquo;ll quickly revive the beauty on your cabinets. So, ensure that the paint will bond or adhere to the required materials.
Therefore, ensure excellent adhesion to that you as the DIYer or homeowner won&rsquo;t struggle while undertaking the cabinet painting project.</p>
<h2 id="competing-brands-for-furniture-chalk-paint">Competing Brands for Furniture Chalk Paint?</h2>
<h3 id="1-rust-oleum">1. Rust-Oleum</h3>
<p><a href="https://www.rustoleum.com/">Rust-Oleum</a>
is a top brand when it comes to the manufacture of chalk paints. Notably, their paints are high quality but tend to take a longer time to dry.
As a guideline, the Rust-Oleum paint models require roughly 15-30 minutes to dry. But the company doesn&rsquo;t;t have a variety of colours in their palette - but defined its possible to mix &amp; match the paints.
Luckily, these Rust-Oleum chalk paints can be applied to various materials, including canvas, wood, ceramic, and metal. Therefore,m you can easily create that beautiful look on your kitchen cabinets.</p>
<h3 id="2-rennaisance">2. Rennaisance</h3>
<p>Rennaisance also manufactures considerably quality chalk paints suitable for your furniture and kitchen cabinets. Equally, their products in this class are budget-friendly with different sizes.
Unlike with the Rust-Oleum models, the Rennaisance paints have variety in their colour pallet. Get 1 or 2 coats of the Rennaisancepaint to achieve that excellent look with no priming or sanding.
Rennaisance paints will also provide that matte finish that&rsquo;s also silky smooth besides also having a vintage outlook that you&rsquo;ll love
on your furniture.</p>
<h3 id="3-annie-sloan">3. Annie Sloan</h3>
<p>Finally, the Annie Sloan company is also a swimmer for the chalk paints. Its a relatively older brand in this category that came around during the raise of the chalk paints.</p>
<p>So, Annie Sloan is a famous brand with better priced per coverage (150sq ft for each quart) and fast-drying after application on various surfaces including wooden kitchen cabinets.</p>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>On the best chalk paint for kitchen cabinets, the above models will give your furniture an excellent finish.
You might also need to check the silhouette, doors hinges and give them some Polycrylic or polyurethane coating.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Paint for Kitchen Cabinets</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/best-paint-for-kitchen-cabinets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/best-paint-for-kitchen-cabinets/</guid>
      <description>By reading this article on the best paint for cabinets, you will not only acquire in-depth knowledge on the best cabinet paint, but you will also be able t...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By reading this article on the best paint for cabinets, you will not only acquire in-depth knowledge on the best cabinet paint, but you will also be able to select the right paint that matches the primary material of your cabinet.</p>
<p>Often than never, cabinet paint peels due to wrong paint selection in
[<a href="/posts/best-bonding-primer-for-kitchen-cabinets/">kitchen</a> cabinet repainting](<a href="https://pestpolicy.com/how-to-%5Bpaint%5D(/posts/best-chalk-paint-for-kitchen-cabinets/)-kitchen-cabinets-without-sanding/">https://pestpolicy.com/how-to-[paint](/posts/best-chalk-paint-for-kitchen-cabinets/)-kitchen-cabinets-without-sanding/</a>)
.
Thus, consider vital factors like cabinet construction material, the prevailing climate of the area (is it humid, dry, or wet environment?), the texture of surface material for
<a href="https://www.houzz.com/magazine/homeowners-workbook-how-to-remodel-your-kitchen-stsetivw-vs~1198907">kitchen remodeling</a>
.
Also, consider the extent of the area to be painted, the primer used (if any) on the cabinet (is it oil-based or water-based?), and the color of the primary material before placing your purchase order.</p>
<h2 id="s-top-7-best-paint-for-kitchen-cabinets-2025">s: Top 7 Best Paint for Kitchen Cabinets 2025</h2>
<h3 id="1-nuvo-driftwood-1-day-cabinet-paint"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0749QSHLN/?tag=p-policy-20">1. Nuvo Driftwood 1 Day Cabinet Paint</a></h3>
<p>Nova Driftwood is a water-based acrylic paint that features advanced stickiness properties, which guarantees minimal drains/runs when painting your kitchen cabinet.</p>
<p>You will love the attractive grey finish rendered by Nuvo and the incredible sheen resistant to humid chipping - considering the cabinets&rsquo; condition.
The fast-drying solvent is more comfortable to apply or remove. Using Nuvo Driftwood, you will save costs associated with priming, sanding, and polishing since Nuvo can be painted directly without any problem.
Nuvo is budget-friendly and integrates high-performance natural ingredients that firmly stick on the primary cabinet material without chipping or peeling. The single Nuvo coated cabinet attains excellent strength that is not only waterproof but also scratch-resistant.
Moreover, Nuvo Driftwood
features low VOC contents
, thus wont irritate your nasal/respiratory system when inhaled. Indeed, the simple chemical formula that comes with Nuvo is self-activating and act instantly upon application.
Notably, Nuvo Driftwood is exceptionally durable and works for wood, metal, and laminated cabinet material excellently. You can paint up to 100 square feet DIY project and comfortably correct paint errors with soap and water with Nuvo.
Pros:</p>
<ul>
<li>Its more comfortable to prepare  no priming or sanding needed.</li>
<li>Forms a waterproof coat finish</li>
<li>The coat is scratch-resistant and durable.</li>
<li>Comes with low VOC components  minimal pollution</li>
<li>More comfortable to apply with a roller or paintbrush</li>
<li>Requires one or two coats for a perfect finish</li>
<li>Its affordable and wont irritate your skin.</li>
<li>No thinning required</li>
</ul>
<p>Cons:</p>
<ul>
<li>Comes in limited colors  its grey.</li>
<li>The package could be more for commercial application</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vK3cHQGYGtg">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vK3cHQGYGtg</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>See Also:
Best Paints for your Fence</p></blockquote>
<h3 id="2-retique-it-chalk-furniture-paint"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B079QVWTVZ/?tag=p-policy-20">2. Retique It Chalk Furniture Paint</a></h3>
<p>Retique is a modern tech cabinet paint that works for all types of furniture material. The active ingredients that come with the solvent allow direct application without drains or runs.</p>
<p>Indeed, Retique is specially formulated with an instant action chemical structure that firmly sticks on the cabinet material without peeling or chipping.
Unlike other acrylic paints, Retique is water-based, fast-drying, and comes with zero volatile organic compounds  no pollution.
Further, Retique is more comfortable preparing and removing  it sticks sufficiently on a paintbrush or roller and gets removed with soapy detergent at ease.
The chalky smooth surface finish nicely seals edges and delivers unmatched durability - even with your
quality HVLP paint sprayers
.
Retique wont irritate your nasal cavity (virtually no odor) or skin upon contact. The non-toxic compound is manufactured in various beautiful colors (selectable) that look outstanding upon application.
The USA made solvent comes with self-leveling properties and provides a tough coat layer that is both waterproof and dust-resistant.
More so, you can use Retique on metal or laminated wood cabinet material without any problem.
NB: Retique is packed in a 946ml container that covers 100 to 160 square feet.
Pros:</p>
<ul>
<li>Its available in multiple selectable colors.</li>
<li>Non-toxic and virtually no odor</li>
<li>Safe for direct skin contact  no irritation</li>
<li>Forms a tough, thick coat later  durable</li>
<li>Limited drain or runs  improved stickiness</li>
<li>Simple to prepare and remove</li>
<li>More comfortable to apply  no priming or sanding</li>
<li>Creates a smooth chalky finish</li>
<li>Has zero VOC components</li>
</ul>
<p>Cons:</p>
<ul>
<li>Not transparent  solid coat</li>
<li>Unsuitable for large scale painting</li>
<li>Not suitable for wet cabinet material</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Fpz7e38B8hw">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Fpz7e38B8hw</a></p>
<h3 id="3-insl-x-cc550109a-01-cabinet"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07KXLPCG1/?tag=p-policy-20">3. INSL-X CC550109A-01 Cabinet</a></h3>
<p>INSL-X is a urethane acrylic satin specially manufactured to deliver a factory smooth finish on your primary cabinet material.</p>
<p>The minimal drain properties integrated into chemical formulation eliminate runs during paint application. You may cover
many wood stains
or colors with no requirement for priming.
By selecting INSL-X, you will enjoy extensive area coverage (350 - 450 square feet) and achieve hard coating that resists chipping, peeling, and scuffing on a single application.
Besides, INSL-X leaves a durable waterproof paint layer that resists dust, grease, and UV rays damage.
INSL-X integrates super adhesive additives that seal porous points and holes during cabinet paint restoration.
Unlike most acrylic paints, INSL-X guarantees unparalleled performance when used within a temperature range of� 10 to 32 degrees.
Besides, the solvent is simple to prepare and apply. You wont experience nasal irritation or skin discomfort when you come into contact with INSL-X.
The white satin compound is packed in a one-gallon container with a classic handle to ease transportation  highly portable.
With INSL-X, you dont need to prime the surface or sand the cabinet material when painting  the paint can be applied directly. INSL-X painting errors can be cleaned with soap and water when still wet  no thinning required.
Pros:</p>
<ul>
<li>Packed in large quantity container  one gallon</li>
<li>Forms a harsh adhesive coat  waterproof</li>
<li>No priming or sanding during application</li>
<li>Durable and more comfortable to apply  elastic</li>
<li>Little peeling, scuffing or chipping on a single-layer coat.</li>
<li>Scratch-resistant and water-based active ingredients</li>
<li>Delivers factory finish coat  impressive</li>
<li>Odor-free and wont cause skin irritation.</li>
<li>Fast-drying  takes 6 hours</li>
</ul>
<p>Cons:</p>
<ul>
<li>Come in one color only  white.</li>
<li>The dried adhesive may take time to remove</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>See Also:
Can You Use Exterior Paint Indoors?</p></blockquote>
<h3 id="4-hemway-black-chalk-based-furniture-paint"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B088P49QSJ/?tag=p-policy-20">4. Hemway Black Chalk Based Furniture Paint</a></h3>
<p>Hemway is a water-based decorative paint that features refined natural ingredients, which stick firmly on the cabinet material without drains or runs.</p>
<p>The low VOC compound comes with attractive colors (selectable) that make your kitchen cabinets stand out upon application -
suitable for woodworking
, metal, prime, or laminate cabinets.
With Hemway, you will lower sanding/priming costs since the solvent requires a direct application.
Hemway is simple to prepare and clean  you can easily remove wet paint with soap and water. Moreover, challenges such as chipping, scuffing, or peeling can permanently be sorted by choosing Hemway for your cabinet paint application.
Besides, Hemway comes with wood additives that improve stickiness and leave a classic, smooth finish, both waterproof and dirt-resistant.
The low VOC solvent is non-toxic and wont irritate your nasal cavity when inhale or cause skin discomfort upon contact.
Hemway guarantees top paint performance and comes with reliable monochrome stickiness strength that resists scratches or surface abrasive motion.
Indeed, you will love the smooth surface finish and fast-drying period (2 hours) that comes with Hemway  you can paint and use the cabinet that same day.
NB: Hemway can be used to coat metal, plaster, laminated wood, or plastic cabinet material without any challenge.
Pros:</p>
<ul>
<li>Its simple to prepare and remove</li>
<li>Has high stickiness strength and low VOCs</li>
<li>Comes in an attractive color and smooth finish</li>
<li>Creates minimal surface drains or runs</li>
<li>Can be used on walls and all other furniture</li>
<li>Doesnt need sanding or priming when painting</li>
<li>Dries fast and covers a wide area  25 square meters</li>
</ul>
<p>Cons:</p>
<ul>
<li>The package could be more for large scale.</li>
<li>Has few selectable colors</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>See Also:
HVLP Paint Sprayer for Latex Paint</p></blockquote>
<h3 id="5-kilz-adhesion-high-bonding-interior-latex-paint"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B00J9Q58VC/?tag=p-policy-20">5. KILZ Adhesion High-Bonding Interior Latex Paint</a></h3>
<p>If you intend to achieve a tough solid finish on your kitchen cabinets, choosing KILZ adhesive will deliver unmatched performance.</p>
<p>The solvent is manufactured to eliminate paint peeling, scuffing, or chipping problems upon application.
Indeed, KILZ features a complex chemical structure that is self-activating upon contact with cabinet material.
The scratch and the abrasive stain will permanently be eliminated by selecting KILZ for your cabinet DIY painting or restoration.
KILZ comes with low volatile compounds that wont cause respiratory irritation when inhale when painting.
You can apply KILZ directly on cabinets without sanding or any surface preparation and achieve an excellent surface finish.
The dense, glossy surface formed by the KILZ paint layer is dust and water-resistant. Indeed, the solvent is agitated with unique natural ingredients that improve stickiness and outlook appearance upon application.
KILZ dries in one hour and forms a permanent coat that protects the cabinet material from mildew and mold growth  best for a damp kitchen environment.
Further, KILZ is packed in a 946ml container that will cover approximately 300 square feet.
Pros:</p>
<ul>
<li>Leaves a smooth glossy surface finish  waterproof</li>
<li>More comfortable to prepare and apply</li>
<li>Non-toxic and doesnt cause skin irritation.</li>
<li>Has improved stickiness strength  no scratches</li>
<li>Dries faster (1 hour) and mold resistant</li>
<li>Direct application  no sanding needed</li>
<li>Comes with a simple water-based formula</li>
</ul>
<p>Cons:</p>
<ul>
<li>Not for extensive scale application  946ml can</li>
<li>May need an extra coat  primer formula</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r_jv9hub5j4&amp;feature=youtu.be">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r_jv9hub5j4&amp;feature=youtu.be</a></p>
<h3 id="6-rust-oleum-258242-base-cabinet-transformations-kit"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B004QECDVA/?tag=p-policy-20">6. RUST-OLEUM 258242 Base Cabinet Transformations Kit</a></h3>
<p>Rust-Oleum features a dark tint base that coats the cabinet primary material firmly without peeling.</p>
<p>You will restore or refurbish your old cabinet excellently by select Rust-Oleum as your number one base coating  it has refined ingredients and quality grain integration.
The base solvent is naturally agitated (to improve stickiness) and comes with a simple action formula that breaks instantly during painting.
Moreover, Rust-Oleum eliminates sanding and priming processes, thus lowering the overall cost with a single kit.
By selecting Rust-Oleum, you will enjoy limited chipping or scuffing and attain a stunning cabinet impression.
More so, Rust-Oleum guarantees you over ten tint-able colors with optional tinting to match your cabinet finish choice.
Rust-Oleum is formulated to improve drying time (fast drying) and extend the paint restoration period without overlooking overall appearance.
Further, the dark tint rendered by Rust-Oleum resists mold and mildew  you can comfortably cover cabinets located in a humid environment without any problem.
Rust-Oleum is reliable and comes in a large package that covers over 200 square feet. The solvent is packed in a base form that requires tinting to match your cabinet color before application.
You will love the stunning final finish and impressive match that Rust-Oleum delivers in your kitchen.
Pros:</p>
<ul>
<li>Its budget-friendly and attractive.</li>
<li>Comes in multiple tint-able colors</li>
<li>Forms a classic outlook impression</li>
<li>Doesnt require sanding or priming</li>
<li>Covers wide surface area  200sq ft</li>
<li>Its fast-drying and resists mold/mildew.</li>
<li>No peeling or scuffing upon use</li>
<li>Its waterproof and resists dirt</li>
</ul>
<p>Cons:</p>
<ul>
<li>Require tinting before application</li>
<li>A dried coat is tedious to clean</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>See Also:
<a href="https://pestpolicy.com/best-stain-for-swing-set/">Quality Playset Stains</a></p></blockquote>
<h3 id="7-shabby-chic-furniture-chalk-paint"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B00YF2YA8W/?tag=p-policy-20">7. Shabby Chic Furniture Chalk Paint</a></h3>
<p>Shabby Chic is a water-based chalk paint that features a simple chemical formulation, which breaks and spreads smoothly during application.</p>
<p>The solvent integrates natural grains that improve surface stickiness and eliminates unnecessary drains/runs when painting.
By selecting Shabby Chic, you will enjoy improved service life (for cabinet) on a single application and excellent final finish  the solvent forms a smooth finish that is both attractive and abrasive resistant.
Moreover, Shabby Chic comes with low VOC compounds; thus, it wont cause nasal irritation (when inhaled) or irritated your skin upon contact.
Indeed, Shabby Chic guarantees a permanent solution to peeling, chipping, or scuffing on a single application.
The non-toxic cabinet paint integrates beautiful, selectable colors that will resist fading and leave your kitchen cabinets attractive/stunning.
Further, Shabby Chic penetrates the cabinet material without affecting the primary surface grain during application.
With Shabby Chic, you will eliminate mildew or mold growth  the product is best for damp areas.
Furthermore, Shabby Chic is more comfortable to prepare and remove  paint errors can be cleaned using soapy detergent and water when still wet.
The chalk pigments integrated into Shabby Chic improves surface strength and resist dirt. Importantly, Shabby Chic can be used on wood, metal, composite, or plastic cabinet material without any problem.
Pros:</p>
<ul>
<li>Comes with simple chemical formula  more comfortable to apply</li>
<li>Has multiple selectable colors  attractive</li>
<li>Its water-based and comes with refined chalk grains</li>
<li>Eliminates peeling and chipping on a single coat</li>
<li>Water-resistant and dirt proof</li>
<li>Doesnt cause skin or respiratory irritation</li>
<li>Has low VOC components  environmentally safe</li>
<li>Improve stickiness and smooth surface finish</li>
<li>Extended service life and abrasion resistant-coat</li>
</ul>
<p>Cons:</p>
<ul>
<li>Unsuitable for commercial application</li>
<li>Require surface preparation to improve stickiness</li>
<li>The container doesnt have a handle</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>See Also:
Using TSP prior to Painting</p></blockquote>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>The best paint for kitchen cabinets article is written as an eye-opener towards eliminating low-quality or wrong cabinet paint selection.
I believe you have gained a more in-depth insight into avoiding paint drains, chipping, or peeling of painted cabined by purchasing the best quality paint from the above reviews.
Remember, its always important to consider the extent of the area to be painted, the type of cabinet material, the prevailing climate of the area, and the intended finish color before placing your order.
Notably, go for a cabinet paint that is more comfortable to apply and one that wont weigh you down financially.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Primer for Kitchen Cabinets</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/best-primer-for-kitchen-cabinets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/best-primer-for-kitchen-cabinets/</guid>
      <description>Are you looking to facelift your</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Are you looking to facelift your
[<a href="/posts/best-bonding-primer-for-kitchen-cabinets/">kitchen</a> cabinets](<a href="https://pestpolicy.com/best-paint-for-kitchen-cabinets/">https://pestpolicy.com/best-paint-for-kitchen-cabinets/</a>)
? A primer is used as a preparatory coat on previously unpainted wood, metal, or canvas, mainly to prevent the absorption of subsequent layers of paint or the development of rust.</p>
<p>Choosing the best primers for your stained or newly installed kitchen cabinets is therapeutic and gives you a good bonding with your household.
In this article, I have outlined the most renowned kitchen cabinets primers in the market that will assist you as you do the
kitchen remodeling
.</p>
<h2 id="s-top-7-best-primer-for-kitchen-cabinets-in-2025">s: Top 7 Best Primer for Kitchen Cabinets in 2025</h2>
<h3 id="1-rust-oleum-primer-2004-zinsser-bulls-eye"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B000H5VKBQ/?tag=p-policy-20">1. Rust-Oleum Primer, 2004 Zinsser Bulls Eye</a></h3>
<p>This is one of the most highly sort after primer due to its multiple benefits and adhesiveness.</p>
<p>Formulated as a water-based primer, Rust-Oleum 2004 sticks to multiple surfaces, including tile and metal surfaces, without the requirement of sanding.
Interestingly you can use this primer on almost all exterior and interior surfaces. Its rustproof ability makes it ideal for applying on metal surfaces and exterior surfaces exposed to harsh weather.
Additionally, it inhibits blistering, peeling off, and well mildew growth making it one of the best primers to own - and hence it&rsquo;s approved for
<a href="https://www.housebeautiful.com/home-remodeling/g3813/kitchen-makeovers/">remodeling your cabinets</a>
.
What is so exceptional about this product is that it makes an excellent choice for PH surfaces, including concretes, and works well on glossy surfaces like enameled trim and tiles. The result is ultimately a surface easy to clean with water and soap.
The primer I packaged in a quart can cover at least 100 square ft. However, with these primers, you may be required to apply more than two coats to achieve the desired surface.
Pros:</p>
<ul>
<li>Rust-proof</li>
<li>Applied on all surfaces</li>
<li>High adhesiveness</li>
<li>No sanding required</li>
</ul>
<p>Cons:</p>
<ul>
<li>Requires more than one coat</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=w1NTFj1XR54">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=w1NTFj1XR54</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>See Also:
Painting the Kitchen Cabinets without Sanding</p></blockquote>
<h3 id="2-kilz-l211101-primer-adhesion-high-bonding-interior-sealer"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B01LYXUU4E/?tag=p-policy-20">2. KILZ-L211101 Primer Adhesion High Bonding Interior Sealer</a></h3>
<p>KILZ L-211101, as popularly known, is a good bonding primer. This uniquely designed primer adheres well with slick and tough to paint surfaces like vinyl,
glass surfaces
, Formica, among others where other primers can hardly work.</p>
<p>Important to note, clean the surface from materials such as chalk, grease mold, rust, and dust to achieve the best surface - this is one of the
quality primers
for longer protection and excellent adhesion.
Surprisingly, this primer also outsmarts all the other primers in the market in terms of efficacy and prevents mold from growing from the surface.
When applying, you can either
use a roller
, a brush, or spray while the prime only takes 30 minutes to dry and touch. However, a second coat can only be applied after an hour to achieve the best results.
This primer has also featured among the best primers to use on kitchen cabinets and other hard surfaces. You can get this primer packaged on 1 quart, and 1 gallon and one gallon can cover a surface of about 300 square ft.
Pros:</p>
<ul>
<li>Suitable for tough surfaces likefiberglass</li>
<li>Applied by brush, roller, or spray</li>
<li>Fast-drying</li>
<li>Adheres most surfaces</li>
</ul>
<p>Cons:</p>
<ul>
<li>Proper cleaning before priming</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dxD_4XldUvg">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dxD_4XldUvg</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>See Also:
Painted Vs Stained Cabinets</p></blockquote>
<h3 id="3-kilz-restoration-maximum-stain-primersealer"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B007XH9PKO/?tag=p-policy-20">3. KILZ Restoration Maximum Stain Primer/Sealer</a></h3>
<p>KILZ Restoration Max is one of the finest water-based primers you can find in the market.</p>
<p>It is quality defined by how it blocks strong stains such as smoke, rust grease, nicotine, or water damage - it also helps in the
prevention of rust
.
This makes it a perfect stain for vintage cabinets&rsquo; preparation before application of latex or oil-based paints.
You can use KILZ Restoration to tickle tough stains and save yourself the unnecessary cost of sanding your cabinets. Moreover, you can get the primer in one and 5-gallon cans, of which one gallon covers about 300-400 square ft.
In case you intend to do a quick paint, this primer has a quick-drying feature that enables you to cover your work fast on
plastic
,�plaster, metal, and wooden kitchen cabinets.
However, to achieve excellent results, this primer should be applied as fast as possible. You can apply this primer either by use of a roller brush or an
airless sprayer
.
Pros:</p>
<ul>
<li>Blocks stains</li>
<li>Fast drying</li>
<li>Adheres to multiple surfaces</li>
</ul>
<p>Cons:</p>
<ul>
<li>Proper surface cleaning prior application</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>See Also:
Valspar Cabinet Paint</p></blockquote>
<h3 id="4-zinsser-03504-interiorexterior-oil-primer-sealer"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B000BZX6B4/?tag=p-policy-20">4. Zinsser-03504 Interior/Exterior Oil Primer Sealer</a></h3>
<p>If you are a professional painter, Zinsser-03504 is an
oil-based paint
or primer designed to give you a perfectly smooth look on your cabinets.</p>
<p>This primer is formulated to block many stains and seal smoke, water, and nicotine stains. It is versatile - it works like a glass primer, tile primer, concrete primer, and
<a href="https://pestpolicy.com/best-primer-for-rusted-metal/">metal primer</a>
.
Similarly, this primer has extraordinary hiding abilities and can be used both on the exterior and interior surfaces with easy sanding.
On exterior surfaces, this primer is mostly preferred for its great flexibility and penetration on surfaces.
Apart from the new constructions, you can also use them for remodeling,
repainting a cabinet
, or prime other projects.
Similarly, its preference for interior surfaces is due to its fast-drying feature and providing undercoat enamel.
In the case of redwood bleeding, dark colors, and stains, Zinsser primer is all you need for an excellent job.
On using this primer, it takes 8 hours to dry before a second coat is applied, and in the case of imperfections, sandpaper can be used to achieve a clean, smooth surface.
Pros:</p>
<ul>
<li>Suitable for interior and exterior surfaces</li>
<li>Blocks stains - prevents<a href="https://www.justthewoods.com/bleed-through-painting-furniture/">tanning from bleed</a>.</li>
<li>Made in the USA</li>
<li>Has great penetration and flexibility</li>
</ul>
<p>Cons:</p>
<ul>
<li>Contains VOCs</li>
<li>Has odor</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>See Also:
Varathane Fast Dry Wood Stain</p></blockquote>
<h3 id="5-zinsser-b-i-n-shellac-base-primer-1-gallon"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B000C02C68/?tag=p-policy-20">5. Zinsser B-I-N Shellac-Base Primer, 1-Gallon</a></h3>
<p>Zinsser B-I-N is an oil-based primer that can be used both on the interior and exterior surfaces- such as on
new or old metal surfaces
.</p>
<p>It is best known to cover stains better than all other oil and latex-based
paint
. Similarly, it is also known to cover smoke, moldy odor, and pet stains.
It can be best achieved through prior priming before painting or topcoats on your kitchen cabinet. You can apply this primer on all surfaces, which sticks well even without sanding required.
It is important to note that the Zinsser B-I-N primer has strong fumes and must be applied when in a well-ventilated area.
Similarly,
use a brush
and avoid spraying the primer since this will increase the fumes in the environment, which is hazardous.
For such cases, ensure you put on gas masks or respirators whenever applying this primer to avoid inhaling the fumes.
Pros:</p>
<ul>
<li>Sticks to all surfaces</li>
<li>Fast drying</li>
<li>Good for interior and exteriors surfaces</li>
<li>Good stain sealer</li>
</ul>
<p>Cons:</p>
<ul>
<li>Strong odor</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>See Also:
Interior vs Exterior Paint Compared</p></blockquote>
<h3 id="6-insl-x-sxa11009a-01-acrylic-waterborne-bonding-primer"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07KX8NV7Y/?tag=p-policy-20">6. INSL-X SXA11009A-01 Acrylic Waterborne Bonding Primer</a></h3>
<p>INSL-X SXA11009A-01 is one of the finest acrylic primers competent enough to compete with both oil and shellac-based primers -
use suitable paintbrushes
.</p>
<p>It is formulated with adherent ability to glossy surfaces and creates a hard film on challenging and tough surfaces.
However, this primer is not recommended for polypropylene, and such a strong topcoat must be used - it
<a href="https://rainbowintl.com/blog/how-to-remove-cigarette-tar-and-nicotine-from-walls">prevents nicotine stains</a>
, smoke, and water from seeping.
If you are experiencing a challenge of tough stains and smell in your kitchen cabinets, this primer will be a good reproof for you.
I like this primer because it adheres to almost all rigid surfaces and cures into challenging films with enamel holdouts, has quick resistance to cracking and blistering, and a smooth leveling.
This primer is
low on VOCs
and equally easy to clean with soap and water.
With INSL-X SXA11009A-01, you achieve fast results as it is fast to dry with 3 hours for a recoat. However, when applying, ensure low temperatures of not above for quick drying and better results.
Pros:</p>
<ul>
<li>Fast drying</li>
<li>Low VOCs</li>
<li>Easy to clean</li>
<li>Applicable on tough surfaces</li>
</ul>
<p>Cons:</p>
<ul>
<li>Needs more than two coats</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>See Also:
If You Dont Paint Over Primer - What Happens
?</p></blockquote>
<h3 id="7-kilz-2-multi-surface-interiorexterior-latex-primersealer"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0013FE5R0/?tag=p-policy-20">7. KILZ-2 Multi-Surface Interior/Exterior Latex Primer/Sealer</a></h3>
<p>KILZ 2 is a water-based multi-surface primer that provides superb adhesion to paints on porous surfaces and suitable in interior and exterior surface painting.</p>
<p>You can use it to treat strong films, and suitable for
resisting mildew growth
in your kitchen cabinets.
You can use this primer on surfaces such as plaster, metal bricks, and drywall, among others, due to its ability to adhere to multi-surfaces.
Among the stains, you can use this primer to hide water, ink, grease, felt markers, among others.
This prime is quite efficient on interior surfaces and only takes 30 minutes to dry-to-touch and approximately one hour for a second coat.
Afterward, you can you oil or latex-based paints to do a top coat to achieve the best results. Before applying primer, ensure the surface is clean of dust, grease, paint peels, and
rust inhibitor
.
Care should be taken as the primer has very strong odor and therefore a gas mask or ventilator is advisable during application.
Pros:</p>
<ul>
<li>Fast drying</li>
<li>Suitable on all surfaces</li>
<li>Works on both interior and exterior surfaces</li>
<li>Masks stains</li>
<li>Manufactured in the USA</li>
</ul>
<p>Cons:</p>
<ul>
<li>Has strong odor</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>See Also:
<a href="https://pestpolicy.com/best-drywall-primer-sealer/">Drywall Primer Sealer</a></p></blockquote>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>With the above reviews and outline, it is easier to narrow down to the choice of the best primer for your kitchen. But, I have made a few recommendations for you that will be more helpful.</p>
<ul>
<li>The most rated primer Rust-Oleum Primer, 2004 Zinsser Bulls Eye, makes an excellent choice for you. It adheres to most surfaces and requires no sanding.</li>
<li>For a suitable water-based primer, KILZ Restoration Maximum Stain Primer/Sealer is excellent. Being environmentally friendly is most appropriate for the application ofindoor and outdoor.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Much Does It Cost to Paint Kitchen Cabinets</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-much-does-it-cost-to-paint-kitchen-cabinets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-much-does-it-cost-to-paint-kitchen-cabinets/</guid>
      <description>Painting protects primary material from damage and eliminates external agents that weaken the structural strength. However, costing</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Painting protects primary material from damage and eliminates external agents that weaken the structural strength. However, costing
[<a href="/posts/how-to-paint-kitchen-cabinets-without-sanding/">kitchen</a> cabinet paintwork](<a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07KXLPCG1/?tag=p-policy-20">https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07KXLPCG1/?tag=p-policy-20</a>)
may not be easy, especially when wrong data is estimated.</p>
<p><em>So, how much does it cost to paint kitchen cabinets? Well, the painting cost for kitchen cabinets ranges from $700 to $2200. However, the cost of repainting, the cost may rise up to $400.�</em>
*But the answer varies with the size of the cabinet, location, type of paint to be used, and the quality of finish expected eventually. *
<em>When planning for your painting work, you need to account for the cost of material and tools required, labor cost, transport cost, the cost associated with a method of painting (is it spray painting or use of a paintbrush/roller?), and miscellaneous costs.</em>
<em>Moreover, you need to familiarize yourself with the costs of various paints, the cost of repainting, painting cost per square foot, and the overall painting cost that you may end up incurring; for your own budget purpose.�</em></p>
<h2 id="details-how-much-does-it-cost-to-paint-kitchen-cabinets">Details: How Much Does It Cost To Paint Kitchen Cabinets</h2>
<p>Remember, cabinet painting costs may vary from place to place due to economic factors. Therefore, its important to keep yourself up to date with painting trends in your area.</p>
<h3 id="a-cost-of-material-and-tools">a. Cost of Material and Tools</h3>
<p>Material cost and tools are the primary need for any painting activity to be undertaken since the quote gives the aerial view of the initial cost needed.
When selecting material, you will need to consult a professional painter (in case you are new to painting) or contract a painter to do the task.
<strong>Material or Tool</strong>
<strong>Average Cost</strong>
1.
<a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07KXLPCG1/?tag=p-policy-20">Cabinet paint</a>
$50
2.
<a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B01M0AVNP6/?tag=p-policy-20">Cabinet Primer</a>
(if needed)
$32
3.
<a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B00QXXN79O/?tag=p-policy-20">Paint Thinner</a>
$12
4.
Paint Scraper (for paint restoration)
$2
5.
<a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07JHQ4L4F/?tag=p-policy-20">Paint Brush</a>
$6
6.
Paint Roller (Alternative)
$16
7.
<a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B003PGQI48/?tag=p-policy-20">Paint Sprayer</a>
(Alternative)
$145
8.
<a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B005HJ8PBU/?tag=p-policy-20">Overall</a>
$40
9.
Boots
$120
10.
<a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08C7C825D/?tag=p-policy-20">Respirator</a>
$36
11.
Gloves
$22
12.
<a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08PFZ7FKL/?tag=p-policy-20">Bucket or Container</a>
$14
13.
Water  10 liters
$5</p>
<h3 id="b-labor-cost">b. Labor Cost</h3>
<p>Labor cost is a function of the nature of the agreement  is it a contract-based or hourly charge rate? Usually, the labor cost range from $0.5 to $20 per square foot according to the nature of your cabinet material.
Rough cabinet material required a lot of surface preparation before actual preparation is carried out. Therefore, a professional painter will tend to charge slightly more.
In order to estimate the labor cost of your cabinet painting, you will need to measure and calculate the total surface area to be painted. This particular approach is necessary as it will also help you in accounting for the quantity of paint to purchase.
Remember, the quoted labor cost doesnt incorporate the transport cost  for those painters coming from far, you may need to go deeper into your pocket.
Alternatively, you may agree to charge your painting cost per day  the standard rate is about $200 to $500 per day at most.
Further, you may opt to fix your paintwork at an hourly rate where you pay your professional painter somewhere between $20 to $54 per hour.
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6R9HKvGxbR0">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6R9HKvGxbR0</a></p>
<h3 id="c-miscellaneous-cost">c. Miscellaneous Cost</h3>
<p>Miscellaneous costs are costs that may be incurred and not accounted for in the budget.
Its necessary to always have an extra side budget when planning for your kitchen cabinet painting since most times, the budget always spills over the actual plan.
For example, the paint may run short, and there you may need to buy more from a local vendor, or the paint/
thinner
may even spill when painting accidentally.
The transport costs associated with miscellaneous purchases were not in the initial budget too  failure to meet such costs affects the projects completion time and hence the overall cost is increased.
You can always set aside $50 to $70 for a miscellaneous costs plan.</p>
<h3 id="d-transport-cost">d. Transport Cost</h3>
<p>Depending on where your home is located, the transport cost will also vary  the far the kitchen (home) the higher the transport cost. Moreover, the cost of transporting the material and tools needed is determined by the quantity ordered.
You will pay more if the quantities ordered are more  unless the seller offers after-sales services.�Transport costs also include the cost of ferrying the painter to your home and back.
Otherwise, such costs will be accounted for in labor costing. In case you are buying a few materials and tools, its advisable to purchase them from a nearby retailer/vendor.
However, for large quantities, its recommended that you buy them from manufacturers or wholesalers in order to enjoy after-sales services and other discounts.
The transport may cost you about $13 to $60 per mile depending on the road infrastructure in your locality.</p>
<h3 id="e-painting-cost-per-foot">e. Painting Cost per Foot</h3>
<p>The average painting costs per square foot range between $3 to $24. The cost entails, labor and paint needed. The cost may vary slightly upward, especially when there is inflation of products within the economy.
Besides, the kitchen cabinets (under paint reinforcement) may cost more per foot since the labor cost is increased and the
<a href="https://pestpolicy.com/best-bonding-primer-for-kitchen-cabinets/">bonding primer</a>
(which at times is an option) is always used to attain a quality finish.
Importantly, the complexity of your cabinet design calls for more painting costs (up to $20 additional costs per square foot) since the paint application process becomes more cumbersome to a professional painter.</p>
<h3 id="f-spray-paint-cost">f. Spray Paint Cost</h3>
<p>Spray painting is slightly expensive as compared to the use of a paintbrush or a roller (when painting your kitchen cabinets) since the prayer requires power and a professional for quality results.
To undertake spray painting, you will have to purchase or hire a paint sprayer  the hiring cost range between $20 to $35, while the purchasing cost of a paint sprayer maybe somewhere between $18 to $1500  its a matter of the size and efficiency you need.
On average, its advisable to consider hiring
a paint sprayer
instead of purchasing one  unless you are intending to use the sprayer for commercial purposes.</p>
<h3 id="g-roller-or-brush-painting-cost">g. Roller or Brush Painting Cost</h3>
<p>By using a roller or a paintbrush, you will lower the paint cost by half since the power bills and professional sprayer operator may not be needed.
The cost of paint using
a paintbrush
or a roller ranges between $2.5 to $7.5 per square foot.
The extent to which the cost varies when painting using a roller or a paintbrush is determined by the cabinets design and ease to use a bush (when painting) without obstacles.
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=S49L_GoFO6Y">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=S49L_GoFO6Y</a></p>
<h3 id="h-repaint-cost">h. Repaint Cost</h3>
<p>The average cost of repainting a kitchen cabinet ranges from $800 to $3500. The cost entails, the labor cost (surface preparation, sanding, and polishing, actual paint application), material, and tools needed.
In case your cabinet requires partial repair, you may need to pay more (up to $100) for repair material and another reinforcement before actual painting is undertaken.
Repainting kitchen cabinets is always a cumbersome process (especially kitchen found in the sooty area).
Therefore, most professional painters tend to charge slightly higher than normal paint application rates.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>See Also:
<a href="https://pestpolicy.com/how-to-thin-acrylic-paint/">Thin Acrylic Paint (Acrylics Paint)</a></p></blockquote>
<h2 id="what-are-major-kitchen-cabinet-painting-considerations">What are Major Kitchen Cabinet Painting Considerations?</h2>
<p>Before commencing your kitchen cabinets paintworks, its advisable to consider some of these factors:</p>
<h3 id="1-expected-quality">1. Expected Quality</h3>
<p>Every homeowner desires to have quality painted kitchen cabinets though this is not always the case due to other limiting factors highlighted below:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Price</strong>. The quality finish coat is a function of quality paint, which is more expensive. Most homeowners arent willing to pay extra.</li>
<li>You are therefore needed to come to terms with the quality of finish coat you need to attain and match that with the cost.</li>
<li><strong>Scuff and peel-resistant paint</strong>. Though costly such paints deliver a quality paint coat that resists chipping when used in humid areas too.</li>
<li><strong>Wear-resistant</strong>. Top-quality paint should resist wear and tear in case of abrasive force. Usually, the best quality paint sticks strongly and limits drains or scratches.</li>
<li><strong>Appearance longevity</strong>. The quality finish coat should resist color fading and maintain the initial paint color.</li>
<li><strong>Water, dirt, and grime resistance</strong>. A quality painted kitchen cabinet should resist water, dirt, or grime upon contact.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="2-choice-of-paint-type-to-use">2. Choice of Paint Type to Use</h3>
<p>The paint type for the kitchen cabinet could either be oil-based or water-based  the choice depends on the type of quality finish you intend to achieve and the location of your kitchen cabinets.
Oil-based paint should not be used on cabinets found near the fireplace, while water-based paint should be used on kitchen cabinets located away from the water point.
Otherwise, waterproofing is mandatory.�When selecting your paint choice, consider other factors listed below:
<strong>Water-based paint or latex paint</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Easier to apply</li>
<li>More comfortable to thin</li>
<li>Fast drying</li>
<li>Easier to strip</li>
<li>Fade-resistant</li>
<li>Low VOCs
<strong>Oil-based paint or Acrylic Paint</strong></li>
<li>Not susceptible to wear and tear</li>
<li>Scratch-resistant</li>
<li>Fast drying and more comfortable to apply</li>
<li>Minimal VOCs</li>
<li>Integrates alkyds resins</li>
<li>Easier to remove</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>See Also:
Acrylic Paint for Pouring</p></blockquote>
<h3 id="3-color-to-use">3. Color to Use</h3>
<p>Paints are manufactured in endless color options and combinations that are more challenging when it comes to cabinet paint matching. However, some of the common cabinet colors include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Black</li>
<li>Grey</li>
<li>Brown</li>
<li>White</li>
<li>Sky-blue</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="4-quantity-needed">4. Quantity Needed</h3>
<p>The quantity of paint needed to coat your kitchen cabinets is determined by the total surface area. Usually, one gallon covers 400 square feet.
As said earlier, the 1
st
step in determining the cost of painting your kitchen cabinets is to take the overall measurement (both interior and exterior surface) and compute the surface area where possible.
Then, equate one gallon to 400 square feet and divide it with the total surface area to get the total paint gallons needed to paint your kitchen cabinets completely. Remember, net paint quantity should have extra 3 or 4 gallons to cater for any spillage or drains.</p>
<h2 id="how-to-choose-a-professional-painter-for-your-kitchen-cabinet-painting-job">How to Choose a Professional Painter for Your Kitchen Cabinet Painting Job</h2>
<p>Perhaps you are new to painting; consider some of the following factors when choosing the best professional painter:</p>
<ol>
<li>Should be in a position to offer warranty for labor and material</li>
<li>Should have a great work portfolio</li>
<li>They should be insured in case of an accident</li>
<li>Should have a high rating in a matter of painting and home improvement</li>
<li>Should be in a position to set up clear quotation and costing</li>
<li>One should offer clear communication concerning the work at hand</li>
<li>Should be able to calculate for material and equipment needed</li>
<li>Should be fair in labor cost and minimizes other expenditures</li>
<li>They should be able to keep you updated on the progress  clear report.
See Also:
Acrylic Paint for Canvas</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>In summary, on how much does it cost to paint kitchen cabinets, the cost is a function of the size of the cabinet to be painted, the location, type of paint to be used, and the finish quality expected at the end.
When planning for your painting work, you need to account for the cost of material and tools required, transport cost, labor cost, the cost associated with a particular method of painting (is it spray painting or use of a paintbrush/roller?), and miscellaneous costs.
Besides, you have to familiarize yourself with current paint costs (in your locality), cost of repainting, painting cost per square foot, and the net painting cost that you may incur eventually; for budgeting purposes.
Painting costs vary from place to place due to economic factors. Therefore, its advisable to adjust your cost estimates in relation to the current location.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Paint Kitchen Cabinets Without Sanding</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-to-paint-kitchen-cabinets-without-sanding/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-to-paint-kitchen-cabinets-without-sanding/</guid>
      <description>Painting cabinets is a common activity carried out during paint restoration or new coat application in homes of commercial places. Whether its a kitchen ca...</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Painting cabinets is a common activity carried out during paint restoration or new coat application in homes of commercial places. Whether its a kitchen <a href="/posts/best-paint-for-kitchen-cabinets/">cabinet</a> or a wardrobe, sanding affects the finish outlook upon paint application, especially the case of the laminate wood.</p>
<p>Could you be facing similar challenges and wonder how to paint your cabinet afresh or restore old paint?
<em>On how to paint <a href="/posts/how-much-does-it-cost-to-paint-kitchen-cabinets/">kitchen</a> cabinets without sanding, select the right material and tools, detach cabinet drawers and doors, clean the entire cabinet, select the right paint, and prepare it accordingly.�</em>
<em>Further, carry out actual painting step by step, attain a classic final finish before fixing back the cabinet drawers and doors. Put on proper protection gear during paint application to boost your safety and avoid any hazards. See Also:�</em>
stain for your swing set
.</p>
<h2 id="details-how-to-paint-kitchen-cabinets-without-sanding">Details: How to Paint Kitchen Cabinets without Sanding</h2>
<h3 id="a-material-and-tools-needed">a. Material and Tools Needed</h3>
<ul>
<li>Screwdriver/<a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07QG5P2MG/?tag=p-policy-20">Drill</a>and a scrubbing sponge</li>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0015KROXU/?tag=p-policy-20">Degreaser</a>and warm water</li>
<li>Cabinet paintand primer</li>
<li>A paintbrush,a roller, ora paint sprayer</li>
<li>A piece of clean cloth and deglosser</li>
<li>Fine bristle brush and bucket</li>
<li>Soapy detergent and power source</li>
<li>Protective gear  respirator, facemask, overall, gloves,glasses, and boots</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="b-removing-cabinet-drawers-and-doors">b. Removing cabinet drawers and doors</h3>
<p>Follow the given steps when detaching doors and drawers:</p>
<ol>
<li>Wear protective gear - respirator, facemask, overall, gloves, and boots</li>
<li>Remove all the items in the drawers and place them away from the kitchen</li>
<li>Gently, pull out the drawers from the cabinets and place them in an open place for individual paint application</li>
<li>Carefully, unscrew the hinges using the screwdriver/drill to remove the door and place them in an open place</li>
<li>Remove latched partitions in the cabinet, in case of any</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="c-cleaning-the-cabinet">c. Cleaning the cabinet</h3>
<ul>
<li>Precisely, apply the degreaser on the cabinet surface and scrub gently using a sponge. Avoid scrubbing a given area for a very long period as it may deface the primary material color</li>
<li>Remove labels that may be fixed on the cabinet material using a heat gun or stain remover</li>
<li>Soak the piece of cloth in warm water, clean the cabinets shelves, doors, and frames gently, and allow them to dry completely.</li>
<li>Pour deglosser on a piece of cloth, rub on the shelves, drawer, and either side of the cabinet doors. Ensure the kitchen is well ventilated since the deglosser may irritate your respiratory system when inhaled</li>
<li>Leave the deglosser to dry for about 3o minutes. Do not touch the surface until its dry to touch</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>See Also:
Staining your Pressure Treated Wood</p></blockquote>
<h3 id="d-primer-paint-selection">d. Primer Paint Selection</h3>
<p>Cabinet paint should be selected according to the type of material under paint application. metallic cabinets are best painted with acrylic paint, while wooden cabinets are best painted with latex-acrylic paint.
The laminate wood cabinet should be painted with
<a href="https://pestpolicy.com/what-is-enamel-paint-used-for/">enamel paint</a>
for best service life performance. Avoid painted kitchen cabinets with highly concentrated oil-based paint  the oil ratio in the paint should be as low as possible to prevent fire outbreaks.
Pure latex paint should be avoided on the cabinet since its easily removed or gets washed out by fluid or water spillage within the cabinet drawers or shelves.
The primer selected should be matched with the type of finish paint chosen i.e.,
oil-based pain
t should be used on the oil-based primer.</p>
<h3 id="e-primer-and-paint-preparation">e. Primer and Paint Preparation</h3>
<p>Paint or primer preparation should strictly be followed using the manufacturers instructions given on the labels. In the case of the optional thinning method, a drop test experiment should be carried out to ascertain the paint performance on the cabinets primary material.
Moreover, paint or primer preparation should be done in relation to the painting method to be used. Paint to be applied using a paint sprayer is lightly thinner than that which should be applied using a roller. Further, the paint geared for
paintbrush application
is thicker.
NB: Well-prepared primer or paint should hold onto a paintbrush or a roller without any much dripping upon lifting  it should cause minimal surface drains.</p>
<h3 id="f-actual-painting">f. Actual painting</h3>
<ol>
<li>Begin by priming the cabinet shelves and doors to set a firm base for better paint stickiness during the application process. A primer is necessary for boosting paint strength, reducing the number of coats applied, and eliminating the chances of frequent peeling when exposed to a harsh environment.</li>
<li>Leave the primer to dry for about one hour before applying the second coat where necessary</li>
<li>Deep the paintbrush/roller and paint the cabinet shelves, and frames sufficiently. Dont overload the paintbrush to reduce drains and run formation when painting</li>
<li>Coat the drawers and doors with a single paint layer and leave them to dry naturally. A roller is best used for flat section, while a paintbrush would work sufficiently when cutting cabinet corners and sharp edges</li>
<li>Apply a second paint coat, where necessary after 1 to 2 hours (according to manufacturers instruction) and leave the cabinet shelves, doors, and frames to dry</li>
</ol>
<blockquote>
<p>See Also:
Sealer for Pressure Treated Deck Wood</p></blockquote>
<h3 id="g-final-finish">g. Final Finish</h3>
<p>The surface finish should not have ant runs/drains whatsoever  runs should be eliminated before the paint begins to dry as they are cumbersome to correct when dried and form an unpleasant surface finish upon restoration.
You can sprinkle cold water over the painted cabinet (if the area is dusty) to prevent dust and dirt particles from settling before the paint has dried. A well-painted kitchen cabinet should have a smooth finish without any streak or drain.
To achieve a high-quality finish when painting your kitchen cabinet, consider using
a paint sprayer
.</p>
<h3 id="h-fixing-cabinet-door-and-drawers">h. Fixing cabinet door and Drawers</h3>
<p>After 24 hours, the cabinet doors, shelves, and frames will have dried sufficiently. Return the drawers into their previous positions (ensure they are well latched in place). Using a screwdriver/drill, Fix the cabinet door hinges and fasten the doors into place.
You can reinforce the screw to improve the holding strength  dont change the hinges from previous positions.
NB: You can blow air fresher within the kitchen in case the paint smell still exists. Avoid interchanging cabinet hinges with a new model as this may affect the swing or door orientation.</p>
<h2 id="maintenance-tits-for-painted-kitchen-cabinets">Maintenance Tits for Painted Kitchen Cabinets</h2>
<p>To enjoy longer paint service life for your kitchen cabinet, proper maintenance tips highlighted below should be considered:</p>
<ol>
<li>Kitchen cabinets should not be exposed to high heat conditions  the paint coat weakens and tends to deface or peel with time.</li>
<li>The oil-based paint coating is sensitive to smoke particles (attracts smoke). You should consider placing your gas cooker or fire point slightly far away from the cabinets as much as possible.</li>
<li>Clean kitchen cabinets often (weekly) with degreaser/clean warm water to remove dust and surface stain that may cause loss of aesthetic beauty and aging.</li>
<li>Drawers and sliding shelves should be removed often and cleaned separately during general cleaning  often, dust and debris settle and accumulate within shelves gap if not attended to.</li>
<li>Avoid sticking adhesive labels/stickers on the cabinet surface  they stain the surface and affect the paint durability. Alternatively, you can use sliding labels or clips where necessary.</li>
<li>Repaint your cabinet regularly to protect primary material from aging or getting damaged. With time, youll find peeling or scuffing action occurring on the surface.</li>
<li>Avoid storing substances that may wet or spill on the cabinets- they lead to chipping or coat destruction/weakening of the paint layer.</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="precautions-and-safety-measures-to-consider-when-painting-kitchen-cabinet">Precautions and Safety Measures to Consider When Painting Kitchen cabinet</h2>
<p>Safety is paramount for health hazard prevention when carrying out cabinet paint application. Follow precautions and safety rules highlighted below strictly:</p>
<ol>
<li>Always put on protection gear (respirator, facemask, overall, gloves, and boots) during paint application.</li>
<li>Follow manufacturers instruction during paint or primer preparation to avoid wrong paint concentration.</li>
<li>Never smell oil-based paints or thinners directly as they contain chemical compounds that may irritate the nasal cavity when inhaled.</li>
<li>Avoid touching degreaser or deglosser with your naked hand when cleaning the cabinet surfaces as they may cause skin irritation upon contact.</li>
<li>All paint remain should be stored in a safe place away from pets and children to avoid intoxication.</li>
<li>Always check the expiry date of the paint or primer before you begin preparation. Expired paint or primer should be disposed of or returned to the seller immediately.</li>
<li>When painting your cabinets, cover the floor with a polyethylene bag to avoid staining.</li>
<li>In case you get into contact with deglosser, degreaser, primer, or paint, wash the area with plenty of water and soap.</li>
<li>Keep the fireplace or gas cooker as far as possible from the cabinets to protect them from smoke stains.
Always carry out a drop test experiment over the cabinet surface material after paint preparation to ascertain stickiness action before actual painting is undertaken.
See Also:
Deck Stain for Pressure Treated Wood
.</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>Learning how to paint cabinets without sanding, as highlighted in this article, not only boosted your painting skills but also opened your eyes to various DIY projects paint works. Sanding should be avoided when painting laminate wood or polished metal as it destroys the primary surface material and hence the overall aesthetic impression is affected.
Youll need to select the right material and tools, detach cabinet drawers and doors, clean the entire cabinet, select the right paint, and prepare it accordingly. Further, carry out actual painting step by step, attain a classic final finish before fixing back the cabinet drawers and doors. Remembers, wear appropriate protective gear for safety purposes when carrying out paint application.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
